<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Store of Value</title>
    <description>In July 2010, one bitcoin was worth $0.08 USD. Today, one bitcoin is worth $2500 USD. Bitcoin's meteoric growth has pushed cryptocurrencies from an obscure niche to the mainstream, and created fortunes along the way. Store Of Value is a blog that will help you navigate the cryptocurrency world. As an avid crypto researcher and a crypto day-trader, I hope to keep you up-to-date with the technology and help identify market opportunities. In this way, I hope that you too, can benefit from crypto.
</description>
    <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://storeofvalue.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 06:52:05 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 06:52:05 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Deep Dive Into EOS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-header -center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/t0u6yns.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-eos&quot;&gt;What is EOS?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS is a smart contracts platform founded and designed by cryptocurrency genius and serial entrepreneur, Dan Larimer. EOS promises to be a next generation smart contracts platform that uses a novel blockchain architecture designed to enable vertical and horizontal scaling that supports many decentralized applications in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS focuses on performance and useability. Its use of a delegated Proof of Stake consensus algorithm and a messaging-centric design allows it to have incredibly fast block times. Its unique token economics enables free transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, using Ethereum’s decentralized applications (dApps) can be quite cumbersome. A user needs to pay fees and transactions take a while to confirm. In high usage conditions, Ethereum becomes increasingly painful to use as fees rise and transaction confirmation times increase. EOS aims to solve all these issues in order to create a business-ready blockchain that doesn’t feel like a blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are grandiose goals but it’s important to keep in mind that EOS is still an early stage project. The main net hasn’t been released yet and EOS has yet to prove whether it will work as well as advertised in production. There are also concerns with centralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eoss-design-principles&quot;&gt;EOS’s design principles&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/8sBXh3r.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS very nicely lays out 6 requirements for blockchain applications in its whitepaper:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supports millions of users&lt;/strong&gt;: can’t build a successful blockchain with large network effects if it can only support a small network of users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free usage&lt;/strong&gt;: users should not have to pay transaction fees to use the network. It’s a bad experience doing so.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy upgrades and bug recovery&lt;/strong&gt;: applications should be super easy to upgrade. Software bugs are inevitable so it should be easy for developers to recover from them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sequential performance&lt;/strong&gt;: basically, a blockchain needs to have super high transaction throughput.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parallel performance&lt;/strong&gt;: a blockchain should be able to parallelize the execution of dApps, since many dApps often work in their own siloes and don’t really care about any other dApps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-is-dan-larimer&quot;&gt;Who is Dan Larimer?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/DJUPPl4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Larimer has been involved with cryptocurrencies for quite a long time. He registered his BitcoinTalk account, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?action=profile;u=611&quot;&gt;bytemaster&lt;/a&gt;, in 2010 and has been very vocal about blockchain designs on the forum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Larimer is a blockchain genius and serial entrepreneur. He’s the founder of two  blockchain projects, Bitshares and Steem. Both of which have hundreds of millions of dollars in market cap. Bitshares is a blockchain that supports decentralized exchange of custom assets and stablecoins. Steem is a social network blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Larimer has mentioned that his ultimate plan is to build a high performance generalized smart contract platform. He is highly critical of Ethereum and intends for EOS to drastically improve on Ethereum’s shortcomings. It’s clear that EOS incorporates many of his learnings from building Bitshares and Steem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend watching Larimer’s debate on blockchain scaling with Vitalik Buterin &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZQUvcmzenoc&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-does-eos-work&quot;&gt;How does EOS work?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS’s vision is to achieve widespread blockchain adoption. It plans to get there by building a general purpose, high performance, highly useable, and self-governing smart contracts blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do so, EOS needs to have high-scale, support parallelized dApp execution, free transactions, and a self-governing system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dpos-consensus-algorithm-and-a-5-annual-inflation&quot;&gt;DPoS consensus algorithm and a 5% annual inflation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS uses a consensus algorithm developed by Dan Larimer. The algorithm closely resembles delegated Proof of Stake (dPoS) algorithms so I’ll refer to it as dPoS in this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DPoS is incredibly fast. In EOS, blocks are produced in rounds. In each round, 21 block producers are chosen and the producers take turns to produce a block every 3 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users vote for block producers; the top 20 accounts with the most votes are guaranteed to be block producers. The 21st block producer is randomly chosen, with the chance being chosen proportional to the number of votes the account has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS has 5% annual inflation and the community will be able to vote on who receives the inflation. Although the exact distribution of the inflation is still unknown, it’s very likely that the block producers will receive a good portion of the inflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-eos-scale-to-millions-of-transactions-per-second&quot;&gt;How does EOS scale to millions of transactions per second?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS is able to achieve its high scalability and throughput as a result of its dPoS consensus algorithm and a novel blockchain architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DPoS is a blazingly fast consensus algorithm but the catch is, it’s quite centralized and block producers need to run super high performance computers in order to meet EOS’s blockchain demands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS’s novel blockchain architecture augments its dPoS algorithm to enable EOS to scale to millions of transactions per second. The architecture is messaged-based and supports parallelized dApp execution. You can read more about its architecture &lt;a href=&quot;http://iang.org/papers/EOS_An_Introduction.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;eos-supports-dapp-parallelization&quot;&gt;EOS supports dApp parallelization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, EOS is capable of parallelized dApp execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, EOS blocks are split into different threads with each thread assigned a group of dApps and other EOS accounts by the block producer. Two dApps can be safely assigned into different threads if there are no transactions referencing both dApps at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is made possible by the fact that a dApp’s state only depends on the messages it receives, and EOS has a constraint that messages generated in one block cycle can only be delivered in the next cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 3 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3806401153&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;eos-transactions-are-free&quot;&gt;EOS transactions are free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transactions in EOS are free. Block producers are compensated partly by an annual 5% inflation rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchains with free transactions are vulnerable to spam. EOS combats this by using a completely different resource model. Holding EOS tokens gives an account a set amount of transaction, computation, and storage bandwidth to use. The more EOS tokens a user holds, relative to other users in the system, the more blockchain resources available to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This limit is elastic. In low blockchain usage conditions, each EOS token provides more bandwidth. As overall blockchain usage increases, bandwidth allocation shrinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that this bandwidth restriction is enforced by EOS block producers in almost a subjective fashion. Since a block is produced by a single block producer, the producer can reject transactions if the producer believes that the transaction is wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-eoss-self-gzovernance-system-work&quot;&gt;How does EOS’s self-gzovernance system work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users holding EOS tokens have a say in the governance of EOS. Users get to vote for block producers and how EOS’s 5% annual inflation is allocated. Each EOS token represents one vote. The top 20 accounts (by votes) are guaranteed to be block producers while the 21st block producer is randomly chosen (chance proportional to the amount of votes an account has).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a block producer gives you tremendous power. Producers can collectively choose to freeze EOS accounts, change a smart contract’s code, and propose protocol changes. In addition, the block producers will likely have a significant portion of EOS tokens and thus have a huge influence over EOS’s governance decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS also introduces the concept of a blockchain constitution. In order to use the blockchain, users will need to sign the constitution by adding a hash of the constitution into the transaction’s signature. The constitution defines user obligations which cannot be entirely enforced by code. The constitution can be changed through proposals made by the block producers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-much-more&quot;&gt;And much more…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS is an incredibly complex blockchain and it has many features that make dApp development as easy as possible. These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a built-in permission management system&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an account recovery system&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ability for full nodes to partially evaluate blockchain state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about EOS’s technology, I highly recommend reading its &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/EOSIO/Documentation/blob/master/TechnicalWhitePaper.md&quot;&gt;technical whitepaper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eos-is-designed-for-businesses&quot;&gt;EOS is designed for businesses&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Larimer has stated that if EOS is successful, it’d be a blockchain where businesses would run their high performance dApps. These applications could include decentralized exchanges, social networks, and games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because EOS scales so well, it’d be able to support all these applications without being bogged down like Ethereum. EOS’s rich feature set also makes it very convenient for businesses to build dApps. On the flip side, dApps on EOS should be very easy and intuitive to use because of its high transaction throughput, fast confirmation times, and free transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eoss-ecosystem-is-gaining-momentum&quot;&gt;EOS’s ecosystem is gaining momentum&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/nNteLxP.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company behind EOS, block.one, has a very strong executive team. The team includes Brendan Blumer, a serial entrepreneur who has built businesses like okay.com in Hong Kong and 1Group in India, Richard Jung, a former CEO of Bithumb who has also held an executive position in Alibaba, and of course, the blockchain genius himself, Dan Larimer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Novogratz, a renowned billionaire ex-hedge fund manager who was an incredibly early investor in Ethereum, has invested in EOS through his venture capital firm, Galaxy Digital. Galaxy Digital and block.one announced in January that they have formed a $325 million fund to invest in EOS’s ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Block.one also announced in January that it has formed another EOS ecosystem fund with TomorrowBC, a blockchain investment arm of Eric Schmidt’s venture firm, TomorrowVentures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to these investment funds, block.one announced in September last year that it will be channeling $1 billion of its token sale proceeds to investing in its ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies that have announced they will build on EOS include Everipedia, a blockchain-based fork of Wikipedia, and EOSfinx, an EOS-based decentralized exchange operated by Bitfinex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With so much capital for block.one to deploy, look to seeing more and more companies build dApps on EOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 4 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2933037642&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;project-concerns&quot;&gt;Project concerns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;centralized-cartel-with-the-power-to-modify-contracts-and-censor-accounts&quot;&gt;Centralized cartel, with the power to modify contracts and censor accounts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are huge centralization concerns with EOS. Block producers have tremendous power and the blockchain has weak mechanisms to replace any. If you’re a block producer, you’d likely have a disproportionately large amount of EOS tokens which will basically ensure that you remain as a block producer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a block producer likely entitles you to a large portion of inflation income. You’ll also have the ability to modify contracts and censor accounts. This is a scary amount of power to give to a select few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also really hard for a user to become a block producer. Besides the paramount task of getting enough votes to be in the top 20 accounts, a user would need to operate high performance computers with large storage capacities (I would not be surprised if this reaches the scale of data centers) in order to support blockchain operations. How else will EOS be able to support so many high performance dApps on its platform?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, I’m quite certain that EOS will become a highly centralized system with the top 20 block producers forming a rigid cartel. Is this worth the ease of development and large performance gains? I don’t think so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jack-of-all-trades-master-of-none&quot;&gt;Jack of all trades, master of none&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS is essentially trying to be a blockchain-based AWS. I don’t think this will work out. Blockchains are not designed to be ultra high scale cloud computing platforms. The essence of blockchains is trustless security and tremendous liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If companies want a high scale cloud computing platform, they’d simply use AWS. AWS is cheap and provides SLAs that a blockchain will never be able to provide. Block producers have varying capabilities because they operate completely different computational and storage hardware. The producers are also able to control which transactions get processed and which don’t without any recourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain platforms like Ethereum and Bitcoin, which although have pitiful performance, provides a level of trustless security and liquidity that AWS will never be able to provide. These core properties are what sets these blockchain platforms apart from any other technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Because EOS tries to do both things at once, it will likely devolve into a centralized system that will never be great at any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because EOS tries to do both things at once, it will likely devolve into a centralized system that will never be great at any. Companies who want performance will use AWS and companies who want trustless security and liquidity will use Ethereum. Besides, Ethereum has some very powerful scaling technologies in its roadmap that do not sacrifice decentralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS tries to fix the scaling problems of existing blockchains in order to create a blockchain that will be ready for widespread adoption. However, its ease of use, performance, and scalability comes with a very expensive tradeoff: centralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s almost inevitable that EOS will become a highly centralized system with the top 20 block producers forming an unchanging cartel holding the vast majority of power. I really hope this doesn’t happen but I don’t see any way it doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I predict that EOS will be a jack of all trades but a master of none. It will not be the Ethereum killer many claim it will be. Having said this, I do believe the technology has a lot of potential and will watch it closely to see whether my prediction comes true.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 17:36:22 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-eos/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-eos/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Crypto Scam Spotlight: Ethertanks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-header -center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ocZdwip.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The massive success of CryptoKitties inspired many dApp developers to build games on Ethereum. A few developers, unfortunately, have decided to take a different path and build CryptoKitties-like games that were actually scams. Ethertanks was one of these games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as users can buy virtual cats on CryptoKitties, users can buy virtual tanks in EtherTanks. However, unlike CryptoKitties, Ethertanks doesn’t have any unique gameplay mechanics. In CryptoKitties, users could breed new, unique cats that had a combination of phenotypes from its parents. In Ethertanks, users simply bought tanks. There was nothing else they could do with the tanks accept earn money from users that bought in after them. The game was a clear Ponzi scheme. The devs did promise that users will eventually be able to trade and battle their tanks but they never delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-ponzi-scheme&quot;&gt;The Ponzi scheme&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A Ponzi scheme is defined as “a fraudulent investment operation where the operator generates returns for older investors through revenue paid by new investors, rather than from legitimate business activities or profit of financial trading.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethertanks’s economics system was a clear Ponzi scheme. Every type of tank had a base cost and this increased whenever a new tank of the type is bought. The cost of the new tank consists of the tank’s base cost and a small payout to every existing owner of a tank with the same type. As such, every time a user buys a tank, s/he is essentially paying fees to everyone else that bought in before him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a user wanted to make money from the scheme, they needed to get in early such that there would be enough suckers who’d buy in afterwards such that their returns could cover their initial investment and even exceed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a huge incentive for people to buy in as fast as possible and then shill the heck out of the “game” so that they can exit with meaningful profits. All the while, the devs were also making a huge amount of money as they took a cut out of each transaction and they were probably also the first users to buy into the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-pyramid-scheme&quot;&gt;The Pyramid scheme&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A Pyramid scheme is defined as “a form of investment (illegal in the US and elsewhere) in which each paying participant recruits two further participants, with returns being given to early participants using money contributed by later ones”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ponzi structure of Ethertanks resulted in a legion of shills (many from 4chan) that brigaded social networks like Reddit and Twitter to promote Ethertanks as the next CryptoKitties game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a post on 4chan’s infamous /biz/ forum calling its users to promote the Ponzi on the largest cryptocurrency subreddit, /r/cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ZG6sUtl.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brigading was particularly intense on Reddit with users creating and upvoting posts advertising Ethertanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many users justified Ethertanks’s Ponzi structure by saying that the devs had promised a marketplace so any users who bought in could always flip their tanks in the marketplace, just like CryptoKitties. Of course, this was only a promise and many users would learn, to their dismay, that the devs would never deliver on the promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To have a feel of the scale of Ethertanks brigading, check out the frontpage of /r/ethtrader soon after the game was released:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RqCMJhK.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ethtrader/comments/7n6sdg/ethertank_new_ethereum_dapp_buying_tanks_and/&quot;&gt;highest upvoted posts&lt;/a&gt; on Ethertanks. Notice how the poster emphasized how much money they were able to make…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/VYThV7v.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When users asked about the game’s obvious Ponzi scheme structure, the poster immediately countered by saying that there will eventually be a marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/T7nTZGO.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some other comments on Reddit shilling EtherTanks. Honestly, it makes me absolutely sick reading some of them. The comments on this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ethtrader/comments/7n48qm/be_careful_ethertanks_looks_like_a_pyramidponzi/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; where a /r/ethtrader mod was warning readers about the scam were particularly tough to read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Well my LT-1 is ready for battle”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Looked sketchy as fuck yet here I am earning a bunch of ETH.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Anyone with half a brain knows this is a Ponzi scheme lol. No need to read the code for that. That being said, LT-1 checking in.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I just bought the LT-1 and Eskimo 15 min ago. The shit actually works. And I’ve already recooped 8% of the cost that I purchased the tanks for. Crazy. I look at it as a learning process, how to actually interact with the blockchain. Now I have a decent grasp of it, and I can confidently send and receive crypto, know how to lock it all up, know how to view the blocks of a chain, can view any transaction from the public…and it all really works!!”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I am having a hard time believing this is real…yet here we are. Now I’ve made back ~15% of my initial investment (~$300) in the past 25 minutes.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“This received a lot of FUD today, but the community is great, devs have been responsive and supportive. HT-1 is the play.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I think this is good way to make some extra eth since market is moving slowly recently”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Bought the newest tank and got the investment back in like 30 minutes. Nice :)”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even The Merkle, a popular cryptocurrency news and editorial website, published an &lt;a href=&quot;https://themerkle.com/what-is-ethertanks/&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; promoting Ethertanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;false-promises&quot;&gt;False promises&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/GFT6WGK.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The devs promised that users would be able to trade and battle their tanks. The marketplace was supposed to launch on January 7th while battle mode was supposed to launch a few weeks afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, the devs never delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the devs did pull a final trick to try to get more people to buy in. After missing their January 7th deadline, they created a new dApp called EtherArmy where users can not only buy tanks, but ships and planes as well. EtherArmy was the exact same thing as EtherTanks except for a few new reskinned useless blockchain assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;aftermath&quot;&gt;Aftermath&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Ponzi schemes, most people who bought in lost money. The devs made a huge amount of money, the earliest adopters a little less but still a significant amount, and the latecomers lost most of what they put in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some posts from the game’s subreddit, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ethtanks/&quot;&gt;/r/ethtanks&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/1aYlB5W.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/N8fs1Hp.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one good thing that came out of this game is an important lesson for everyone involved, as well as outsiders. Never let your greed, your desire to make a quick buck, override your common sense. Understand that social media can easily be manipulated and you should not let Reddit and Twitter posts do the decision making for you. If it’s too good to be true and it looks like a scam, it probably is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 23:12:47 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/crypto-scam-spotlight-ethertanks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/crypto-scam-spotlight-ethertanks/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Deep Dive Into Cardano</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-header -center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/SMeXznA.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano is a proof of stake, smart contracts blockchain. Its native cryptocurrency is called ADA and the smallest unit of ADA (1/1,000,000 ADA) is called a Lovelace. This is in tribute to the first recognized computer programmer, Ada Lovelace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano prides itself in the rigorous academic process used to develop various aspects of the blockchain. Its website claims that Cardano is “the first blockchain project to be developed from a scientific philosophy, and the only one to be designed and built by a global team of leading academics and engineers”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to say that blockchain is the new religion and the consensus algorithm is its God. It is clear that Cardano has dedicated significant academic resources in developing its consensus algorithm, Ouroboros. Ouroboros is a provably secure proof of stake algorithm developed by a team of IOHK scientists led by Prof. Aggelos Kiayias. The algorithm is backed by a peer reviewed &lt;a href=&quot;https://iohk.io/research/papers/#9BKRHCSI&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;. According to Charles Hoskinson, the founder of Cardano, Ouroboros’s paper was rewritten 8 times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extent to which the academic process has influenced Cardano’s development currently does not extend beyond Ouroboros. The team has published a set of other papers, one for a scalable and decentralized randomness algorithm, one for an efficient and decentralized poker protocol, and one for secure sidechains. Besides the randomness algorithm, which is used in Ouroboros to select stake winners, Cardano has not incorporated the ideas of the other papers, yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano is built as a layered blockchain. The Cardano Settlement Layer (SL) is where account balances and transactions are managed. It uses the UTXO model and is supposed to be the most secure part of the blockchain. The SL is kept apart from the computational layer where smart contracts are executed. This layered architecture gives the system the flexibility to be more easily maintained and allow for upgrades by way of soft forks. In Ethereum, the settlement layer and the computational layer are intertwined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano’s properties of academic rigour and provable safety are unique in the cryptocurrency space and a huge selling point for the platform to enterprise customers. Companies looking to deploy blockchain technology want a guarantee of safety and Cardano is the only cryptocurrency with a consensus algorithm backed by a peer reviewed paper with provable safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cardanos-history&quot;&gt;Cardano’s history&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano’s ICO took place in 4 stages between September 2015 - January 2017 with heavy Know Your Customer (KYC) requirements. It was marketed as an “investment to retire on” to primarily Japanese investors; in fact, 95% of the buyers were of Japanese origin, primarily in the 35-55 age bracket. 2.56% of buyers were Korean, and 2.39% were Chinese. The ICO oversaw a total sale of approximately 26,000,000,000 of the 45,000,000,000 maximum supply of ADA tokens. At the conclusion of the ICO a total of approximately $63 million USD was raised; this puts the price at an average of $0.00242 per ADA, and the market capitalization immediately after the ICO at approximately $109 million USD. (&lt;a href=&quot;cardanohub.org&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While 26,000,000,000 ADA was sold in the ICO, an additional 5,185,414,108 ADA were distributed to IOHK, Emurgo, and the Cardano Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total of 31,112,484,646 ADA was made available at Cardano’s launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;current-state-of-cardano&quot;&gt;Current state of Cardano&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano lays out three eras in its timeline: the Testnet Era, Bootstrap Era, and Reward Era. The Testnet Era is pretty self-explanatory, Cardano is deployed on a test net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bootstrap Era is when Cardano SL is deployed on the main net BUT it is centralized in order to maintain security. Only a fixed, predefined set of users have control over the system. The assumption is that security is poor in this era since people are slow to redeem their ADA coins. For the first few months, stakeholders who jointly possess the majority of the ADA stake are mostly not online yet. The blockchain can be easily attacked if only a small amount of ADA is staked. As consolation to the community, Ouroboros will not provide any block rewards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano is currently in the Bootstrap Era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reward Era is when the network is in a completely decentralized and trustless mode. According to Cardano’s website, “the system will receive regular software updates moving forward, and a massive amount of new features will be released” in this era. These features would include upgrades to Ouroboros, Cardano’s consensus algorithm, an implementation of Cardano’s control layer, and sidechains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;iohk-and-the-cardano-foundation&quot;&gt;IOHK and the Cardano Foundation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/auw5cpJ.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IOHK, or Input Output Hong Kong, is the engineering company implementing Cardano and the Cardano Foundation is the promotor, educator, and standard body for the blockchain and its apps. In October, Hoskinson stated that IOHK had nearly 100 employees and contractors, three research engineers, and operate in nearly ten countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charles Hoskinson is the founder of IOHK and subsequently Cardano and the Cardano Foundation. Hoskinson has a long history as a blockchain entrepreneur. He was initially the CEO of Ethereum before being fired. Reasons of the firing are complicated. Ethereum at the time was 6 months old with a $15 million market cap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoskinson then founded IOHK and IOHK subsequently led the development of Ethereum Classic. Ethereum Classic came to be when Ethereum hard forked after the major DAO hack. A small portion of the community was against this idea and maintained the original chain, which is now known as Ethereum Classic. For IOHK to lead the development of Ethereum Classic suggests that Hoskinson might have some bad blood with members of the Ethereum Foundation, likely from earlier disagreements that resulted in his ousting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While IOHK continues to lead Ethereum Classic’s development, its primary focus is now on Cardano. Hoskinson aspires for Cardano to be a compelling alternative to Ethereum and he plans to do so by building a blockchain that was designed for scale, security, and upgradeability from day one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ouroboros&quot;&gt;Ouroboros&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ouroboros is Cardano’s proof of stake consensus algorithm. Proof of stake was chosen over proof of work since it’s more efficient and it’s way more expensive to perform a 51% attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/eBykRrr.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name Ouroboros comes from the name of an ancient symbol depicting a serpent or dragon eating its own tail. The symbol originated in ancient Egyptian iconography. The name is fitting for this algorithm, since Ouroboros operates in epochs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each Ouroboros epoch contains a fixed number of slots. Each slot represents a new block. The slot leader is an account staking ADA that is responsible for creating the block. Epochs last for 5 days (&lt;a href=&quot;https://steemit.com/cardamon/@dan/peer-review-of-cardano-s-ouroboros&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). Slot leaders for an epoch are chosen during the previous epoch. An account’s chance of being chosen is directly tied to the amount of ADA it’s staking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An account can only participate in staking if it has at least 1% of the total supply of ADA (&lt;a href=&quot;https://steemit.com/cardamon/@dan/peer-review-of-cardano-s-ouroboros&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). For the accounts that don’t meet that criteria, staking pools will exist so everyone is compensated for owning ADA. This high minimum staking requirement gives rise to concerns of centralization. I outline the concerns below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ouroboros will initially provide both newly minted ADA and transaction fees as block rewards. When the total supply of ADA reaches 45,000,000,000 block rewards will consist only of transaction fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to IOHK/Cardano Foundation, Ouroboros is the first provably secure proof of stake algorithm. The team behind Cardano has mathematically proven that the algorithm is safe from all the known proof of stake attack methods including grinding attacks, nothing-at-stake attacks, and long range attacks. This safety and security should be a very powerful enterprise selling point for Cardano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more about Ouroboros &lt;a href=&quot;https://cardanodocs.com/cardano/proof-of-stake/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ouroboros-praos&quot;&gt;Ouroboros Praos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ouroboros Praos is an initiative to upgrade Ouroboros. Praos is semi-synchronous, doesn’t require a heavy MPC protocol for randomness and encourages the adoption of a quantum resistant signature scheme for input endorsers and slot leaders. Praos allows for shorter block times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read about Praos &lt;a href=&quot;https://iohk.io/research/papers/#XJ6MHFXX&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ouroboros-hydra&quot;&gt;Ouroboros Hydra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ouroboros Hydra is another upgrade to Ouroboros that introduces sharding. Sharding allows multiple Ouroboros epochs to run at the same time which significantly increases Cardano’s throughput. One of the hardest things to figure out for sharding is inter-shard communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still a ways away from the Hydra upgrade. Expect a paper from Cardano’s team on Hydra before any serious development efforts begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 3 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3806401153&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;sidechains&quot;&gt;Sidechains&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Okl88yP.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidechains are blockchains running in parallel and independently from the main chain. Sidechains and the main chain should be able to securely transfer assets back and forth. If any problems arise in the sidechain, the main chain can confiscate the sidechain’s assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidechains significantly extend the main chain’s capabilities. Because they are separate from the main chain, they can be more centralized and faster and perform more specialized functions. By pegging themselves to the main chain, side chains can take advantage of the main chain’s security without having to adhere to the main chain’s inefficiencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main problem with sidechains today is their security. There are several attacks where mainchains can be compromised through side chains. The Cardanos team has changed this by introducing a provably secure sidechain technology that fixes all known avenues of attack, opening the way for secure sidechains. They call it Non-interactive Proofs of Proof of Work (NIPoPoW). Altough the Cardano’s team is far from implementing NIPoPoW sidechains on Cardano, the technology is a significant step forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;blockchain-performance&quot;&gt;Blockchain performance&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano’s average transaction throughput is 10-15 transactions per second. This is comparable to Ethereum. Charles Hoskinson has claimed that Ouroboros can perform at more than 200 transactions per second in a lab unsharded. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/cardano/comments/77ej8i/cardano_vs_eos/&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 4 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2933037642&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;project-concerns&quot;&gt;Project concerns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;smart-contracts-are-not-ready&quot;&gt;Smart contracts are not ready&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano’s smart contract virtual machine, the IELE virtual machine, is currently under development. According to Cardano’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://cardanoroadmap.com/&quot;&gt;roadmap&lt;/a&gt;, it is 33% complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano’s smart contract language, Plutus, is also currently under development. The specification of Plutus is complete but the implementation, Plutus core, is not. According to the roadmap, it is 12% complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the control layer still in the early stages of development, Cardano is currently a UTXO blockchain using a proof of stake consensus algorithm. In order for it to compete against existing decentralized smart contract blockchains like Ethereum and QTUM, Cardano needs to get out its control model ASAP in order to get its network effect going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ouroboros-is-prone-to-centralization&quot;&gt;Ouroboros is prone to centralization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, an account can only participate in staking if it has at least 1% of the total supply of ADA. At the current market cap of $13 billion, one needs to have $130 million worth of ADA to participate in staking. If you assume Cardano will be successful, this number will be significantly higher. Who will be able to afford $130 million worth of ADA? Sure there will be staking pools but even staking pools encourage the centralization of wealth. Those participating in the pools will most likely have to pay fees to the pool owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This minimum balance requirement also means that at most 100 accounts can participate in staking and because of the power law, it will be much less than 100 accounts that will be staking. There will most certainly be a few entities with exponentially large balances of ADA and the minimum balance requirement will only serve to consolidate their power and control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cardano-vs-eos&quot;&gt;Cardano vs EOS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This topic is extremely complex. There is a long history between Dan Larimer and Charles Hoskinson. In fact, before Ethereum, Hoskinson actually worked with Larimer on Bitshares but also left on bad terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out this &lt;a href=&quot;https://steemit.com/cardamon/@dan/peer-review-of-cardano-s-ouroboros&quot;&gt;post by Larimer on the flaws of Cardano&lt;/a&gt;. Also check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://hoskinsoncharles.blogspot.com/2018/01/the-price-of-craftsman-and-zen-of.html&quot;&gt;Hoskinson’s rebuttal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano is a fundamentally strong cryptocurrency. Ouroboros is a very cool proof of stake algorithm. Its layered blockchain design is sound. Cardano’s security, modularity, and upgradeability will be a big boon for Cardano when it tries to attract enterprise customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Cardano has some fierce competitors and academic rigour and peer research might not be enough to win against years of main net stability and gigantic network effects. That said, Cardano is not going anywhere in the medium term and it does have a very good chance at becoming a top tier smart contracts platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s not a sprint, it’s a marathon” - Charles Hoskinson&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 20:52:53 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-cardano/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-cardano/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Deep Dive Into Theta</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-header -center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/LQN3Oky.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A coworker recently brought to my attention a new cryptocurrency project called Theta. Initially, I dismissed it as just another low cap cryptocurrency project but the more I researched, the more interested I got. The first thing that caught my attention was the impressive list of advisors and investors. The project’s advisors include Steve Chen, a &lt;strong&gt;co-founder of YouTube&lt;/strong&gt;, Justin Kan, a &lt;strong&gt;co-founder of Twitch&lt;/strong&gt;, Fan Zhang, &lt;strong&gt;founding member of Sequoia Capital China&lt;/strong&gt;, and many more. The project’s investors include Sony and Samsung.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what exactly IS Theta to warrant all these high profile advisors and investors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a high level, Theta is a work-in-progress blockchain designed for peer-to-peer video streaming. It aims to be a decentralized video Content Distribution Network (CDN) by allowing anyone with spare bandwidth to become video distribution nodes. These nodes are compensated through proof of work mining on Theta’s blockchain. In order to fairly compensate nodes, Theta introduces a novel concept called Reputation Dependent Mining that increases block rewards based on how many clients a node is serving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world, the Theta blockchain will have a robust internal economy where streamers upload video to Ingest Nodes that transcode video. Video distribution nodes relay the video to viewers and are compensated by the number of viewers the node serves. Advertisers can advertise on Theta by paying streamers Theta tokens and viewers can donate to streamers using Theta tokens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theta is a relatively new project. The team raised $16 million in equity funding and launched Theta in Q2 2017. In Q3 2017, Theta completed &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ThetaLabs/theta-token-sale-success-ac6828d04e97&quot;&gt;an incredibly successful pre-sale&lt;/a&gt; of Theta tokens to strategic investors. A public ICO was scheduled for January 2018 but was cancelled partly from legal concerns. Theta was listed on exchanges starting January 17th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team wil start development of the Theta blockchain in Q1 2018 and plans to launch the blockchain in Q4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-theta&quot;&gt;Why Theta?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Theta’s innovation is set to disrupt today’s online video industry much in the same way that the YouTube platform did to traditional video back in 2005. One of our biggest challenges had been the high costs of delivering video to various parts of the world, and this problem is only getting bigger with HD, 4K and higher quality video streams,” said Steve Chen, Co-Founder of YouTube.
I’m excited to be part of the next evolution of the streaming space, helping Theta create a decentralized peer-to-peer network that can offer improved video delivery at lower costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The live streaming market is growing at a breakneck pace, seriously. 81% of internet and mobile audiences watched more live video in 2016 than in 2015. Live video is outpacing all other video content formats in terms of ad revenue and is seeing a 113% increase in annual ad growth. Live streaming is huge in China and growing at the same pace it is in the West. The Chinese live streaming market alone is valued at more than $3 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Steve Chen, Co-founder of Youtube&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Live streaming platforms rely on Content Distribution Networks (CDNs) to distribute video to viewers. Streamers upload video to ingest nodes, ingest nodes transcode the video to different qualities, the video is passed on to the CDN, and viewers connect to the CDN to download video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, CDNs are incredibly expensive to run well. Because video is so bandwidth intensive, companies need to make sure CDN edge nodes are as close to their end users as possible in order to maximize quality of service. As such, nodes need to be numerous and geographically distributed. Bandwidth costs for CDNs are also enormous. Every video stream passing through a CDN is duplicated for every cluster of edge nodes. Publishers like Twitch and YouTube absorb the high costs of operating a CDN which reduces the revenue shared with their streamers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theta aims to solve this problem by acting like torrent for live streams. Users contribute their unused bandwidth to distribute video and are compensated automatically and transparently by the Theta blockchain. Geographical distribution, server costs, and bandwidth costs come for free with such a peer-to-peer network. In addition, it is theoretically a more efficient system compared to centralized CDNs as it takes advantage of the ample amount of spare bandwidth out there. Put together, this SHOULD mean streaming companies will be more willing to use Theta over centralized CDNs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this all relies on the fact that both Theta’s economic model and technology works. This is a big if.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;team-investors-and-advisors&quot;&gt;Team, investors, and advisors&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/TWuUAgZ.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theta has a strong team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mitch Liu, the CEO, has a BS in Computer Science and Engineering from MIT and an MBA from the Stanford Graduate School of Business. He co-founded Tapjoy which today is a 100+ employee company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jieyi Long, the CTO, has a BS in Microelectronics from Peking University, one of China’s top universities. He has a PhD in Computer Engineering from Northwestern University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan Nichols, the Head of Product and Platform at SLIVER.tv, was once the director at Tencent for Wechat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Riz Virk, the Head of Corp Development, was the director at MIT’s Play Labs. He has a BS in Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering from MIT and a Masters in management from Stanford Graduate School of Business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advisors of Theta/SLIVER.tv include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Steve Chen, Co-founder of YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shoucheng Zhang, Founder Danhua Capital&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Justin Kan, Co-founder of Twitch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fan Zhang, Founding member, Sequoia Capital China&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dennis Fong, Founder Plays.tv&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clifford Morgan, CEO of G FUEL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/VbmV99j.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investors of Theta/SLIVER.tv include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lead investor in the token presale is DHVC (Danhua Capital). DHVC was founded by Prof. Shoucheng Zhang, a tenured professor in the Department of Physics at Stanford&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sony Innovation Fund&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SamsungNEXT ventures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sparkland&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sierra Ventures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DCM ventures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and many more…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;slivertv&quot;&gt;SLIVER.tv&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/hlyRMBr.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SLIVER.tv is an existing live streaming platform owned by the Theta team. SLIVER.tv allows users to watch esports events in 360° video. When there are no ongoing events, users can watch streams and bet on in-game events using currency passively earned from watching streams. Winners of bets get tickets to enter a raffle for a Steam item (some can be worth hundreds of dollars). A raffle is held for every game of PUBG or CSGO a streamer is currently playing. SLIVER.tv has more than 1 million Monthly Active Users (MAU).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theta’s team plans to use SLIVER.tv to bootstrap Theta’s network. This will possibly introduce millions of users to the network early on. This bootstrapping is incredibly important for the growth and adoption of Theta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thetas-architecture&quot;&gt;Theta’s architecture&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, Theta’s caching nodes act as both miners and relayers of video. The more reliable its service and the more viewers the node serves, the great the rewards from mining a block. To implement this, Theta’s team has come up with two novel concepts they call Reputation Dependent Mining and Proof of Engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reputation Dependent Mining uses Proof of Engagement to calculate a miner’s “reputation”. Reputation is essentially the number of viewers that a miner serves and it essentially determines the miner’s rewards from mining a block. The more viewers a miner serves, the higher its reputation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A miner increases its reputation by having its downstream viewers periodically compute “service certificates” to send back to the caching node. A service certificate is a simple Proof of Work puzzle that helps a miner attest to the rest of Theta’s network that the viewer is being served by the miner. If a viewer decides to stop computing service certificates for a miner, the miner can stop sending video to the viewer. If the miner doesn’t send video to a viewer, then it will be incredibly hard for the miner to convince anyone to compute service certificates for it. If it spends its own computing resources to generate service certificates, it will have less computing resources to create blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/mpk5BD7.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;project-concerns&quot;&gt;Project Concerns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If mining rewards are not enough to cover the costs of operating a miner, then there will be very few miners resulting in a poor CDN.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will viewers want to watch Theta streams if it means they need to compute service certificates?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volatility in the value of Theta tokens might incentivize network participants like advertisers, streamers, and miners to hold onto Theta in as short a time period as possible in order to lock in income. Volatility comes with risk whereas network participants are not investors and adverse to risk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How will advertisers plug into the system? Will advertisers be incentivized to buy Theta or simply pay in fiat? Will streamers be willing accept Theta or simply get paid in fiat?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will service certificates be enough to guarantee service quality? Service certificates are binary, either a viewer computes one or not. What if there’s gray area video quality issues like buffering and dropped frames?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 3 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3806401153&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theta is certainly a very innovative idea. CDNs are, in fact, very expensive to operate and the ability to mobilize spare bandwidth and CPU resources has the potential to create a much more efficient content distribution model. Besides an innovative idea, Theta has many other accolades. Its list of investors and advisors are impressive. Its co-founders have very strong backgrounds. It already has a very popular product in the form of SLIVER.tv that will be perfect for bootstrapping Theta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are several project concerns. The concerns cover both the demand and supply side. Important questions include whether mining rewards are enough to cover the costs of operating a miner, whether viewers are willing to compute service certificates in order to watch streams, and whether video quality will actually be good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Theta works, it will create a self-sustaining economy generating constant value in the form of live streamed entertainment. Large companies will be operating Theta miners and using the Theta network as their CDN. Viewers will be able to choose from a large number of independently operated Theta miners that are closeby to download video from. However, this is certainly a big IF.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 20:27:18 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-theta/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-theta/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why 2018 Will Be The Year Of Ethereum And QTUM</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a prediction - Ethereum will overtake Bitcoin by the end of 2018 and QTUM will be a top 5 cryptocurrency. There are some incredible things brewing for both and I don’t believe the market has fully realized nor appreciated what’s going on. Ethereum has the largest user and developer base in the West. QTUM has gained a strong foothold in the East. If you’re not convinced, keep reading! I list a few developments for both cryptocurrencies that I am incredibly bullish on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ethereum&quot;&gt;Ethereum&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/bK322a2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;proof-of-stake&quot;&gt;Proof of Stake&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethereum’s Casper upgrade, which introduces Proof of Stake to Ethereum, is very close to being released. Here’s a brief primer on how Proof of Stake works. Unlike Proof of Work, where powerful computers are used to solve arbitrarily hard mathematical problems to create blocks, Proof of Stake miners only need to “stake” their ether and the amount staked will determine the chance of creating a block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proof of Stake has many many benefits over Proof of Work. They include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;drastically lower electricity costs to operate the blockchain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;more incentives to own ether&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;less need to issue as many new ethers in each block to incentivize mining, since the cost of mining will be low&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;increased decentralization as the barrier to entry for mining is significantly lower than Proof of Work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;51% attacks are vastly more expensive to carry out than Proof of Work. If you successfully attack a Proof of Stake blockchain, the value of your stake will significantly drop as well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;makes the implementation of Sharding easier. Sharding is another Ethereum scaling upgrade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sharding&quot;&gt;Sharding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, Ethereum nodes need to validate every single transaction on the network. This is why people often stress that blockchains are not just distributed, but replicated. Since every node needs to store and validate every transaction, replication is really bad for scalability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With sharding, the Ethereum blockchain can be securely split into shards such that the nodes in each shard only needs to worry about transactions within that shard. Sharding is an incredibly complicated technology that is really hard to implement as you’d need mechanisms to allow ether to be transferred between shards, to guarantee that mining power will be evenly distributed between shards, and much more. Luckily, proof of stake makes the latter problem easier to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If executed well, sharding will reduce the load on Ethereum nodes and since each shard can operate semi-independently like a separate blockchain, Ethereum can sustain a much high transaction throughput. It will be another big leap in Ethereum scalability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A V1 sharding specification document is ready and Vitalik Buterin believes it is “good enough to get us to thousands of transactions per second”. Read more about Ethereum sharding &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ethereum/wiki/wiki/Sharding-FAQ&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plasma&quot;&gt;Plasma&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plasma is a very cool technology that not only improves Ethereum scaling but also great increases its utility. Here’s a very &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ethereum/comments/7rm98l/eli5_plasma/dsy0v89/&quot;&gt;cool ELI5 on Plasma&lt;/a&gt; found on /r/Ethereum by /u/enricotal70:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Plasma is a smart contract to create baby chains.&lt;br /&gt;
This new baby chain can run free at its own speed… but once in a while it needs to report back to its parent chain.&lt;br /&gt;
To enforce good behaviour on the youngling, the parent chain asks for a cautionary deposit.&lt;br /&gt;
If all the activities are the baby chain are within parameters, that’s great.. everybody is happy.&lt;br /&gt;
But if a user of the child chain discovers that something is fishy… can report it to the parent, the transactions could be reversed and the depost is gone.&lt;br /&gt;
Each baby chain can also give birth to another child chain and therefore theroretically enabling infinite scaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plasma allows private and permissioned blockchains to interface with and be rooted to Ethereum. These blockchains are often significantly faster due to increased centralization. However, this comes with a greater risk of a loss of integrity and security. By being rooted to Ethereum, it’s possible to detect when the permissioned blockchain is compromised and rollback any damage done to the public chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most promising Plasma projects is the OmiseGo blockchain. OmiseGo is a payments blockchain that will allow payments across many different types of assets. As such, it needs a trading engine built in and the blockchain will use ether as a central trading pair for liquidity reasons. OmiseGo is a separate blockchain from Ethereum and it will use Plasma to source ether in a decentralized manner into its own blockchain. Plasma allows OmiseGo to have OmiseGo-ether, which is very cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;makerdai&quot;&gt;MakerDai&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/AXvPhK6.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MakerDai is a decentralized and homeostatic stable coin system built on Ethereum as a series of smart contracts. Dai, the stable asset of the system, tracks the US dollar. MakerDai launched on December 18th, 2017. I believe it is one of the most important projects for Ethereum out there and great increases Ethereum’s utility. Here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The volatility and deflationary nature of cryptocurrencies are two key obstacles stopping cryptocurrencies from being treated as money. Here’s a famous joke:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A boy asked his Bitcoin-investing dad for $10 worth of Bitcoin currency&lt;br /&gt;
Dad: $17? What do you need $132 for?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now imagine you’re a retailer. If you’d just sold an iPhone for 1 ether and the price of ether tanked while you waited for the transaction, you just lost a lot of money. On the other hand, if you were the buyer and the price of ether skyrocketed as you waited for your transaction to clear, you also just lost a lot of money. Volatility in an asset adds risk to using it as money and discourages people from doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A deflationary asset also discourages people from using it as money. If people expect the asset’s price to increase over time, they are more inclined to hoard it than spend it. This is why a deflationary currency is really bad for an economy and central banks work really hard to keep inflation stable and positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most cryptocurrencies are deflationary and volatile. This makes them terrible forms of money. To fully realize the peer-to-peer value transfer utility of a cryptocurrency, we need stable coins that track a real world curreny like the USD. Needless to say, this is incredibly hard to achieve in a decentralized manner. This is where MakerDai comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MakerDai is a decentralized, transparent, and homeostatic stable coin system on Ethereum. It was released in December 2017. It is one of the first stable coins on Ethereum and will allow dApps to charge for services in terms of USD. How cool is that? Imagine if the Brave system and the 0x protocol could work with USD instead of the BAT token or 0x token. It makes Ethereum so much more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buiding a decentralized stable coin is by no means a simple feat. Check out how the team accomplished this by reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/cryptolinks/maker-for-dummies-a-plain-english-explanation-of-the-dai-stablecoin-e4481d79b90&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; and browsing their &lt;a href=&quot;https://makerdao.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. It’s fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;0x&quot;&gt;0x&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0x is a protocol built on Ethereum. I believe it is one of the biggest scaling solutions for Ethereum right now. Here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0x is an open, permissionless protocol allowing for ERC20 tokens to be efficiently traded on Ethereum. Specifically, 0x enables offchain order creation and onchain order settling. A user can create a 0x order to buy (or sell) an ERC20 token offchain and another user can take that order and fill it. 0x smart contracts will automatically complete the order onchain. One of the most promising applications of Ethereum is as a platform for the tokenized economy, i.e. the tokenizing of real world assets such that they can be traded on Ethereum trustlessly and transparently. With 0x, you can do that incredibly efficiently too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an example, decentralized exchanges benefit tremendously from 0x. The most popular decentralized exchange, EtherDelta, stores an orderbook in the smart contract. In order to update the orderbook, users need to send costly and slow transactions to the smart contract. Highly dynamic data structures like orderbooks are too expensive to run on the blockchain and really, are not meant for the blockchain. With 0x, users can create offchain orders and still hold on to their assets. This allows the orderbook of a decentralized exchange to be moved offchain. Many 0x-based decentralized exchanges have either been announced or have been released. They include RadarRelay, Paradex, The Ocean, and Ethfinex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I’ve focused on decentralized exchanges, it’s also important to note that use cases for the 0x protocol extends beyond decentralized exchanges since it’s fundamentally about the exchange of Ethereum assets. Many other dApps such as Augur, district0x, dydx, and Status are planning to use 0x.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 3 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3806401153&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;qtum&quot;&gt;QTUM&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/gpzQAWD.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those that do not know what QTUM is, here’s a brief primer: QTUM is a layered, proof of stake blockchain where the computing layer consists of the EVM and the settlement layer consists of a Bitcoin-based Unspent Transaction Output (UTXO) blockchain. QTUM’s main net was launched in September 2017 and so far there are more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://eco.qtum.org/dapps&quot;&gt;20 companies building QTUM-based projects&lt;/a&gt;. Most of them are Eastern projects and many have been quite successful. These projects include: Vevue, Bodhi, INK, Spacechain, Medibloc, and Energo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of my readers know that I have been bullish on QTUM for quite a while now. I think it is incredibly undervalued, partly because of a distinct lack of interest and awareness of QTUM in the West (QTUM is huge in the East), and partly because many people still do not understand its potential. Here’s a few reasons why I believe QTUM will be a top 5 cryptocurrency by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ethereum-ecosystem-wins--qtum-ecosystem-wins&quot;&gt;Ethereum ecosystem wins = QTUM ecosystem wins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because QTUM uses the EVM, any projects building on Ethereum can be easily ported to QTUM. A corollary to this is that any successful dApp or protocol on Ethereum can easily become a successful dApp or protocol on QTUM. QTUM doesn’t need to compete with Ethereum for its developer ecosystem, it shares Etheruem’s developer ecosystem. There are many amazing up-and-coming projects for Ethereum such as 0x and Augur and I can envision a world where QTUM has its own 0x’s and Augurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some readers might be wondering: why would people use QTUM when Ethereum exists? First of all, I don’t believe that cryptocurrencies is a winner takes all market. Second, I believe that many will choose QTUM over Ethereum because of a number of advantages that QTUM has. I elaborate on some of them below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that I do not believe QTUM can overtake Ethereum anytime soon. Ethereum is king and will remain king for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitcoin-ecosystem-wins--qtum-ecosystem-wins&quot;&gt;Bitcoin ecosystem wins = QTUM ecosystem wins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because QTUM uses a Bitcoin-based UTXO blockchain as its settlement layer, QTUM can take advantage of any upgrades to Bitcoin. Here’s a few examples: QTUM is already using SegWit and is primed to deploy its own version of Lightning. Once deployed, QTUM is essentially Ethereum with Lightning. How cool is that? It’d be even better for QTUM if Lightning turns out to be a massive success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are many more benefits for QTUM to use a UTXO blockchain besides being able to absorb Bitcoin upgrades. I outline them in a previous article: &lt;a href=&quot;http://storeofvalueblog.com/posts/is-qtum-the-dark-horse/&quot;&gt; 
Is Qtum Overlooked And Undervalued? - A Detailed Analysis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 4 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2933037642&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bodhi-and-qweb3js&quot;&gt;Bodhi and Qweb3.js&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is one thing to have a few companies building dApps on your platform, it is another for these companies to start enriching your developer ecosystem by contributing powerful, open source developer tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bodhi is one such company. The company is building a decentralized prediction market on QTUM and has also taken the lead to build &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@bodhitoken/bodhi-development-tools-qweb3-web3-js-for-qtum-a1cd52abbcc4&quot;&gt;QTUM’s version of web3.js, qweb3.js&lt;/a&gt;. Ethereum dApp developers will know how useful web3.js is for dApp development. I have recently been getting my hands dirty with developing dApps and can testify that it is indeed awesome. I believe that qweb3.js is crucial to jump-starting QTUM’s community dApp development and it is very good news that Bodhi has taken the initiative to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, for those interested in Bodhi, check out their website and whitepaper &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bodhi.network&quot;&gt;to learn more&lt;/a&gt;. Bodhi distinguishes itself from Augur and Gnosis by introducing a few novel market mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;worlds-largest-pension-fund-invests-in-ink&quot;&gt;World’s Largest Pension Fund Invests in Ink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/9YWLbRQ.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ink is another company building on QTUM. The company recently received an investment from the operators of Russia’s largest pension fund, NPF Gazfond. Gazprom (Russia’s national oil and gas company) and Alor Invest manages NPF Gazfond. Other investors of Ink include Fenbushi Capital’s Bo Shen and Softbank SAIF’s Yan Yan. For such high profile investors to invest in a budding cryptocurrency project is a huge vote of confidence on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ink aims to build a blockchain, interoperable with QTUM’s, that can manage IP rights and enable the free trade of cultural assets. Learn more about Ink on their &lt;a href=&quot;https://ink.plus&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good news for QTUM’s projects is good news for QTUM. I have only chosen to discuss Bodhi and Ink but many others are also gaining momentum and we should start hearing more about them later in the year. Check out the projects &lt;a href=&quot;https://eco.qtum.org/dapps&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;x86-virtual-machine&quot;&gt;x86 virtual machine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most anticipated upgrades to QTUM is the x86 virtual machine. QTUM merges the EVM with its UTXO blockchain through what’s known as the Account Abstraction Layer (AAL). The AAL enables the EVM to play nice with the UTXO blockchain. This layered architecture also allows QTUM to plug and play different smart contract virtual machines. QTUM is currently developing an x86 virtual machine that offers many benefits over the EVM. For one, any programming language with x86 compiler support today, which is almost all the languages that matter, can be easily ported to QTUM’s x86 virtual machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@earlz/thoughts-and-goals-on-qtums-x86-vm-9622cf349427&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; by QTUM’s cofounder and lead developer, Jordan Earls, outlines the myriad of advantages an x86 virtual machine has over the EVM much better than I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;growing-influence-in-asia-and-specifically-china&quot;&gt;Growing influence in Asia, and specifically China&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrick Dai, a cofounder of QTUM, claimed that QTUM is one of the most influential cryptocurrencies in the East. Many indicators, such as trading volume, media coverage, projects building on QTUM, support this claim. It is a well known fact that the Chinese government dislikes cryptocurrency speculation but is favorable of the development and adoption of blockchain technology. A series of recent events from China strongly hints that QTUM has received tacit support from the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;patrick-dai-was-interviewed-on-chinese-state-television&quot;&gt;Patrick Dai was interviewed on Chinese state television&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/LFkaa2v.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrick Dai was recently interviewed on China Global Television Network (CGTN). CGTN is the English channel of the China’s predominant state television broadcaster, China Central Television (CCTV). Patrick appeared on the show, The Point with Liu Xin, along with Henry Cao, Professor of Finance at the Cheung Keung Graduate School of Business. Topics covered include an overview of blockchain technology, how the financial industry can make use of blockchains, “blockchain fever”, and the challenges facing the technology. You can read about it &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.qtum.org/qtums-patrick-dai-on-china-global-television-network-239a9f4baad5&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the interview was very bullish on the technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;qihoo-360-partnership&quot;&gt;Qihoo 360 partnership&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qihoo 360 is one of China’s largest internet security companies. It’s products have over a billion users and its annual revenue reached $1.4 billion in 2014 (couldn’t find any data past 2014). The company is known for its antivirus software, web browser, and mobile application store. Qihoo 360 recently partnered with the QTUM Foundation to establish China’s first ever blockchain research center. The goal of this research center is to commercialize blockchain technology such that it can be deployed into Qihoo 360’s products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;baofeng-partnership&quot;&gt;Baofeng partnership&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baofeng is the company behind the Storm Player, one of the most popular online video players in China with hundreds of millions of users. Baofeng has a market cap of more than 8 billion CNY on the Shenzhen securities exchange. In December 2017, Baofeng announced that its Bokocloud division will help deploy up to 50,000 QTUM nodes. This strategic cooperation will make Baofeng Bokocloud the world’s first BCN (blockchain consensus network) service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We are very excited to sign the world’s first Blockchain Consensus Network (BCN) service agreement with Qtum,” said Reccon Cui, CEO of Baofeng Bokocloud. “Baofeng Group operates the world’s largest P2P network, so we are impressed by the security and superior flexibility of the Qtum’s blockchain architecture, and we found that the current ecosystem of Qtum is rapidly developing. We are very happy to cooperate with one of the best blockchain technical teams in this field.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;strong-eastern-awareness-and-interest&quot;&gt;Strong Eastern awareness and interest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good indicator of awareness and interest for a cryptocurrency project is the number of people that show up to its community events. QTUM recently held a Taiwan meetup where more than 800 people attended. Not bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/PQBHIwa.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 16:53:36 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/why-2018-will-be-the-year-of-ethereum/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/why-2018-will-be-the-year-of-ethereum/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Definitive Guide To NEO (2nd Edition)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/SbPjcBr.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DISCLAIMER: I am diversified across Ethereum, QTUM, and Vechain. All of which are competing smart contract platforms. I choose not to diversify into NEO.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As before, there will be a few avid NEO supporters that will… respond negatively to this article. I implore anyone who is inclined to do so to avoid ad hominem attacks and address my arguments. Look into them and verify them yourselves.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote about NEO back in July 2017 when it was still Antshares and at $7. Today, it’s more than $150. I’ve been following NEO closely since I was fascinated with the platform. A smart contracts platform that can perform up to 10,000 transactions per second (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7oap5g/neo_transactions_per_second/&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)? Smart contracts that can be written in multiple popular languages like Java and C#? Earning GAS rewards just for having NEO in your wallet? NEO was a nascent cryptocurrency that seemed like it. could easily challenge Ethereum and I wanted to learn everything about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you know that I’ve been highly skeptical of NEO over the past few months. A few have stated that I’m a critic either because I’m invested in Etheruem and QTUM (competitors to NEO) or that I sold early and missed the boat. I see these as crude arguments that completely ignores the reasons I put forth from the research I’ve poured into NEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a diehard fundamentals investor and I dig deep into every aspect of a project. What made me balk at NEO was the layers of deceit and manipulation I found that I couldn’t accept and be quiet about. If I truly believed in projects that were rivals, I would diversify among the competitors to derisk. That’s why I’ve invested in QTUM, Ethereum and even Vechain. I have very good reasons why I won’t diversify into NEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I believe that it’s best to compile everything I’ve found about NEO and let my readers be the judge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;10000-feet-summary&quot;&gt;10,000 feet summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NEO is a smart contracts blockchain started by Onchain, a Shanghai-based blockchain R&amp;amp;D company led by Da Hongfei and Erik Zhang.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Held two phases in its ICO, one in August 2016 and another in September 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Originally named Antshares, the platform was rebranded to NEO in August 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uses the delegated Byzantine Fault Tolerance (dBFT) algorithm as a consensus algorithm. &lt;strong&gt;NEO is not a Proof of Stake system.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Claims to support up to 1,000 transactions per second and 10,000 transactions per second with optimizations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Smart contracts platform that supports multiple languages including Java and C#.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Several ICOs have launched on NEO since the rebranding event in July.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NEO acts as shares of the blockchain and owners can vote on consensus nodes. Holding NEO also automatically generates GAS. Every NEO will eventually generate at most 1 GAS and this process is slated to complete in a few years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GAS is the fee to use the network. It’s supposed to pay for transactions and smart contract deployment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NEO’s team currently operates all 7 validator nodes in the network and has set transaction fees to zero. To deploy a smart contract, one needs to pay 500 GAS. At the current GAS price of about $60, it would cost $30,000 to deploy a smart contract (&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.neo.org/en-us/sc/systemfees.html&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NEO’s consensus algorithm requires every validator to know every other validator. The global number of validators needs to be known and constant as well. This validator list is maintained by NEO’s team and the team gets to choose validator candidates to be voted in by the community. Candidates are legally liable for operating the validators (&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/proof-of-working/decentralization-from-coopetition-b10d7ce3b9d&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NEO is undergoing a process of decentralizing the location of their validator nodes, but they still maintain full control over the nodes. &lt;strong&gt;They are not in a process of decentralizing control, as many would like to think&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NEO is more centralized than Ripple.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NEO has a strong third party developer ecosystem led by the City of Zion (CoZ). CoZ develops blockchain tooling such as wallets and blockchain explorers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neos-history-team-and-onchain&quot;&gt;NEO’s history, team, and Onchain&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO held the first phase of its ICO in August 2016 and the second phase in September 2016. It was originally named Antshares before rebranding to NEO in August 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO is an open source blockchain developed and managed by Onchain, a Shanghai-based blockchain R&amp;amp;D company. Onchain was founded by CEO Da Hongfei and CTO Erik Zhang. Erik Zhang is also the lead developer of NEO. A large Chinese international conglomerate investment company, Fosun International, has invested in Onchain. Onchain has its own blockchain product, called the Distributed Networks Architecture, or DNA. DNA is comparable to the Linux Foundation’s Hyperledger project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ucfW1S0.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Da Hongfei is popular among the NEO community. He is soft spoken and often implores his audience to “focus on the technology and not the price”. He has appeared in numerous interviews with popular cryptocurrency public figures and was even on Bloomberg recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;consensus-algorithm---dbft-and-neo&quot;&gt;Consensus algorithm - dBFT and NEO&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good resource for NEO’s consensus algorithm is Erik Zhang’s paper on dBFT which can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.neo.org/en-us/node/whitepaper.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve scoured through it and here’s what I found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The global validator count in dBFT needs to be constant and every validator needs to know every other validator. Validators work together to reach consensus on the next block. As long as more than two thirds of the nodes are in agreement, the network moves forward. dBFT is very similar to Ripple’s and Stellar’s consensus algorithms; all three fall under the Byzantine Fault Tolerance class of consensus algorithms. This is why NEO can match Ripple and Stellar speeds of up to 10,000 transactions per second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key difference, however, between Ripple/Stellar’s consensus algorithms and NEO’s consensus algorithm is that NEO’s is closed and much more centralized. In Ripple and Stellar, anyone can join as a validator whereas NEO is very strict on how many validators can exist and who the validators are. This closed-ness and the requirement that two thirds of the network needs to be in agreement to reach consensus forces the NEO’s team to maintain centralized control in order to keep the network secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO’s team currently sets the total validator count to be at 7 and they operate all 7 nodes. They have claimed to decentralize the network by placing validator nodes in different locations such as in a Swiss bunker and a Dutch telecommunications company’s (KPN) server farm. However, the NEO’s team still owns and operates these nodes, so it’s &lt;strong&gt;decentralization of location but still a centralization of control&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a very important distinction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another important thing to keep in mind is that dBFT is NOT Proof of Stake. dBFT is a consensus algorithm where validators aim to cooperate instead of competing for rewards. NEO holders do not have the ability to provide input in the consensus algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;legally-liable-for-operating-a-validator-node&quot;&gt;Legally liable for operating a validator node?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO’s team has a plan to eventually allow NEO holders to vote on validator operators. However, since validator up time is incredibly important, the team gets to approve candidates. &lt;strong&gt;In addition, those that are voted in will be held legally liable by the team to keep the validator up (&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/proof-of-working/decentralization-from-coopetition-b10d7ce3b9d&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/a8ls69S.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much for decentralized control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;centralized-control-means-possible-blockchain-blackouts&quot;&gt;Centralized control means possible blockchain blackouts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/A9vahBl.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very interesting event happened in October last year when NEO’s blockchain went offline for several hours. This was incredibly disturbing to many people since blockchains are not supposed to just disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO’s team provided a very vague reason for the blackout: they had to shutdown the blockchain in order to perform “manual checks” when they attempted to free 15 million NEO from the 50 million NEO locked up as a developer fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the reason, the fact that NEO’s team could turn off their blockchain at a whim should be unsettling for any cryptocurrency investor. No single entity should have so much power over the network. However, it is also not surprising that the team can turn off the blockchain… they control all 7 validation servers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This incident demonstrates the tremendous risk of centralization in a cryptocurrency. In times of mania, it’s always good to remember the fundamental value propositions of cryptocurrencies and not be blinded by price action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 3 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3806401153&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;smart-contracts-on-neo&quot;&gt;Smart contracts on NEO&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/HhkYhMm.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price to deploy a smart contract on NEO at this moment is 500 GAS (or $30,000 at $60/GAS). Because it’s so expensive to deploy smart contracts on NEO, there are very few smart contracts on the main net right now. In fact, as of last week, there were only 10 smart contracts. 3 of which are test smart contracts deployed by Erik Zhang. 6 of the rest are cookie cutter ICO smart contracts. There is one smart contract for Hash Puppies, an upcoming game on NEO similar to CryptoKitties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also interesting to note that there are 27 dApps listed on NEO’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://neo.org/dapps&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;, yet many of them are from a CoZ competition held in November last year that will probably never be deployed on the main net. Each winner of the competition won 1350 GAS but none of them have used it to deploy their smart contract. Would you consider the listing of demo, test net smart contracts as dApps on NEO dishonest? At the very least, it doesn’t increase my confidence in the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;city-of-zion---neos-community-of-developers&quot;&gt;City of Zion - NEO’s community of developers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all the shit I give NEO, I am actually quite impressed with the third party developer community that have formed around the project. While Erik Zhang and his engineers work on NEO core (which consists the consensus algorithm and the core wallet), NEO’s large third party developer community, City of Zion (CoZ) works on tooling around the fledgling blockchain. This tooling includes blockchain explorers, blockchain APIs, and light wallets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CoZ is well known in the community and have often even acted as the mouthpiece of NEO’s team, publishing blog posts on NEO’s mission, vision, and roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;gas-generation-and-us-securities-law&quot;&gt;GAS generation and US securities law&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO holders earn GAS at a constant rate based on the amount of NEO owned. GAS generation is finite and gas rewards stop in a few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GAS rewards are essentially dividend payments for owning NEO. This is because GAS is generated at a predictable rate and NEO holders do not have to do any work to receive GAS. As such, NEO is easily classified as an equity security under securities laws in the US, South Korea, and certain EU countries. This makes it illegal for non-certified exchanges to trade NEO in these countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see that Bittrex, which has disabled their NEO wallet for over a month now, is likely in the process of phasing out NEO trading as the US tax season approaches. Bithumb and Coinone, two of the largest South Korean exchanges, have refused to list NEO even with so much investor interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write about this in further detail &lt;a href=&quot;http://storeofvalueblog.com/posts/investor-warning-cryptocurrency-exchanges-are-breaking-us-law/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 4 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2933037642&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neos-icos&quot;&gt;NEO’s ICOs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the rebranding event in August and the launch of their smart contract 2.0 system, NEO has hosted quite a few ICOs. There are a little under 10 ICOs so far, not a breathtaking amount but still impressive. However, many have turned out to be questionable; dubious ideas, mysterious teams, and amateurishly run ICOs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;red-pulse&quot;&gt;Red Pulse&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Red Pulse was the first ICO on NEO. The ICO started in August 15th and ended in October 8th. Red Pulse is an interesting project. The company provides paid research and news reports of Chinese markets to Western consumers. Users pay for their services in fiat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does the Red Pulse token (RPX) factor into their system? From what I can gather reading their website, it seems like the Red Pulse token would be used as a means of payment to independent Red Pulse contributors… and that’s about it. The only reason any contributor would accept these payments is because the exuberant cryptocurrency markets right now has given it value. Otherwise, the value of the RPX token is really a one way street. Without market speculators, there is no demand side to this token, only a supply side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/4CXa9c7.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think this is a sustainable economic model. Besides being a vehicle of speculation and a way for Red Pulse to fund their content, the RPX token has no utility. The RPX token market cap is currently at $150 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aphelion&quot;&gt;Aphelion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aphelion was NEO’s second ever ICO. The ICO ended last year on December 8th. There were so many red flags the project and I was quite surprised NEO’s team and community managers failed to issue any warnings about it. Here’s a very good explanation from NEO’s subreddit on why the project is a scam: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7c35ks/aphelion_is_probably_a_money_dump/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7c35ks/aphelion_is_probably_a_money_dump/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;deepbrain-chain&quot;&gt;DeepBrain Chain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/iTH58Uv.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DeepBrain is a Chinese AI company. They concluded their ICO last year on December 15th. The company develops AI software and plans to build a decentralized AI computing platform with the DBC token as a means of payment. Users that want to access the computational power of the platform will pay in DBC tokens, and the users that operate “mining nodes” providing computational power are paid in DBC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combining Artificial Intelligence and blockchain technology sounds exciting but is it practical? Take a look at this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/CryptoCurrency/comments/7od7vg/deep_brain_chain_dbc_is_vaporware_and_heres_why/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; by a Harvard postdoctoral researcher who works on neural networks. The researcher believes that DeepBrain Chain is impractical and will very likely turn out to be vaporware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thekeyvip&quot;&gt;TheKey.VIP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TheKey is a company aiming to build an identity verification system on NEO. It’s essentially NEO’s equivalent of Ethereum’s Civic project. TheKey’s ICO ended recently on January 15th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/HIi5vKx.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard from many accounts that TheKey’s ICO was a disaster. One author went so far as to dub it the &lt;a href=&quot;https://71republic.com/2018/01/15/thekey-rip-the-story-behind-the-worst-ico-of-2018/&quot;&gt;“worst ICO of 2018”&lt;/a&gt;. In the hours leading up to the start of the ICO, the website was slow and often failed to load. The ICO’s Telegram group was filled with scams, porn, and shit posts with zero moderation. The team also whitelisted 40,000 people for the ICO, yet was only going to accept 10,000 NEO (NEO is indivisable so at most 10,000 people will get their orders filled). This needlessly overloaded the ICO. To make matters worse, the team significantly raised the price RIGHT BEFORE THE SALE STARTED. Finally, when you thought it couldn’t get any worse, it does. Apparently, any extra NEO sent to the crowdsale past the 10,000 NEO hard cap would be kept by the team in order for them to perform an audit of the sale. Seriously? This not only locks up the capital of investors who failed to participate in the ICO, it’s also robbing investors of GAS dividends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, why would an audit of the sale even require the withholding of the extra NEO. The team shouldn’t accept any NEO past the 10,000 NEO hard cap in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This highly amateurish and borderline scammy administration of the ICO is not the project’s only red flag. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://concourseq.io/Q/TheKey&quot;&gt;ConcourseQ’s page&lt;/a&gt; on TheKey.VIP where they have listed numerous other red flags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posts on NEO’s main subreddit (/r/neo) that questioned the legitimacy of TheKey.VIP were all removed by the subreddit’s admins:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/sBwpHkr.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/XKoEhPU.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7qesy8/5_reasons_that_why_thekeyvip_is_a_possible_scam/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7qesy8/5_reasons_that_why_thekeyvip_is_a_possible_scam/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7qgd5p/thekey_ico_scam_alert/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7qgd5p/thekey_ico_scam_alert/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trinity&quot;&gt;Trinity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trinity aims to build state channels on NEO, similar to what Raiden is doing on Ethereum. Its ICO ended on January 14th. I have my doubts on whether state channels have utility in a dBFT blockchain that is already incredibly fast but sure, let’s bring state channels to everything I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Trinity ICO exhibits a couple red flags. First of all, they were caught copying source material from the Raiden Network (&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@DeepLearningBitcoin/trinity-neo-ico-copied-raiden-network-b0147975eeda&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). Second, they somehow allowed people to continue sending them NEO even after the ICO hard cap was reached (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CoinHodl/status/953361678040813568&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-bottomline&quot;&gt;The Bottomline&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO is a blockchain project that appears to have tremendous potential. A nascent smart contracts platform that is already hosting a wide array of ICOs, a strong third party developer community in the form of the City of Zion, and a fervent fanbase. Taking all these attributes at face value, one could easily believe that NEO is set to dominate 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, things are not what they seem; there is a lot of misinformation surrounding the project and there are many NEO investors that do not understand what they’re investing in. I hope that by compiling my research into an article, I can clear up this misinformation and help people make their own informed judgement on NEO.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:56:27 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-definitive-guide-to-neo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-definitive-guide-to-neo/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Deep Dive Into Nano/RaiBlocks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/2i9SqoV.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;RaiBlocks won the community vote on which cryptocurrency I should review next: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.strawpoll.me/14761169&quot;&gt;http://www.strawpoll.me/14761169&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: I don’t own any RaiBlocks, haven’t owned RaiBlocks in the past, and don’t plan to own any RaiBlocks in the future.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RaiBlocks is a cryptocurrency that supports feeless, near-instant transactions, with tremendous scalability. It does so by veering from the traditional single-threaded blockchain data structure to a directed acyclic graph (DAG) data structure. RaiBlocks uses a unique DAG that the team calls a block-lattice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Bitcoin’s price rose over 2017, so did its transaction fees. The developers of Bitcoin’s insistence on keeping Bitcoin’s maximum block size at 1mb has caused tremendous congestion in its network. This congestion brought many altcoins with low fees and fast transaction times into the limelight. RaiBlocks, which boasts feeless and near instant transactions, was one of them. From a price of $0.20 in December to a peak price of $35 in early January, RaiBlocks’s price boomed as Bitcoin’s price stalled. At the time of writing, RaiBlocks’s price has stabilized at around $22.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RaiBlocks’s claim to fame is its feeless transactions and tremendous scalability. This sounds too good to be true and has had many people raising their eyebrows. The two fundamental properties of cryptocurrencies are decentralization and consistency and it’s generally accepted that it’s incredibly hard, maybe even impossible, to create a cryptocurrency that satisfies all three criteria of the “DCS triangle”: decentralization, consistency, and scalability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So is RaiBlocks legitimate? Is it everything that it claims to be or is it vaporware? Let’s dive into the technology to see how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;10000-feet-summary&quot;&gt;10,000 feet summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RaiBlocks was started in 2014 as a side project by Colin LeMahieu. The project took three years to complete and a fully functional main net was launched in 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RaiBlocks has a fixed, maximum supply of 133,248,289 XRB. All XRB was created when the main net was launched.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All transactions are free and they are confirmed within 5 seconds. RaiBlocks has an extremely high network throughput capacity and is only limited by computational speed and data transfer delays.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RaiBlocks uses a DAG-based, block-lattice data structure instead of the traditional single-threaded blockchain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consensus is maintained through a voting mechanism. Validator nodes vote on a world state that they believe is true. The number of votes each node has is the addition of the number of XRB owned plus the number of XRB delegated to the node by other accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The RaiBlocks team didn’t conduct an ICO and instead distributed RaiBlocks for free through a web faucet. 7,000,000 XRB was retained as a development fund.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/azcmAlx.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;is-raiblocks-a-scam&quot;&gt;Is RaiBlocks a scam?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve scoured through the whitepaper and looked over the team’s history and believe that RaiBlocks is everything it claims to be, but with a few caveats. There are many open questions around its consensus algorithm. It’s not well tested and to my understanding, lacks peer review. This increases the risk of critical flaws that could bring down the network. Although RaiBlocks does indeed support near instant and free transactions, the jury is still out on whether the consensus algorithm is correct and robust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides open questions on the integrity of RaiBlocks’s consensus algorithm, it’s also important to note that RaiBlocks is more centralized than traditional blockchain cryptocurrencies. RaiBlocks’s validation nodes are very very to operate and they do not provide any financial incentive. This means that the number of validators on the network will tend to be very few living it inherently prone to centralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RaiBlocks is not a scam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-does-raiblocks-work&quot;&gt;How does RaiBlocks work?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RaiBlocks uses a novel data structure known as a block-lattice. While traditional blockchain-based cryptocurrencies maintain a single, global blockchain, RaiBlocks maintains a blockchain for every RaiBlocks account. Each blockchain can only be updated by the its owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To send funds, the sender needs to issue a “send” transaction in its own blockchain and the receiver needs to issue a corresponding “receive” transaction to its blockchain. This is why RaiBlocks is so fast. Because the account is the only entity that can update its blockchain, each blockchain can be updated immediately and asynchronously. This results in really fast transactions. Once a blockchain update is made, the transaction is propagated across the network and as long as no validator discovers a conflict, the transaction is confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RaiBlocks network consists of wallets and validator nodes. In order for a wallet to issue a transaction, it must send it to a validator node. The node validates the transaction and then broadcasts it to all other validator nodes that it’s connected to. Every subsequent validator node performs the same validate-and-relay process until the whole network has seen the transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A validator node keeps track of the state of the entire network by storing every address’s blockchain. Conflicts or “forks” happen when a published transaction conflicts with a validator node’s internal state. To resolve the conflict, the node initiates a voting process by announcing the conflict to other nodes. The voting process occurs over a predefined period where each node votes on a state of the network it believes is correct. The number of votes a node has equals the amount of RaiBlocks it owns plus the RaiBlocks delegated to it from other accounts. When a state has more than 133,248,289/2 votes (133,248,289 is the total number of XRBs in existence), it’s automatically accepted as the real state of the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RaiBlocks network provides no rewards for running a validator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To mitigate spam, an account needs to perform an easy proof of work problem to add a transaction to its own blockchain. This is, of course, not a cure-all as transactions can still be created within a few seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;team-and-history&quot;&gt;Team and history&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key developer behind RaiBlocks is Colin LeMahieu. LeMahieu started developing RaiBlocks in 2014 and he released the network in 2017. RaiBlocks didn’t hold an ICO and instead, distributed the cryptocurrency through a web faucet. Users need only complete a captcha in order to receive RaiBlocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team behind RaiBlocks is small and fairly unknown but with the cryptocurrency’s recent success, LeMahieu is in the process of building a larger team. Expect RaiBlocks to make big ecosystem plays in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/L3bJAEW.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;paypal-lead-engineer--raiblocks&quot;&gt;PayPal lead engineer + RaiBlocks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting to note that a lead PayPal engineer built a RaiBlocks checkout app as a weekend hack project. Check it out &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@bluepnume/introducing-brainblocks-my-weekend-hack-project-to-build-a-simple-checkout-app-for-raiblocks-5f5770c06c14&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. For a lead PayPal engineer to build something with RaiBlocks, even if it was just a weekend hack project, is quite significant for this nascent cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;raiblocks-vs-iota&quot;&gt;RaiBlocks vs IOTA&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IOTA is another cryptocurrency that offers free and near instant transactions with high scalability. IOTA, like RaiBlocks, saw a tremendous increase in price over the past month. It’s not surprising that the two are frequently compared against each other. Here’s how the two cryptocurrencies differ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, RaiBlocks uses a block-lattice structure where every account has its own blockchain. IOTA uses a global DAG data structure (called Tangle) where every node in the graph represents one whole transaction. In order to issue a new transaction, an account needs to validate two previous transactions by solving an easy proof of work problem. The new transaction would then “reference” or connect to the previous two transactions in the Tangle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While IOTA transactions happen in a single phase (i.e. one transaction that represents both a send and a receive), RaiBlocks transactions happen in two phases: a sender needs to issue a “send” transaction in its blockchain and the receiver needs to issue a corresponding “receive” transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RaiBlocks is more decentralized than IOTA (though both pale in comparison to Bitcoin and Ethereum). IOTA currently needs a centralized Coordinator to ensure network security and direct network progress. This is because IOTA’s network security is directly tied to the number of transactions occuring in the network. In low transaction conditions, network security drops significantly. In theory, the Coordinator will eventually become unnecessary as the network reaches a critical mass of adoption but IOTA is far from this reality. A scary consequence of the existence of a Coordinator is the fact that IOTA’s developers can freeze any user’s funds at a whim… and they have done so before (&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.iota.org/official-iota-foundation-response-to-the-digital-currency-initiative-at-the-mit-media-lab-part-1-72434583a2&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). The security of RaiBlocks’s network, on the other hand, does not depend on the amount of transactions going through it. As such, RaiBlocks currently doesn’t need a centralized entity as a security crutch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s not all that bad for IOTA. After all, it was one of the first movers for free and fast cryptocurrencies and it has an ecosystem advantage over RaiBlocks. IOTA has more users and the IOTA Foundation has more business connections. For example, the Foundation recently launched an IOTA Data Marketplace initiative with many large companies participating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am primarily concerned with how expensive it is to operate a RaiBlocks or IOTA validator node since both require high performance computers but the network provides no financial reward to do so. This discourages the operation of validator nodes and the less validator nodes in a network, the more centralized it is and thus the less secure it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 3 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3806401153&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;project-concerns&quot;&gt;Project concerns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;concerns-with-the-consensus-algorithm&quot;&gt;Concerns with the consensus algorithm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, there are many open questions around the consensus algorithm. Given that RaiBlocks is so young, it’s not well tested and lacks peer review. This introduces the risk of a serious flaw in the consensus algorithm. For example, what happens if there aren’t enough votes for a quorum in order to resolve a network conflict? Currently, validator nodes rely on the maximum supply number (133,248,289 XRB) in order to determine a quorum and it’s totally possible that a voting process could not have enough validator nodes participating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s another big question I have: in the event that parts of the RaiBlocks network get separated for a long period of time (perhaps due to network issues or other freak occurences), what happens when you rejoin the separated networks? Will the rejoined network be crippled from all the voting processes that would inevitably take place? Is there a mathematical guarantee that the new network will recover?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all very important questions and their answers will determine the robustness and, ultimately, the longevity of RaiBlocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;spam-vulnerability&quot;&gt;Spam vulnerability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RaiBlocks, being inherently feeless, is highly vulnerable to spam. I could run a script where multiple accounts will constantly send transactions between each other creating massive blockchains. Run long enough, it will make validators incredibly expensive to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It costs next to nothing to create spam in the system yet spam can be very costly. Unlike the traditional blockchain where storage and computational costs are predictable, RaiBlocks’s feeless transactions and scalability makes both of these costs highly unpredictable and there is no rule that prevents them from skyrocketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect these spam attacks to occur as RaiBlocks increases in popularity and we will have to see how the development team responds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;raiblocks-doesnt-incentivize-decentralization&quot;&gt;RaiBlocks doesn’t incentivize decentralization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RaiBlocks’s validator nodes are very expensive to operate run. The operation costs consist of high network throughput costs and modest processing and storage costs. Since there’s no reward for running a RaiBlocks validator node, validator node operators are prone to centralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people argue that this is not a problem since wealthy businesses relying on the RaiBlocks network are incentivized to run validator nodes to secure the network. Large investors might also be incentivized to run validator nodes in order to secure their investment. However, we have yet to see if this is true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;limited-applications---no-smart-contracts&quot;&gt;Limited applications - no smart contracts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart contracts are an undervalued yet very powerful extension to cryptocurrencies. I have a strong feeling that the any cryptocurrency that wants to be successful in the long run must support smart contracts. However, I have reservations on whether RaiBlocks will ever be able to support smart contracts given that its system is so radically different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;bottomline---am-i-bullish-on-raiblocks&quot;&gt;Bottomline - am I bullish on RaiBlocks?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RaiBlocks works as described - near instant and feeless transactions with unlimited transaction throughput. It has a lot of potential to seriously challenge big names like IOTA and even Bitcoin. However, RaiBlocks is currently being held back by an unproven consensus algorithm, spam vulnerability, centralization concerns, and the lack of smart contracts. Nevertheless, the network in its current state works and it works well. Although there are still many open questions around the project, I am quite bullish for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 01:40:35 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-raiblocks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-raiblocks/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Investor Warning: Certain Cryptocurrency Exchanges Are Breaking US Federal Securities Laws</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Axga15N.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TLDR: Certain cryptocurrencies are easily considered securities under United States federal securities laws. These cryptocurrencies are actively traded in several cryptocurrency exchanges operating in the United States. The SEC has made it abundantly clear that they are placing cryptocurrencies under tighter scrutiny and will have stricter enforcement of securities laws in 2018. Investors of securities-like cryptocurrencies should beware that exchanges will very likely delist these cryptocurrencies in 2018.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United States recently passed a tax law that exempted cryptocurrency-to-cryptocurrency trading as like-kind exchanges. This means that trading Bitcoin for Ethereum or Ethereum for OmiseGo will now be considered a taxable event. It is clear that the United States government is starting to place more scrutiny on cryptocurrency exchanges, especially cryptocurrency-to-cryptocurrency exchanges, and there will be more stringent regulations in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this said, one of the most obvious regulatory pain points of existing crypto-to-crypto exchanges operating in the United States is the listing of cryptocurrencies that are easily considered securities. The Securities Exchange Act of 1934 established the Securities and Exchange Commision (SEC) as well as a law that states that any exchanges trading securities needs to be licensed by the SEC. A key requirement for acquiring a license is the strict adherence to very stringent security trading rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Existing crypto-to-crypto exchanges operating in the United States, such as Bittrex, Kraken, and Poloniex, most certainly do not have SEC licenses to trade securities, yet are listing a few cryptocurrencies that are considered securities under United States federal securities law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we continue, the reader might be wondering: what constitutes a security under United States federal securities law anyways? For this, we use what’s commonly known as the Howey Test. Back in July 2017, the SEC released a report that defined the DAO token as a security. The report also gave guidance for other cryptocurrencies stating that if they cannot pass the Howey Test then they will be considered securities. According to the test, in order for a cryptocurrency to be considered a security, all three elements listed below must be met:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An investment of money&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in a common enterprise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;with an expectation of profits predominantly from the efforts of others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GDAX has helpfully published a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1QxOV2dgxO3C_TyVE0-41ZwLlzPmB-EE1NNshJGuedCU&quot;&gt;Howey Test spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; that makes it very easy to apply the test on a cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this said, let’s go through some popular cryptocurrencies that passes the Howey Test and is considered a security (note: almost every cryptocurrency meets element 1, an investment of money. The grey areas lie in elements 2 and 3):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iconomi (ICN)&lt;/strong&gt;: Iconomi lays out in their whitepaper that ICN holders: own the Iconomi platform, are entitled to dividends, and have voting rights. This means that ICN meets both “Common Enterprise” and “Expectation of Profit” criterion. ICN is listed on Kraken and Binance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NEO (NEO)&lt;/strong&gt;: NEO meets the “Common Enterprise” criteria because of Gas. Gas is paid to all NEO holders, with the amount of payment proportional to the amount of NEO held, regardless of any action on the part of the NEO holder. As such, Gas is earned as a dividend from holding NEO. According to NEO’s whitepaper, “NEO token holders are the network owners and managers, managing the network through voting in the network”. This means that NEO most certainly meets the “Expection of Profit” criteria. Adding on to this, manual action is required outside of the network in order for the holder to get the benefit of the token. This is because the NEO team, and not the network, is solely responsible for policing its network of validators and if a validator misbehaves, the NEO team is responsible for suing the validator owner and revoking validator status. NEO is listed on Bittrex, Poloniex, and Binance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aragon (ANT)&lt;/strong&gt;: ANT tokens are very similar to DAO tokens which were specifically called out by the SEC to be a security. ANT gives holders governance and voting power for the distribution of assets with the purpose of profit making. As such, it meets both the “Common Enterprise” and “Expectation of Profit” criterion. ANT is listed on Bittrex.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Etheroll (DICE)&lt;/strong&gt;: DICE meets both the “Common Enterprise” and “Expectation of Profit” criterion since DICE holders earn ether based off of the profits the network makes from its gambling enterprise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TenX (PAY)&lt;/strong&gt;: TenX used to meet both the “Common Enterprise” and “Expectation of Profit” criterion since PAY holders were entitled to a portion of the fees paid by TenX credit card users. However, TenX has decided to distance themselves from being considered a security by &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.tenx.tech/tenx-pay-token-structure-update-4f19be727870&quot;&gt;restructuring the PAY token&lt;/a&gt;. Details on the restructuring are unclear but the PAY token should be safe for exchanges to list post-restructuring. PAY is listed on Bittrex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are invested in a cryptocurrency that passes the Howey Test, be mindful of the fact that the SEC is very likely going to crackdown on securities-like cryptocurrencies in 2018 and will force their delisting from cryptocurrency exchanges operating in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 07:10:46 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/investor-warning-cryptocurrency-exchanges-are-breaking-us-law/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/investor-warning-cryptocurrency-exchanges-are-breaking-us-law/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Is Why Ripple's Price Is Surging</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/zAVEor4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following cryptocurrency markets recently, you’d notice that one cryptocurrency, Ripple, has been on fire. If I was a snarky a**hole, I’d have told you that the reason Ripple is flying is because more people are buying than selling. But I won’t, because you’re here to learn and not to read snarky replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been following Ripple closely and have even wrote an &lt;a href=&quot;http://storeofvalueblog.com/posts/what-is-ripple-and-should-you-invest/&quot;&gt;fundamental analysis article&lt;/a&gt; on it recently. I believe I have very good reasons for why Ripple’s price is surging. They center around three things: (1) Successful pilot project with Japanese banks involving RC Cloud, (2) South Korea, and (3) a possible Coinbase listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rc-cloud-and-japanese-banks&quot;&gt;RC Cloud and Japanese banks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I begin, I want to clear up a misconception around Ripple. Although Ripple has impressive banking partnerships, very few banks have any desire to work with RippleNet and XRP. The current banking partnerships center around Ripple’s xCurrent product which as no relationship with RippleNet and XRP. The problem with XRP is that it’s an incredibly unstable and deflationary cryptocurrency being speculated and manipulated on in often shoddy cryptocurrency exchanges all over the world. This, and the fact that Ripple holds 50% of the total supply of XRP, makes it a very undesirable asset for banks to hold, even if it can help banks reduce liquidity costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, here’s one reason for Ripple’s recent price surge: a consortium of Japanese banks recently completed a successful pilot program where the banks used Ripple’s RC Cloud product to settle interbank payments. RC Cloud is built on Ripple’s xCurrent product. As I’ve mentioned above, xCurrent has no relationship with RippleNet and XRP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the successful pilot, the banks are ready to bring the RC Cloud solution into production. This is great for Ripple, the company, but has little implications for RippleNet and XRP. Nevertheless, it’s clear that the excitement for the successful pilot program has spilt over to XRP investors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitsonline.com/japanese-korean-ripple-pilot/&quot;&gt;https://www.bitsonline.com/japanese-korean-ripple-pilot/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;south-korea&quot;&gt;South Korea&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bithumb, a South Korean exchange, has consistently held the top spot for XRP trading volume over the entire period when XRP’s price surged from $0.25 USD to $2.80 USD. In fact, Bithumb currently has $2.6 billion USD in daily XRP trading volume. This is more than the XRP trading volumes of the next 3 top exchanges put together. Clearly, the South Koreans are incredibly excited for XRP as well. But why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably because two major South Korean banks are joining the consortium of Japanese banks in trialing RC Cloud for settling cross border payments. This new pilot program between Japanese and South Korean banks will take place over December. If successful, the project is planned to go live in early 2018. Having major South Korean banks involved in this RC Cloud pilot program is exciting, especially for South Korean investors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we need to keep in mind that RC Cloud has no relationship with RippleNet and XRP. Banks are not adventurous enough to dabble in a cryptocurrency like XRP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ripple.com/insights/top-korean-banks-work-japan-bank-consortium-modernize-cross-border-payments/&quot;&gt;https://ripple.com/insights/top-korean-banks-work-japan-bank-consortium-modernize-cross-border-payments/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;possible-coinbase-listing&quot;&gt;Possible Coinbase listing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coinbase has hinted that they are aiming to list more cryptocurrencies next year. They recently listed Bitcoin Cash, the first cryptocurrency listing on the platform since the Litecoin listing in May 7 months ago. Coinbase is the largest on-ramp for retail cryptocurrency investors in North America. The service allows investors to purchase cryptocurrencies with credit cards and has a very simplistic user interface. A cryptocurrency’s listing on Coinbase will introduce it to many new investors and has very positive implications for its price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XRP seems like one of the best candidates for a Coinbase listing given that it’s a top 3 cryptocurrency with a mature company behind it. However, as diligent investors, we must also cross reference this rumour with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gdax.com/static/digital-asset-framework-2017-11.pdf&quot;&gt;Digital Asset Framework&lt;/a&gt; that Coinbase published last month outlining the properties a cryptocurrency should have for a listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see that XRP passes many of the framework’s requirements but fails at others. In the “Team” requirement, we see that Ripple’s leadership is highly centralized and dependent on a small number of key persons. In the “Governance” requirement, Ripple also performs poorly given that the development of RippleNet is not led by a community development team but by a centralized entity, namely the Ripple company. In the “Open Financial System” requirement, Ripple performs poorly in terms of decentralization. As I’ve mentioned in my &lt;a href=&quot;(http://storeofvalueblog.com/posts/what-is-ripple-and-should-you-invest/)&quot;&gt;Ripple analysis article&lt;/a&gt;, RippleNet is still quite centralized. Finally, in the “Token Sale Structure” requirement, Ripple performs poorly in terms of Team Ownership given that the Ripple team currently owns at least 50% of the total supply of XRP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, XRP does look like a great candidate for a Coinbase listing but an investor should definitely not trade on the hopes that it will go on Coinbase soon. Unless, of course, you want to front run all the other speculators but it’s a bit late for that right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 13:52:06 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/this-is-why-ripples-price-is-surging/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/this-is-why-ripples-price-is-surging/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This User Made 462 Ether ($210,000) in 3 Days Trading CryptoKitties</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/WhmB4m8.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&quot;http://storeofvalueblog.com/posts/cryptokitties-the-aftermath/&quot;&gt;“CryptoKitties - The Aftermath” article&lt;/a&gt;, I wrote about how Kitty #23 was flipped for more than 210 ether (about $94,500 at the time) over 4 days. Turns out, the guy who did one of those tremendously profitable trades read my article and reached out to me with an even wilder story. In 3 days, he made 462 ether trading CryptoKitties. 462 ether was worth $210,000 at the time and $323,400 today. We did an informal interview over email. Here is his CryptoKitties story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our email conversation, this user went by the moniker Dapper Kittie. Dapper Kittie has been involved with Bitcoin since 2012. CoinMarketCap’s Bitcoin chart doesn’t even go back that far. He made his first purchase of Bitcoin through Coinbase in early 2013 for about $20 each. He was an early enough customer of Coinbase that when he reached out to customer support, the founder, Brian Armstrong replied. Coinbase had yet to hire their first employee, Olaf Carlson-Wee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With his early entrance into the cryptocurrency scene and a knack for trading, Dapper Kittie was quite well off even before his success with CryptoKitties. He currently works from home as a cryptocurrency trader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dapper Kittie discovered CryptoKitties when he saw a post on social media about the 246 ether sale of Genesis Founder Cat #1. This peaked his interest with the dApp but he was still hesitant to pull the trigger; he thought it was just a wash sale to generate hype. Nevertheless, he kept a close eye on the CryptoKitties market since he believed there could be some value in these virtual cats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;primary-market-buying-the-newly-released-founder-cats&quot;&gt;Primary Market: Buying the newly released Founder Cats&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, he noticed that the rare “Founder Cats” were slowly being bought up. Founder cats were incredibly rare cats created by the CryptoKitties team to fund the development of the dApp. The team created 100 of these rare cats. They were initially valued as such: 250 ether for founder cat #1, 50 ether for founder cats #2-10, and 10 ether for founder cats #11-100. These values slowly decreased over time until settling at a price floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dapper Kittie started noticing that several of these founder cats were being bought and resold for huge profits. For example, founder cat #88 was bought for 10 ether and resold for 78 ether! 8 is a lucky number in China. This resale got Dapper Kittie to commit and he decided to buy founder cat #42 (because of The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy) for 10 ether and founder cat #7 (lucky 7?) for 50 ether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/TEmP7Dc.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon commiting 60 ether, he was content with his two founder cats when he noticed two accounts that swooped in to buy up all the remaining low number founder cats. This caused him to purchase founder cats #45 and #47 before every other founder cat was bought up. All in all, he invested 80 ether into the founder cats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the accounts that was buying founder cats en masse went by the name &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cryptokitties.co/profile/0x88ba6d5a7abe727d73b0f4c7965775b959646f7e&quot;&gt;“US Treasury”&lt;/a&gt;. Dapper Kittie first noticed that US Treasury relisted several 10 ether founder cats at 30 ether and they were quickly sold! Dapper Kittie did the same with two of his 10 ether founder cats and both of them were quickly sold. A nice tripling in investment, not bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the founder cats were getting more and more expensive. Cat #2 was resold for 150 ether but this was cheap at the time given that many single digit founder cats started selling for 300+ ether. Dapper Kittie decided to up his own prices and sold cat #42 at 75 ether (65 ether profit) and cat #7 at a whopping 190 ether (140 ether profit).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;secondary-market-buying-relisted-founder-cats&quot;&gt;Secondary Market: Buying relisted Founder Cats&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having sold all of his original founder cats at a tremendous profit, Dapper Kittie decided to dabble in the secondary founder cat market. He started buying cheap founder cats being relisted by other traders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, he had made enough from selling his original founder cats that he was just playing with profits. One of the cats that he bought during this time was founder cat #23. He bought it at 70 ether and resold it 24 hours later for 133.9 ether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After flipping a few more secondary market cats, Dapper Kittie was ready to call it quits when a big opportunity jumped in front of him. Someone who evidently wasn’t paying close attention to the market decided to sell two founder cats for only 50 ether each, a far cry from the average market price of ~150 ether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, he jumped at the opportunity and amped up the gas he was willing to pay for his transactions to buy the two cats (the fee was peanuts compared to the amount of ether he was sending). The Ethereum network was quite congested at this point from the CryptoKitties mania and Dapper Kittie could only hope that no one was able to front run him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, he was able to nab both of the cheap founder cats for 50 ether each and resell them for 125 ether and 126 ether a couple hours later. These two cats were both sold to the US treasury account mentioned earlier but has since not been bought by anyone else. The two cats are still being listed for 100 ether each right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;getting-out-before-the-bubble-pops&quot;&gt;Getting out before the bubble pops&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, with most of his cats sold, Dapper Kittie was ready to call it quits. His last cat was sold for 95 ether (25 ether profit). A few days later, the CryptoKitties bubble popped and prices for the cats nosedived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dapper Kittie was apt enough to identify the mania and left early with tremendous profits. In the end, he made 462 ether over the span of 3 days trading CryptoKitties. This was worth about $210,000 at the time. Definitely not bad for 3 days of trading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;CAT&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;BOUGHT (eth)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;SOLD (eth)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;PROFIT (-fees)&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;BOUGHT&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;SOLD&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;49.21&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;190.05&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;133.71&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/3 21:28&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/4 19:45&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;42&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9.86&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;75.08&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;62.41&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/3 9:21&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/4 8:19&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;69.14&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;133.88&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;59.71&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/4 8:38&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/5 7:07&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;45&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9.84&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;35.06&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;23.90&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/3 19:39&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/4 7:24&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;47&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9.84&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;30.17&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;19.19&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/3 19:47&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/4 6:27&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;27&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;70.46&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;95.33&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;21.29&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/4 8:46&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/7 13:27&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;52&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;50.15&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;125.73&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;70.87&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/6 5:15&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/6 6:01&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;93&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;50.32&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;126.03&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;70.98&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/6 5:30&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12/6 7:26&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Total&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;318.84&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;811.33&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;462.06&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asked what he planned to do with all this extra capital, he said that he wants to give back to charity by donating to animal rescue and welfare groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is his CryptoKitties address: &lt;a href=&quot;https://etherscan.io/txs?a=0xa3e6fea802c91140b832127aea816ce78b0be0de&amp;amp;p=1&quot;&gt;https://etherscan.io/txs?a=0xa3e6fea802c91140b832127aea816ce78b0be0de&amp;amp;p=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What. A. Legend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to thank Dapper Kittie for reaching out to me and doing the informal interview with me. His story is fascinating and definitely something to be remembered in cryptocurrency history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/0q8W6jV.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 23:36:10 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/this-user-made-462-ether-in-3-days-playing-cryptokitties/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/this-user-made-462-ether-in-3-days-playing-cryptokitties/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
