<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Store of Value</title>
    <description>In July 2010, one bitcoin was worth $0.08 USD. Today, one bitcoin is worth $2500 USD. Bitcoin&#39;s meteoric growth has pushed cryptocurrencies from an obscure niche to the mainstream, and created fortunes along the way. Store Of Value is a blog that will help you navigate the cryptocurrency world. As an avid crypto researcher and a crypto day-trader, I hope to keep you up-to-date with the technology and help identify market opportunities. In this way, I hope that you too, can benefit from crypto.
</description>
    <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://storeofvalue.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:14:32 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:14:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>This Is Why Ripple&#39;s Price Is Surging</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/zAVEor4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following cryptocurrency markets recently, you’d notice that one cryptocurrency, Ripple, has been on fire. If I was a snarky a**hole, I’d have told you that the reason Ripple is flying is because more people are buying than selling. But I won’t, because you’re here to learn and not to read snarky replies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been following Ripple closely and have even wrote an &lt;a href=&quot;http://storeofvalueblog.com/posts/what-is-ripple-and-should-you-invest/&quot;&gt;fundamental analysis article&lt;/a&gt; on it recently. I believe I have very good reasons for why Ripple’s price is surging. They center around three things: (1) Successful pilot project with Japanese banks involving RC Cloud, (2) South Korea, and (3) a possible Coinbase listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rc-cloud-and-japanese-banks&quot;&gt;RC Cloud and Japanese banks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I begin, I want to clear up a misconception around Ripple. Although Ripple has impressive banking partnerships, very few banks have any desire to work with RippleNet and XRP. The current banking partnerships center around Ripple’s xCurrent product which as no relationship with RippleNet and XRP. The problem with XRP is that it’s an incredibly unstable and deflationary cryptocurrency being speculated and manipulated on in often shoddy cryptocurrency exchanges all over the world. This, and the fact that Ripple holds 50% of the total supply of XRP, makes it a very undesirable asset for banks to hold, even if it can help banks reduce liquidity costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, here’s one reason for Ripple’s recent price surge: a consortium of Japanese banks recently completed a successful pilot program where the banks used Ripple’s RC Cloud product to settle interbank payments. RC Cloud is built on Ripple’s xCurrent product. As I’ve mentioned above, xCurrent has no relationship with RippleNet and XRP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the successful pilot, the banks are ready to bring the RC Cloud solution into production. This is great for Ripple, the company, but has little implications for RippleNet and XRP. Nevertheless, it’s clear that the excitement for the successful pilot program has spilt over to XRP investors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bitsonline.com/japanese-korean-ripple-pilot/&quot;&gt;https://www.bitsonline.com/japanese-korean-ripple-pilot/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;south-korea&quot;&gt;South Korea&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bithumb, a South Korean exchange, has consistently held the top spot for XRP trading volume over the entire period when XRP’s price surged from $0.25 USD to $2.80 USD. In fact, Bithumb currently has $2.6 billion USD in daily XRP trading volume. This is more than the XRP trading volumes of the next 3 top exchanges put together. Clearly, the South Koreans are incredibly excited for XRP as well. But why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably because two major South Korean banks are joining the consortium of Japanese banks in trialing RC Cloud for settling cross border payments. This new pilot program between Japanese and South Korean banks will take place over December. If successful, the project is planned to go live in early 2018. Having major South Korean banks involved in this RC Cloud pilot program is exciting, especially for South Korean investors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we need to keep in mind that RC Cloud has no relationship with RippleNet and XRP. Banks are not adventurous enough to dabble in a cryptocurrency like XRP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ripple.com/insights/top-korean-banks-work-japan-bank-consortium-modernize-cross-border-payments/&quot;&gt;https://ripple.com/insights/top-korean-banks-work-japan-bank-consortium-modernize-cross-border-payments/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;possible-coinbase-listing&quot;&gt;Possible Coinbase listing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coinbase has hinted that they are aiming to list more cryptocurrencies next year. They recently listed Bitcoin Cash, the first cryptocurrency listing on the platform since the Litecoin listing in May 7 months ago. Coinbase is the largest on-ramp for retail cryptocurrency investors in North America. The service allows investors to purchase cryptocurrencies with credit cards and has a very simplistic user interface. A cryptocurrency’s listing on Coinbase will introduce it to many new investors and has very positive implications for its price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XRP seems like one of the best candidates for a Coinbase listing given that it’s a top 3 cryptocurrency with a mature company behind it. However, as diligent investors, we must also cross reference this rumour with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gdax.com/static/digital-asset-framework-2017-11.pdf&quot;&gt;Digital Asset Framework&lt;/a&gt; that Coinbase published last month outlining the properties a cryptocurrency should have for a listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see that XRP passes many of the framework’s requirements but fails at others. In the “Team” requirement, we see that Ripple’s leadership is highly centralized and dependent on a small number of key persons. In the “Governance” requirement, Ripple also performs poorly given that the development of RippleNet is not led by a community development team but by a centralized entity, namely the Ripple company. In the “Open Financial System” requirement, Ripple performs poorly in terms of decentralization. As I’ve mentioned in my &lt;a href=&quot;(http://storeofvalueblog.com/posts/what-is-ripple-and-should-you-invest/)&quot;&gt;Ripple analysis article&lt;/a&gt;, RippleNet is still quite centralized. Finally, in the “Token Sale Structure” requirement, Ripple performs poorly in terms of Team Ownership given that the Ripple team currently owns at least 50% of the total supply of XRP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, XRP does look like a great candidate for a Coinbase listing but an investor should definitely not trade on the hopes that it will go on Coinbase soon. Unless, of course, you want to front run all the other speculators but it’s a bit late for that right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 16:52:06 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/this-is-why-ripples-price-is-surging/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/this-is-why-ripples-price-is-surging/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is Ripple And Should You Invest?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/arrVrRp.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, I’ll refer to RippleNet as the distributed payments network with which XRP is its native currency. I’ll refer to Ripple as the company developing and marketing RippleNet. Keep in mind that most people refer to all three as simply Ripple. However, in the interest of keeping this article sane and not confusing, I found the nuanced terminology necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XRP has been on fire lately. From $0.20 USD per XRP in early December, its price has skyrocketed within a month to $1.13 at the time of writing. To be fair, this increase was driven mostly by a rumour of an impending Coinbase/GDAX listing instead of any significant improvements to its fundamentals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XRP is one of the largest cryptocurrencies out there. It’s been consistently a top 5 cryptocurrency by market cap since April of this year. Besides its most recent bull run and a bull run back in May, XRP’s price has been surprisingly stable with respect to other cryptocurrencies. This is incredibly impressive when you realize that Ripple doesn’t invest significant resources into marketing XRP to retail investors. Instead, the company’s marketing efforts are focused almost solely on enterprise customers like banks and other corporations. This is one of the reasons why I believe XRP has the strongest fundamentals out of any other cryptocurrencies out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that I’ve mostly ignored XRP due to its price stability but its recent price action has caught the attention of many investors, me included. I realized that I actually know very little about it so I spent the last few days researching XRP. Here’s a summary of what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-ripplenet&quot;&gt;What is RippleNet?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feet-summary&quot;&gt;10,000 feet summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/dlenHgZ.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Like Bitcoin, RippleNet is a partially decentralized and distributed ledger.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RippleNet, in its current state, is not decentralized. Although the network has potential for a higher degree of decentralization, Ripple’s use of a default and recommended “Unique Node List” that contains a series of Ripple-operated validators makes the network centralized. Ripple has laid out a decentralization plan where they’d like to remove the default Unique Node List altogether and encourage the community to build their own lists.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are at most 100 billion XRPs in existence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;XRP is a deflationary currency. No new XRPs will ever be created and the fee paid for each transaction is actually burned.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All XRPs were created in the network’s inception and originally owned by Ripple. The company has since distributed a significant percentage of XRPs to investors, exchanges, and other institutions. The remaining XRPs have been locked away in a Ripple escrow. A billion XRPs are released by the escrow every month.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is no mining equivalent in RippleNet; you can run a Ripple validator node but validating transactions will not reward you with XRP.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Validators can vote on the network’s base transaction fee.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RippleNet has incredibly low fees. The current base transaction fee is 0.00001 XRP. The actual transaction fee increases based on the load on the network.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RippleNet has a 4 second transaction confirmation time, which is incredibly fast compared to Ethereum’s 2 minute confirmation time and Bitcoin’s 10 minute confirmation time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RippleNet can consistently handle 1,500 transactions per second, with an upper limit of 50,000 transactions per second. This is comparable to VISA. Ethereum can consistently handle about 15 transactions per second, with an unbounded upper limit (the caveat is that it takes significant time for Ethereum’s network to adjust its maximum transaction throughput). Bitcoin can only handle up to 7 transactions per second.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anyone can issue new assets onto RippleNet. For example, a bank could issue a token representing a real-world currency like USD or EUR. Companies can issue tokens on RippleNet to run ICOs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RippleNet has a built-in decentralized exchange for all the custom assets on the network.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ripple has many banking partnerships but it’s a common misconception that banks are actually using RippleNet or XRP. In fact, most banks today are building instant payment infrastructure on a Ripple product called xCurrent that has no relationship to RippleNet or XRP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-the-point-of-xrp&quot;&gt;What’s the point of XRP?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XRP serves as the native currency of RippleNet as well as an anti-spam mechanism. RippleNet accounts need to have a minimum of 20 XRP in order to submit transactions to the network. This is known as the account’s “reserve” and is one way the network protects itself from spam. Another spam protection mechanism is the set fee each transaction needs to pay in order to be accepted by the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XRP also plays a crucial role in one of the main use cases that RippleNet is advertised for by Ripple. Specifically, RippleNet is great at introducing forex liquidity for banks which will make low-value but high demand cross-border payments like remittances economical for banks, even from low volume currency corridors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many banks avoid supporting a wide range of currency corridors for remittance payments. This is primarily because the current global payments insfrastructure is slow, error prone, and costly. These payments need to occur across different banking systems operating in different timezones often with a low level of coordination. Banks also don’t want to store capital in multiple foreign nostro accounts, denoted in foreign currencies, in order to service low-value remittance payments. This is especially true for low volume currency corridors like the Afghan dollar-New Zealand dollar corrider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ripple believes that RippleNet solves this problem through the XRP currency and RippleNet’s fast, secure, and transparent payments infrastructure. In the RippleNet-supported global payments infrastructure, instead of banks maintaining nostro accounts or the use of expensive and slow correspondent banks for currency corridor payments, banks could just maintain a pool of XRP and make markets directly between its domestic currency and XRP. To issue a currency corridor payment, a bank simply needs to sends its XRP through RippleNet to the foreign bank which will be able to convert the XRP back to its own domestic currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This significantly reduces the number of intemediaries involved which speeds up the transaction, lowers fees, and reduces the chance of errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ripplenets-consensus-protocol&quot;&gt;RippleNet’s consensus protocol&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RippleNet’s ledger consists of a series of mini ledgers, each containing a set of transactions. The mini ledgers are created by and voted on by RippleNet’s validator nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consensus process for mini ledger occurs over multiple rounds. Each round, the validator nodes broadcast their version of a mini ledger to their peers and the votes are tallied. The process ends when a super majority of the participating validator nodes (more than 80%) agree on a mini ledger. The new mini ledger is then added to the overall ledger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RippleNet’s consensus protocol differs from the traditional cryptocurrency mining in two primary ways. First, RippleNet doesn’t have a built-in monetary incentive for people to run Ripple validator nodes whereas successfully mined Bitcoin and Ethereum blocks reward the miner with Bitcoin/ether. Second, consensus in RippleNet is achieved through a voting process whereas consensus in Bitcoin and Ethereum is achieved through competition and mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because there is no incentive to run validator nodes, and consensus is achieved through a voting process, the network is more vulnerable to attacks than a traditional proof of work or proof of stake system. As such, it requires a higher degree of centralization than the traditional systems in order to ensure security. The benefits of this consensus protocol is that it can be significantly faster than traditional systems and there is no risk of forks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-ripple&quot;&gt;Why Ripple?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;powerhouse-list-of-investors&quot;&gt;Powerhouse list of investors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ripple has a powerhouse list of investors. Investors in the company include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CME Ventures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Standard Chartered Bank&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Andreesen Horowitz&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Santander InnoVentures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accenture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avant Global&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And many more: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/ripple-labs/investors/investors_list&quot;&gt;www.crunchbase.com/organization/ripple-labs/investors/investors_list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ripple-is-a-mature-and-sizeable-company&quot;&gt;Ripple is a mature and sizeable company&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/5YRBxoU.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For other cryptocurrencies, I would often look at their GitHub repo and their cofounders’/developers’ backgrounds to make sure they’re legitimate, professional, and still working on the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ripple, on the other hand, is a mature company currently with around 200 employees. The company is headquartered in San Francisco with offices in New York, London, Sydney, India, Singapore and Luxembourg. RippleNet also has a long history, being first released in 2012. As such, there is no doubt of the project’s legitimacy, professionalism, and whether people are still working on it or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;extensive-banking-and-corporate-partnerships&quot;&gt;Extensive banking and corporate partnerships&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/tYAZKK2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ripple focuses its marketing to enterprise customers such as banks and corporations. To say they’ve been successful at it is an understatement. Ripple has one of the most extensive portfolio of banking and corporate partnerships of all other cryptocurrency projects. There are simply too many for me to list but here are some very notable partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is, however, important to keep in mind that most of these banks are not working with RippleNet nor XRP. They’re using Ripple’s xCurrent product which is a secure messaging protocol that’s very useful for coordinating interbank payments but does not touch RippleNet nor XRP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SBI Holdings is a Japanese financial services company with a 10% stake in Ripple. Both companies have formed a joint venture named SBI Ripple Asia which is currently leading a consortium of Japanese banks in testing a pilot project where interbank payments are processed on Ripple’s RC Cloud product (RC Cloud is built on xCurrent). This pilot project was deemed successful and the consortium of banks have now partnered with two major South Korean banks in using RC Cloud for cross-border payments in another pilot project that will take place throughout December. If successful, the project is planned to go live on January 31st, 2018. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sbigroup.co.jp/news/2017/1206_10906.html&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Global Payments Steering Group (GPSG) was formed in 2016 to “oversee the creation and maintenance of Ripple payment transaction rules, formalized standards for activity using Ripple, and other actions to support the implementation of Ripple payment capabilities”. Members of the group include: Bank of America Merrill Lynch, Santander, UniCredit, Standard Chartered, Westpac Banking Corporation, Royal Bank of Canada, CIBC, and the Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi UFJ. According to this &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinjournal.net/banks-unite-around-ripple-launch-new-cross-border-wiring-service/&quot;&gt;CoinJournal article&lt;/a&gt;, the group plans to launch a cross-border wiring service, most likely also built using RC Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ripplenets-longevity&quot;&gt;RippleNet’s longevity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting property of Ripple is that, currently, there will ever be at most 100 billion XRPs ever in existence. In addition, the XRP paid as a fee for a transaction is burned so the more the network is utilized, the faster XRPs are burned. This means that XRP is a super deflationary currency which puts into question RippleNet’s longevity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this state, RippleNet has a finite lifespan as the XRPs will eventually run out, even if you factor in decimal points. Computers can only handle so many decimal points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, this immense deflationary pressure makes XRP conducive to hording and banks might eschew XRP if they find it increasingly expensive to use. Also, why would a bank use its XRP pool for interbank payments if its more profitable to just hold on to them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;is-ripple-centralized&quot;&gt;Is Ripple centralized?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are concerns that RippleNet is centralized. First of all, XRP is a pre-mined cryptocurrency where the entire supply was originally owned by Ripple before the company doled out some to investors, exchanges, and other institutions. Ripple still holds on to 50 billion XRP locked in a RippleNet escrow that releases 1 billion XRP every month for Ripple to spend. What would you do with $1 billion every month for the next 50 months? Sounds like a great lottery prize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have also been concerns of centralization with Ripple’s validator nodes. The concerns are partially valid. Ripple validators use what’s known as the Unique Node List (UNL) to find trusted validator nodes. Every participant in the network can have their own UNL but Ripple provides a default and recommended UNL. This Ripple UNL used to contain only Ripple-operated validator nodes but Ripple is currently executing a decentralization plan where they intend to slowly replace Ripple-operated validator nodes in this list with third party nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The network is currently centralized in that most validator nodes use Ripple’s default UNL and Ripple has full control of what nodes can be on the list. However, it’s important to keep in mind that network participants always have the option to use their own UNLs. At the moment, RippleNet is quite centralized, with Ripple as the single point of failure. But the network has potential to be much more decentralized and Ripple has signalled that it wants to steer the network towards more decentralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read about Ripple’s decentralization strategy here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ripple.com/dev-blog/decentralization-strategy-update/&quot;&gt;https://ripple.com/dev-blog/decentralization-strategy-update&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read about how Ripple validators and UNLs work here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ripple.com/technical-faq-xrp-ledger/&quot;&gt;https://ripple.com/technical-faq-xrp-ledger/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;stellar-vs-ripple&quot;&gt;Stellar vs Ripple&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stellar is a close competitor to RippleNet. Both networks share the same cofounder, Jed McCaleb. McCaleb had a fallout with the other executives at Ripple and decided to build his own network by forking RippleNet’s code base. He named the project Stellar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stellar and RippleNet have diverged significantly. Although both networks still share fundamental capabilities and performance characteristics, there are several key differences. These differences include different consensus algorithms (Stellar decided to develop its own) and the fact that XLM is an inflationary currency, with the maximum supply increasing by 1% every year, while XRP is deflationary, with a fixed maximum supply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also important differences between the mission and strategies of Ripple and the Stellar foundation, the organizations behind RippleNet and Stellar respectively. Ripple is focused on enterprise adoption and is spending most of its efforts in building B2B products on top of RippleNet in order to attract banks and other corporations. Stellar is focused on the open source community and is spending most of its efforts in building a thriving open source developer community through building impressive developer documentation, holding developer meetups, and encouraging companies to hold ICOs on its platform. This is why Ripple has so many more banking partnerships compared to the Stellar Foundation whereas Stellar is a lot more developer friendly and there are many “smaller players” using the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following Stellar though, you’d know that IBM has been making headway using the Stellar network in its own new interbank payments system. The system is currently in the pilot phase being used by a banking network in Oceania that includes 12 currency corridors. Although this is substantial for Stellar, it still pales in comparison to what Ripple brings to the table as far as banking partnerships are concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I speculate that IBM, which generates significant revenue from its banking products, feels threatened by Ripple and is using its more open-source-friendly cousin, Stellar, to build a competing product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://storeofvalueblog.com/posts/stellar-lumens-what-is-it-and-should-you-invest/&quot;&gt;link to my review of Stellar&lt;/a&gt; if you want to learn more about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 00:04:16 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/what-is-ripple-and-should-you-invest/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/what-is-ripple-and-should-you-invest/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CryptoKitties - The Aftermath</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/fIdMxYr.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CryptoKitties was a craze that sweeped the cryptocurrency world a few weeks ago. For those that don’t know what it is, here’s a quick primer: CryptoKitties is a popular new Ethereum-based decentralized application where users can buy, trade, and breed virtual cats on the blockchain. Check out the dApp here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cryptokitties.co&quot;&gt;cryptoKitties.co&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cryptokitty is represented as a string on the blockchain which the cryptokitty website turns into an image of a cat. Parts of the string determines what “cattributes” the cryptokitty has. Cattributes range from minor ones like eyebrow position to major ones like having the body of a chicken. Breeding cryptokitties is similar to breeding cats in real life, the offspring has a mix of cattributes from its parents but there’s no guarantee which cattributes will be there. Certain cattributes are more coveted, and thus expensive, than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;massive-success-in-the-start&quot;&gt;Massive success, in the start&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dApp (decentralized application) that combines cats, the blockchain, and unregulated market fit for rampant speculation? How can CryptoKitties not succeed? For the first couple weeks after its launch, the cryptocurrency community went wild. It was so popular mainstream media caught on as well, with publishers like Quartz, Motherboard, Techcrunch, and CBS publishing articles about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People went wild for trading and breeding cryptokitties. Cryptokitties with rare cattributes were snatched off the market and either bred in hopes of getting more cryptokitties with rare cattributes or sold when the price rose. And the price did rise, spectularly. From an average daily price of 0.02 ether per cryptokitty, average daily price peaked at 0.40 ether per cryptokitty. The most expensive cryptokitty went for 247 ether on December 2nd, which was $111,150 at the time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CryptoKitties was so popular it began severely clogging up the Ethereum network. Ethereum’s average transaction throughput is around 15 transactions/second (technically it’s dynamic as miners can vote to increase or decrease the block size). Interacting with the CryptoKitties dApp requires sending Ethereum transactions and so many people were playing, Ethereum’s network couldn’t keep up. Daily average pending transactions rose from 1,500 transactions to 11,000 transactions. CryptoKitties at one point accounted for 25% of Ethereum traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of December 12th, barely two weeks after CryptoKitties launched, it had more than 150,000 users, processed over $15 million USD in transactions, and there were 260,000 cats in existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;kitty-23&quot;&gt;Kitty #23&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/prK6xgV.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best examples of the irrational exuberance surrounding CryptoKitties is Kitty #23, which was flipped for more than 210 ether (about $94,500 at the time) over 4 days. It was first sold for just 10 ether, before being sold for almost 70 ether (60 ether profit for its second owner!), and it was finally sold for 133.9 ether. It’s current owner has a sale open for the cryptokitty at 100 ether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;133.9 ether was worth around $60,000 at the time. And for what? A string on the blockchain that was turned into a cat picture on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;was-it-just-a-fad&quot;&gt;Was it just a fad?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CryptoKitties fell from prominence as fast as it rose. Take a look at these charts below (found on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kittyexplorer.com/stats/&quot;&gt;www.kittyexplorer.com/stats&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a peak of 4833 transactions per day on December 4th, CryptoKitties processed just 201 transactions on December 21st.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a peak average daily price of 0.4 ether per cryptokitty on December 4th, the average price on December 21st was just 0.04 ether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at those price curves, I’m almost tempted to say CryptoKitties resembles the Tulip craze, except that instead of taking place over 5 years, it took place over 2 weeks. But this is not fair. While other Ethereum dApps are full of promises, CryptoKitties is one of the first dApps that saw tremendous usage. Sure there was a short term mania egged on by the allures of making money, but the bubble popping doesn’t mean CryptoKitties doesn’t have a future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/4TEti3g.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although CryptoKitties will probably not see the same popularity it did in its first couple weeks, I’m confident it will continue to maintain and grow a devout following, especially with so many new people getting involved in cryptocurrencies. It is, after all, the first dApp that introduced cats to the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;wikileaks&quot;&gt;Wikileaks?!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting to note that WikiLeaks recently got into CryptoKitties by buying their own Gen 0 cryptokitties, named Mr. WikiLeaks and Mrs. WikiLeaks. They’re planning to sell the offspring of Mr. and Mrs. WikiLeaks to raise money. They’ve so far gifted a cryptokitty to Donald Trump and one to Hillary Clinton. Some of Mr. and Mrs. WikiLeaks cryptokitties that are on sale include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NSA Spying Kitty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Iraq War Kitty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CIA Vault7 Kitty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check it out here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://wikileaks.shop/pages/cryptokitties&quot;&gt;https://wikileaks.shop/pages/cryptokitties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 03:55:38 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/cryptokitties-the-aftermath/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/cryptokitties-the-aftermath/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Looked Into NEO&#39;s Code Base - What I Found Should Worry Any NEO Investor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/2KVHtc9.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The presence of these hardcoded values in the code base means that the entire NEO network relies on the existence of the 7 servers that the NEO team runs and if any of these servers were to shut down, the network shuts down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I begin, I’d like to remind the reader about what makes cryptocurrencies fundamentally valuable. With so much euphoria and new blood in the market, it can often be incredibly easy to lose sight of the fundamentals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the 2008 financial crisis occurred, Western central banks began something known as Quantitative Easing (QE) to dig Western economies out of the recession. What was QE? It was fundamentally the mass printing and distribution of fiat money. This extra money was quickly channeled into investment assets such as stocks and real estate. It was the only way to prevent inflation from gobbling up your net worth. The heavy influx of QE money explains how the equity markets rebounded so quickly after the crash and why the equity markets today are arguably highly overvalued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although QE brought us out of the recession, it also highlighted the fundamental problem of treating fiat money as a store of value. Fiat money was controlled by central banks and these banks could reduce its value on a whim. Imagine putting 40 hours a week into a job, earning x dollars, placing the money into a savings account, and having it devalued when the banks decides to print more money. How shitty of a feeling is that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;enter-bitcoin&quot;&gt;Enter Bitcoin&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2009, barely a year after the market crash, Satoshi released the whitepaper, &lt;em&gt;Bitcoin: A Peer-to-Peer Electronic Cash System&lt;/em&gt;. This paper introduced the world to one of the most revolutionary economic paradigms since the advent of money. Bitcoin was a way to &lt;strong&gt;store and transfer value over the Internet quickly and securely without needing a middleman and without having to trust a central authority&lt;/strong&gt;. The supply was fixed and the entire ledger was transparent. Bitcoin could not be controlled or taken away by any one entity. It was controlled by democratic consensus and as long as the Internet existed, Bitcoin existed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was crazy! Bitcoin was everything fiat money was not. For once, the people had complete control of the monetary system in which they were a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin achieved all this through a powerful distributed consensus algorithm that upholds majority rule without making any assumptions on who the participants in the system are. This algorithm ensures decentralized control since it allows anyone to be a miner and for miners to enter and leave the system as they please. Majority rule ensures trustless security since participants don’t need to trust any one specific miner. They only need to trust that the majority of miners will do the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin’s transparency, decentralized control, and trustless security is what makes it so attractive and powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;et-tu-neo&quot;&gt;Et tu, NEO?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/zwwCbN9.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin set the standards with which all future cryptocurrencies were evaluated on. After all, if the cryptocurrency relied on a central authority, it was no better than fiat money lying in a database run by a bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was why I was so disappointed to find out that NEO was so incredibly centralized. Investing in NEO was akin to investing in a number in Da Hongfei’s personal database. I tried to get the word out by writing a couple blog posts but NEO’s investors insisted that I was just “spreading FUD” and that NEO was worth as much as or even more than Ethereum!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO currently has 7 validation nodes across the entire network. All 7 nodes are controlled by the development team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this, the NEO investor would rebute by saying, “so what? they promise to decentralize by Christmas”. The only problem is, decentralization here means the NEO team would give a few of these nodes to the City of Zion, an entity with extremely close ties to the NEO team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decentralization implies that anybody with the means to run a validation node should be able to run one. This is core to the spirit of cryptocurrencies and core to their valuation. How does a network decentralize control and uphold majority rule when the participants need to obtain permission from the developers to run a validation node?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;neo-is-not-ready-for-any-kind-of-decentralization&quot;&gt;NEO is not ready for any kind of decentralization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO’s consensus algorithm is called the Delegated Byzantine Fault Tolerance algorithm, or dBFT. dBFT requires the number of nodes in the system to be fixed and known globally. Additionally, every validation node needs to know about the location of every other validation node. &lt;strong&gt;If any node goes offline, consensus cannot occur and the blockchain will effectively shut down.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO’s team argues that a decentralized model can still be built around this system by allowing the community to vote in the validation nodes. If a validation node went offline, the blockchain would stop but the community could just vote in a new validation node.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, NEO’s code base is far from being ready to run this model. I poked around NEO’s code base and discovered that the total number of validation nodes, 7, and the addresses of each validation node, were hardcoded into the code base. Additionally, the official NEO wallet also relied on these hardcoded values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/hhV3KeB.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The presence of these hardcoded values in the code base means that the entire NEO network relies on the existence of the 7 servers that the NEO team runs and if any of these servers were to shut down, the network shuts down.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is insane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/frFVam0.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the October incident when NEO’s blockchain shut down for several hours? Now I know exactly why. One of more of the consensus nodes run by the NEO team broke down and consensus could not be achieved. The NEO team had too manually go in and reboot that machine to keep the lights running in this fake cryptocurrency pyramid scheme they’ve set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO is not a cryptocurrency, NEO is a centralized database with no capability of decentralizing any time soon. NEO is also a 3 year old project with a $4 billion marketcap. What the fuck is going on?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also explains why the NEO team is so reluctant to open up the validation servers to the public. They can’t! They’re only able to give a few to the City of Zion and make sure that the City of Zion never, ever shut down any of the validation nodes they’re running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, NEO giving the City of Zion a few validation nodes to run is not decentralization. it’s just a formal agreement between two entities and is analogous to Netflix running their servers on Amazon! Decentralization by Christmas? It’s just a show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The City of Zion practically confirms my findings in their &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/proof-of-working/decentralization-from-coopetition-b10d7ce3b9d&quot;&gt;latest blog post&lt;/a&gt; on decentralization. In the blog post, they state:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All nominees for consensus nodes will go through a rigorous identification process before being voted in on MainNet. This process includes providing identification that can hold the owners of the consensus node host legally liable. Each node requires exactly two managing legal entities (individuals or institutions) that will be responsible for their maintenance and patching. There will also be a requirement to provide contact availability to ensure that time-critical events can be handled if they arise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Parties that demonstrate they can maintain consensus nodes with outstanding uptime and performance will be voted in as initial MainNet consensus nodes after identification process is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, it was already a huge red sign when an individual can be held “legally liable” if they were to run a consensus node. Now it makes complete sense. If the individual can’t keep the node running, NEO’s blockchain stops and it’ll severely hurt the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;people-without-technical-backgrounds-continue-to-promote-neo&quot;&gt;People without technical backgrounds continue to promote NEO&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will notice that many YouTubers and Reddit users continue to shill NEO. They don’t understand the technology behind it and continue to pump out poorly researched videos and comments proclaiming that NEO is a top-of-the-line cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/2bSS1B0.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reality is, NEO is far from it. I’ve had my suspicions for a long time about NEO’s problems but never truely understood the nuances. Luckily I have a software engineering background and was able to scrounge up some time to look into NEO’s code base to understand how the whole thing works. What I found should worry any NEO investor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO is a 3 year old project. The degree of centralization that permeates the project is utterly unacceptable. Its code base is nowhere close to being ready for decentralization. It is not a cryptocurrency and is far from being worth a $4 billion market cap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Checkout my other blog posts on this subject:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/major-neo-redflags/&quot;&gt;https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/major-neo-redflags/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/neo-responded-to-my-article-and-it-confirms-my-worst-fears/&quot;&gt;https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/neo-responded-to-my-article-and-it-confirms-my-worst-fears/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 22:57:16 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/how-centralized-is-neo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/how-centralized-is-neo/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Is IOTA And Should You Invest?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/gX1qV7b.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: I don’t own any IOTA, haven’t owned IOTA in the past, and don’t plan to own any IOTA in the future.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.strawpoll.me/14596154&quot;&gt;poll&lt;/a&gt; a week ago asking my readers what cryptocurrency I should review next. IOTA received 40% of the votes and won by a wide margin. I’ve since spent several hours researching IOTA and compiling everything I’ve learned in this article. I hope you find it helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although IOTA is currently in consolidation, it has seen a tremendous run-up in price this month. From a price of $1.27 at the start of December, IOTA’s price went as high as $5.34. At the time of writing, it’s price is at $3.90. Rising up more than 500% in 2 weeks is no small feat and there must be something very impressive about this nascent platform. Through my research, I’ve found many great things about IOTA that certainly justifies the excitement around it, I’ve also found several red flags that any serious investor cannot ignore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IOTA was founded by David Sønstebø, Sergey Ivancheglo, Dominik Schiener, and Dr. Serguei Popov. It has a fixed maximum supply of 2,779,530,283,277,761 IOTA. IOTA’s unique data structure and consensus algorithm sets it apart from traditional blockchains while giving it very special and attractive properties. Whereas traditional blockchains consist of a globally consistent linked list of blocks, IOTA uses a DAG or directed acyclic graph. A DAG is a fancy term for a network of nodes. Each connection between two nodes is unidirectional and the connections are acyclic (i.e. you cannot start from one node, traverse the connections in the graph, and get back to the same node). The use of a DAG allows IOTA to have the almost “too-good-to-be-true” properties of unlimited scaling and zero-fee transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put together, the DAG and IOTA’s consensus algorithm is known as the Tangle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;tangle-in-laymans-terms&quot;&gt;Tangle in layman’s terms&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/nLQKW1j.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In traditional blockchains, such as Bitcoin and Ethereum, transactions are agnostic to the consensus algorithm. Users broadcast transactions and miners package them into blocks to be added to the system through proof of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Tangle, the consensus algorithm is an intrinsic property of using the ledger. There is no separation of users and miners. &lt;strong&gt;Every user is a miner and every miner is a user. How does that work? Well every time a user wants to send a transaction in the Tangle, his/her wallet needs to validate two prior transactions.&lt;/strong&gt; In other words, if you want to use the Tangle, you need to be a miner. Keep this in mind, this is a very important property of IOTA with both positive and negative implications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned above, the Tangle’s underlying data structure is a DAG. As such, the nodes of the DAG are transactions and the connections between two nodes represents a validation. For example, if transaction B connects to transaction A, transaction A validated transaction B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In traditional blockchains, the confirmation time of a transaction depends on the blockchain’s average block time and the fee a user is willing to pay. In the Tangle, a transaction’s confirmation time depends on the usage of the network. With low usage, a transaction will take longer to get validated since there are fewer new transactions that will validate it. With high usage, a transaction will get validated faster since there are more new transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;does-iota-have-trustless-security&quot;&gt;Does IOTA have trustless security?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An important question anyone needs to ask for a cryptocurrency consensus algorithm is how does it protect itself from double spend attacks? This is always a complex topic and an in depth explanation can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.iota.org/t/iota-double-spending-masterclass/1311&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In sum, a double spend attack is prevented by relying on at least two thirds of the network being good actors that select only valid transactions to reference. Any short term inconsistencies in the tangle are quickly overcome by the collective weight of honest users referencing valid transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is a very important caveat here. Since there isn’t a separate “miner class” in IOTA and validation is done through the users of the network issuing transactions, IOTA needs to be heavily used in order to be secure. If there is a lull in transaction frequency, there is a lull in security. I elaborate on this further in the &lt;em&gt;Red Flags&lt;/em&gt; section of the blog post but in sum, because IOTA is a relatively new cryptocurrency with very low network usage, the IOTA Foundation has to run what is known as a Coordinator that dictates the network’s progress. This effectively centralizes the network and significantly reduces its value proposition as a cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If IOTA is able to significantly bump up network usage and shed off its reliance on the Coordinator, it’ll become a truly decentralized network with trustless security. In its current state, it’s centralized without trustless security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;internet-of-things&quot;&gt;Internet of Things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because IOTA theoretically has unlimited scalability with zero-fee transactions, it’s particularly suitable for the Internet of Things (IoT) applications. Specifically, devices can trade exact amounts of resources, as well as store data from sensors and dataloggers cheaply, quickly, and securely on the network. This is great for IoT devices that often need to broadcast and receive large amounts of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;iota-is-quantum-proof&quot;&gt;IOTA is quantum proof&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IOTA is quantum proof. This means that quantum computing cannot theoretically break IOTA’s public-key algorithm. However, this also introduces a dangerous quirk to the system for those unaware. In order to be quantum proof, IOTA uses something called the Winternitz OTS which reveals 50% of an address’s private key every time a transaction is sent from that address. As such, it is not advised to send IOTA from the same address multiple times. This is known as the “address reuse” mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this wasn’t made clear in the official IOTA wallet and many users have made the this mistake. I remember a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/CryptoCurrency/comments/7gwl38/hello_guys_i_have_lost_30k_in_iota_and_i_would/&quot;&gt;Reddit post&lt;/a&gt; where the poster claimed to have lost $30,000 worth of IOTA and had no idea how it happened. Turns out s/he made the address reuse mistake. This was posted at the start of December, right before the price jumped from $1 to $5. Ouch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that IOTA’s public addresses are meant to only be used once, the number of unsafe public addresses will grow at an exceedingly fast pace. Luckily, the space of all possible addresses is insanely large so there’s no need to worry about the number of safe addresses running out any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;flash-channels&quot;&gt;Flash channels&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, IOTA has deployed to production its own version of the Lightning Network called Flash Channels. Flash Channels are a bi-directional off-Tangle payment channel to enable instantaneous, high-throughput transactions. If this is true, it is incredibly impressive as Bitcoin and Ethereum haven’t been able to deploy their own versions of off-chain payment channels (technically Ethereum has deployed μRaiden but it’s a stripped down version of a full off-chain payment channel solution).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only problem is, I haven’t been able to see any real applications of IOTA’s Flash Channels. I’ve tried visiting &lt;a href=&quot;https://satoshipay.tangle.works/&quot;&gt;IOTA’s demo site&lt;/a&gt; where they have blog posts containing paywalled content that needed to be unlocked through a flash channel payment. However, even though the UI indicated a channel will be opened typically within 15 seconds, I was not able to open a channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IOTA also had a flash channel integration with SatoshiPay but that announcement was made in September 24th and nothing new has been announced since. I wonder if IOTA and SatoshiPay’s integration has stalled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;iota-foundation&quot;&gt;IOTA Foundation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IOTA Foundation presides over IOTA. It’s a German non-profit corporation that coordinates and funds the development of IOTA. As of November 2017, the Foundation has a fund consisting of 5% of the total IOTA supply that’s worth $100 million as of November 2017. The fund is used to promote the development of a technological ecosystem around IOTA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Foundation is led by the co-founders of IOTA: David Sønstebø, Sergey Ivancheglo, Dominik Schiener, and Dr. Serguei Popov.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;corporate-interest-in-iota&quot;&gt;Corporate interest in IOTA&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SatoshiPay began exploring the replacement of Bitcoin with IOTA as the company’s settlement network in July 2017. This comes after Bitcoin’s fees and confirmation times have increased significantly due to an increase in adoption of the network. Bitcoin continues to experience significant congestion today. SatoshiPay’s efforts to integrate IOTA has stalled recently in favour of the Stellar network. The IOTA + SatoshiPay integration is stuck at phase 2 of 3 phases and it is unclear whether SatoshiPay will choose Stellar over IOTA.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In August 2017, the IOTA Foundation forged a partnership with REFUNITE, the world’s largest missing persons database, in order to use IOTA technology to help reunite families during and after conflicts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In August 2017, Monster Cleaning Services, a London UK based company, announced that they are accepting IOTA as a payment.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In August 2017, Sopra Steria, a European information technology consultancy company with 40,000 employees, announced a partnership with IOTA to create a framework to optimize security between devices on the Internet of Things.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In November 2017, LATTICE80, a Singapore based Fintech hub and largest of its kind, cemented an agreement to open an IOTA innovation lab for the Internet of Things.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In November 2017, IOTA announced its Data Marketplace. It’s an ambitious project that aims to create a market where individuals and companies can buy and sell data. Suppliers can setup sensors connected to the Tangle that will feed data to the market. Buyers can then ingest this data from the market for a small fee paid to the seller. The project is currently undergoing a 2-month-long pilot phase with several corporations and institutions participating including: Accenture, Fujitsu, Bosch, farmforce, and the University of Oslo. Read more about the project &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.iota.org/iota-data-marketplace-cb6be463ac7f&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;data-marketplace&quot;&gt;Data Marketplace&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/VJ9FPM0.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Data Marketplace was made possible only because of the Tangle’s unique properties of unlimited scaling and zero-fee transactions. This allows IoT devices to continuously inject a large amount of data into the network quickly and cheaply, which creates a highly efficient market where the only supply-side cost is the electricity needed to run IOTA’s node software and to perform proof of work every time a transaction is issued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;red-flags&quot;&gt;Red flags&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve encountered several red flags in the IOTA project that cannot be ignored. The project promises a lot and presents the Tangle as this new revolutionary cryptocurrency paradigm that will phase out blockchain technology. However, as with many things in the cryptocurrency space, there is a disconnect between marketing and reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;iotas-security-and-centralization-problem&quot;&gt;IOTA’s security and centralization problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tangle only provides security guarantees if an attacker doesn’t have more than 33% of the hashpower of the network. The only problem is, this is incredibly easy to do on IOTA since it doesn’t have dedicated miners. Remember that validation in IOTA only happens when a user sends a transaction (a transaction can only be issued if it validates two previous transactions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, an attacker will often find it very easy to muster up more than 33% of the network’s hashpower. This is especially true in times of low network usage. If there is a lull in the transactions being issued on the Tangle, there is a drop in the network’s total hashpower. This is not true for blockchains, which tends to maintain a very steady level of hashpower regardless of the number of transactions being issued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IOTA’s team knows about this inherent security flaw and has created a special node called the Coordinator that only they could operate. The Coordinator’s stated main purpose is to “protect the network until it grows strong enough to sustain against a large scale attack from those who own GPUs”. It does so by issuing special transactions called Milestones that are expected to be treated as a source of truth by normal IOTA nodes. Any transactions referenced by Coordinator-issued Milestone transactions are considered valid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The existence and necessity of a Coordinator makes IOTA incredibly centralized and demonstrates a fundamental security flaw of the network. The only way IOTA can dig itself out of this hole is to significantly increase network usage and this is where the Data Marketplace comes in. If the project is successful, there should be hundreds of thousands if not millions of data sensors issuing transactions on the Tangle to feed data into the market, which will significantly increase and stabilize network usage. If the project fizzles out, IOTA will need to rely on the Coordinator for its foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to support zero-fee transactions and unlimited scaling, IOTA tightly coupled users and miners. However, we’ve demonstrated that this is not a cure-all solution and it brings with it its own flaws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ercwl/iota-is-centralized-6289246e7b4d&quot;&gt;https://medium.com/@ercwl/iota-is-centralized-6289246e7b4d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;curl-fiasco---disregarding-cryptographic-best-practices-and-founders-demonstrating-a-lack-of-integrity&quot;&gt;Curl fiasco - disregarding cryptographic best practices and founders demonstrating a lack of integrity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number one rule of cryptography is to not “roll your own crypto”. Cryptographic functions rely on a great deal of security and existing, well-used functions have gone through years of vetting and testing to ensure that they are on the cutting edge of security. By rolling your own function, you’re eschewing all of this, thus introducing significant risk of security vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this is exactly what IOTA chose to do. They rolled their own custom hash function called Curl. Lo and behold, an MIT team led by Neha Nerula demonstrated significant vulnerabilities in Curl. They found that Curl produced hash collisions in a predictable way (different inputs hash to the same output) and the team was able to “find collisions using commodity hardware within just a few minutes, and forge signatures on IOTA payments”. The MIT team reported this to IOTA’s team and the bug was swiftly patched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would have been a minor hiccup in IOTA’s development had it not been for Sergey Ivancheglo’s (IOTA co-founder) incredibly weird response to the whole situation. He claimed that the security vulnerabilities in the Curl hash function was, in fact, deliberate. The vulnerability was inserted as a “copy protection” to prevent copycat projects and to allow the IOTA team to compromise those projects if they sprang up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is very sketchy and demonstrates a lack of integrity on the part of the co-founder. Introducing flaws to the system so that IOTA can kill competitors is completely against the spirit of both open source development and the cryptocurrency community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most puzzling aspect of the situation is the fact that the co-founders were willing to expose IOTA’s network to such a drastic flaw in the first place. People are transacting their hard earned money on the network and the developers thought it was wise to introduce a massive security flaw just so IOTA couldn’t be copied? That should enrage any user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/why-i-find-iota-deeply-alarming-934f1908194b&quot;&gt;https://hackernoon.com/why-i-find-iota-deeply-alarming-934f1908194b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;iota-data-marketplace-pr-fiasco&quot;&gt;IOTA Data Marketplace PR fiasco&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When IOTA released its launch marketing for the Data Marketplace project, there was a widely disseminated article by a third party publisher that claimed that Microsoft was “partnering” with the IOTA Foundation in building this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this turned out to be objectively false and IOTA was simply using Microsoft’s Azure platform to host the Data Marketplace. In essence, IOTA was a customer of Microsoft instead of a partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was surprising was the IOTA team’s silence around the matter for the first few days that the article was out. During that time, IOTA’s price pumped from $1 to $5. It was not until a new article came out alleging that no such partnership existed did the IOTA team respond and confirm the allegation. The IOTA team’s delayed response in squashing the rumours is questionable and negligent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-use-of-a-balanced-ternary-numeral-system-is-questionable&quot;&gt;The use of a balanced ternary numeral system is questionable&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IOTA’s codebase uses a balanced ternary numeral system. So instead of having only 0’s and 1’s like binary, balanced ternary has -1’s, 0’s, and 1’s. IOTA’s developers defend this decision by stating that ternary processors are theoretically more efficient than binary processors and that certain mathematical constructs are more cleanly represented in balanced ternary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the only problem is almost all modern hardware runs on binary systems. You’ll be hard pressed to find one balanced ternary processor anywhere. This means that all of IOTA’s internal ternary notation needs to be encapsulated in binary, resulting in significant storage and computational overhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this is clearly a questionable technical decision, as long as everything works without any drastic performance issues, the balanced ternary system is actually not that bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackernoon.com/why-i-find-iota-deeply-alarming-934f1908194b&quot;&gt;https://hackernoon.com/why-i-find-iota-deeply-alarming-934f1908194b&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IOTA is an ambitious and technically impressive project. It’s promise of unlimited scaling and zero-fee transactions is particularly enticing, especially for Bitcoin users that are currently seeing transaction confirmation times and fees sky rocket. However, it is not without its shortcomings. The network is definitely not secure in its current level of adoption and needs to be centralized to keep it afloat. The Data Marketplace project is a great initiative that not only brings tremendous utility to the network but also decentralizes it. However, it is important to keep in mind that if the project fails, IOTA will remain centralized for the foreseeable future. I also have some reservations on the maturity and leadership skills of the project’s co-founders. Besides these issues, I think IOTA is a very strong and exciting project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 21:20:21 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/iota-what-is-it-and-should-you-invest/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/iota-what-is-it-and-should-you-invest/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Crazy Things That Have Happened With Cryptocurrencies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/1U5R2HC.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin’s whitepaper was released just 8 years ago in 2009. Since then, one Bitcoin’s price has climbed up to $11,000 and thousands of other cryptocurrencies have popped up alongside it. This meteoric rise has polarised public opinion around this new digital asset class. Those who are invested in cryptocurrencies are diehard fans (who more often than not are making a crap ton of money) while those who don’t are adamant that cryptocurrencies are a scam and equivalent to tulips in the Dutch Tulip mania.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not surprising many are adamant that cryptocurrencies are a scam. It’s really the wild wild west in such a nascent market. With a lack of regulation, low fees trading, skyrocketing prices, and investors who are often quite liberal with their wallets, there is rampant speculation and scams abound. Additionally, cryptocurrencies have a cold and unforgiving user interface that doesn’t mesh well with clumsiness and large sums of money can be lost in an instant with a single typo or misclick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put all this together and you have the perfect breeding grounds for some incredible and jaw dropping stories. Here are some of the craziest things that have happened in the cryptocurrency community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;bitcoins-price-drops-3000-in-6-hours&quot;&gt;Bitcoin’s price drops $3000 in 6 hours&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ZtlukW8.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of this most recent bull run, there was one point when Bitcoin finally broke through $10,000 and hit a peak of $11,485 on GDAX. The ensuing euphoria was swiftly shattered when Bitcoin suddenly plunged $3000 as profit taking peaked and long postion after long position were liquidated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;user-accidentally-locks-out-more-than-1-million-ether-worth-280-million-at-the-time&quot;&gt;User “accidentally” locks out more than 1 million ether (worth $280 million at the time)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/U7rbwqt.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parity wallet offers multi-signature wallets as a service. Multi-signature wallets are great because of their security and many ICOs and wealthy organizations/individuals use Parity wallets to store their Ether battle chests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in November, one user was playing around with one smart contract that turned out to be a critical dependency for all Parity multi-signature wallets created since July 20th. This effectively locked out all ether in these wallets. This amounted to more than 1 million Ether locked out worth around $280 million at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The infamous user subsequently went on Gitter and wrote “i’m eth newbie..just learning”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/0b0pp9A.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;an-eager-ico-investor-spends-236-eth-in-fees-and-still-fails-to-get-into-the-airswap-ico&quot;&gt;An eager ICO investor spends 236 ETH in fees and still fails to get into the AirSwap ICO&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/vdKIqV4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During an Ethereum-hosted ICO, especially a popular one, the network can become exceedingly congested as a large number of investors attempt to send their ether to the ICO’s smart contract in order to purchase the ICO’s tokens. Transaction fees during this time can skyrocket, leaving low fee transactions in the dust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one evidently very rich user decided to guarantee him/herself a spot in the popular AirSwap ICO by spending 236 ether in transaction fees in order to buy 1,700 ether worth of AirSwap tokens. Unfortunately, the transaction was sent too late and the overall ICO funding cap was hit before the user could purchase the AirSwap tokens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transaction was cancelled, leaving the user 236 ether poor. Although the 1,700 ether in the transaction came back, the 236 ether was paid as a transaction fee and was not recuperable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Checkout the transaction on EtherScan here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://etherscan.io/tx/0x167b6e3217536e66e69f906a457b2457c6cc4f95928a47b0443ad895b23c6e76&quot;&gt;https://etherscan.io/tx/0x167b6e3217536e66e69f906a457b2457c6cc4f95928a47b0443ad895b23c6e76&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-bitcoin-exchange-gets-hacked-for-850000-bitcoins&quot;&gt;A Bitcoin exchange gets hacked for 850,000 Bitcoins&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/OFr0PSt.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MtGox was one of the first major Bitcoin exchanges. Due to mismanagement and poor coding practices, hackers were able to slowly siphon hundreds of thousands of Bitcoins from MtGox’s reserves. By the time the company found out, 850,000 Bitcoins were lost. This was worth over $460 million at the time and $14.4 billion today at $17,000 a coin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trading was halted in February 2014 and in April 2014, the company began liquidation proceedings. At one point in time, MtGox was handling 70% of all Bitcoin transactions worldwide. The hack triggered a year-long bear market in which the price of Bitcoin dropped from $1000 to $200.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the largest Bitcoin exchange hack, ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-large-market-sell-order-on-gdax-causes-the-price-of-ether-to-drop-from-320-to-01&quot;&gt;A large market sell order on GDAX causes the price of ether to drop from $320 to $0.1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/mMKcgON.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happened earlier in the summer when a trader placed a multimillion dollar market sell order on GDAX that caused a massive dip in price, which started a huge chain reaction of stop loss orders being hit and margin funding liquidations. The price of Ethereum on GDAX briefly hit $0.1 from $320.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rdogecoin-sponsors-a-nascar-racer&quot;&gt;/r/dogecoin sponsors a NASCAR racer&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/NCcewoU.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A campaign started in /r/NASCAR to sponsor John Wise’s No. 98 Phil Parsons Racing for the NASCAR Sprint Cup Series race at Talladega Superspeedway in May 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An unlikely subreddit decided to step up and crowdfund a sponsorship: /r/dogecoin. The amount needed for the sponsorship was $55,000, at the time worth 100,541,093.89 Dogecoins. One user accidentally donated 20,000,000 Dogecoins instead of the 2,000,000 he intended (a difference of $13,500) but stood by his decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The $55,000 was reached with more than 1,200 redditors participating. Wise’s NASCAR was decorated with a Dogecoin themed skin and he gave an AMA on /r/dogecoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;an-obscure-youtuber-convinces-thousands-to-pump-and-hodl-chaincoin&quot;&gt;An obscure YouTuber convinces thousands to “Pump and HODL” Chaincoin&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/psn4kFG.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YouTuber HighOnCoins started a movement earlier this year called “Pump and HODL”. He convinced his community to start buying Chaincoin and holding it. The movement obtained some virality and caused its price to pump from $0.04 to $6 in a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chaincoin was an abandoned project that traded on a couple exchanges with a daily volume under $100,000. HighOnCoins was a YouTuber that often looked disheveled whilst smoking and drinking during his streams. His selling point was that whales controlled all the major cryptocurrencies and were wringing the noobs dry, so this was the chance for the noobs to take control. But guess what? Him and all his followers that got in at the start were the Chaincoin whales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I documented the timeline of events of the Chaincoin pump and dump scam in this blog post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/timeline-of-the-chaincoin-scam/&quot;&gt; 
Timeline Of The ChainCoin Scam - Massive Cryptocurrency Pump And Dump Scheme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;exploring-old-posts-in-rbitcoin-brings-current-price-levels-into-perspective&quot;&gt;Exploring old posts in /r/Bitcoin brings current price levels into perspective&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/zbm7nGa.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was posted in April 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 05:06:20 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/crazy-things-that-have-happened-in-crypto/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/crazy-things-that-have-happened-in-crypto/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NEO Responded To My Article - And It Confirmed My Worst Fears</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/XY4DDTO.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night, Malcolm Lerider, a “Senior R&amp;amp;D Manager” for NEO, wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@MalcolmLerider/response-to-baseless-fud-9b7e5e2eeeea&quot;&gt;medium post&lt;/a&gt; in response to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/major-neo-redflags/&quot;&gt;“Investor Warning: Major NEO Redflags” post&lt;/a&gt;. And it confirmed my worst fears about NEO and its management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neo-is-embarrassingly-centralized-for-a-2-year-old-3-billion-project&quot;&gt;NEO is embarrassingly centralized for a 2 year old, $3 billion project&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/18X8d53.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my blog post, I argued that a major NEO red flag was its centralization, that there were only 13 validation nodes all controlled by NEO’s team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malcolm confirmed this and even one-upped me. He stated that NEO doesn’t have 13 validation nodes, it only has 7! My whole point was that NEO shouldn’t be this centralized after 2 years in the wild and it definitely brings into question whether a $3 billion valuation is fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, it also doesn’t matter whether they plan to decentralize the system or not. Of course they plan to do so. If they didn’t, NEO would be worth nothing. The essence of the problem is that NEO isn’t decentralized after so long and that’s very weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;limiting-the-number-of-consensus-nodes-should-not-make-the-blockchain-faster---thats-a-sign-of-a-broken-protocol&quot;&gt;Limiting the number of consensus nodes should not make the blockchain faster - that’s a sign of a broken protocol&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/myEv9I5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So NEO is supposed to be fast and operate alongside regulation. It’s supposed to achieve this by balancing the number of consensus nodes. But how does limiting the number of consensus nodes make the blockchain faster? If you knew anything about the blockchain, you would know that increasing consensus nodes only ever increases security. The network speed is only determined by the design of the protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Bitcoin, for example, its protocol dictates that blocks are generated in 10 minute intervals with block size capped at 1mb. Bitcoin’s protocol can be changed to have blocks generated every 2 minutes with an unlimited block size. This would significantly increase Bitcoin’s network speed. On the other hand, the world can have 100,000 or 1,000,000,000 Bitcoin nodes and it won’t affect network speed. That is the whole point of the blockchain, that everyone can run a node and the more people that do run a node, the more secure the network is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If NEO is a system that gets slower the more consensus nodes there are, then it has a broken blockchain protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neos-response-claims-that-the-october-blockchain-outage-was-misinformation-then-agrees-that-it-happened&quot;&gt;NEO’s response claims that the October blockchain outage was misinformation, then agrees that it happened&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/dbaLme5.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malcolm first declares my claim that the blockchain was offline in October was misinformation. Then he surprisingly proceeds to agree that it did, and that the outage was caused by “human error”. Everyone saw the effects of this error. No blocks were generated for several hours and that creeped out investors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how is it misinformation if the October blockchain outage did happen, and NEO’s team did need to shut down the network to perform “manual checks”? Answer: it’s not misinformation, it’s what happened and it’s incredibly scary that NEO’s team can, at a moment’s notice, bring down the entire network. This is wrong, this is not blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neos-reponse-shows-a-lack-of-understanding-of-how-software-development-works-confirming-that-the-lack-of-github-activity-is-a-huge-problem-for-neo&quot;&gt;NEO’s reponse shows a lack of understanding of how software development works, confirming that the lack of GitHub activity is a huge problem for NEO&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/zkYRmOE.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two ridiculous claims are made here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, Malcolm claims that he would be concerned if there were still daily protocol changes done to a production main net. That is completely ridiculous! Look at Bitcoin and Ethereum. Daily commits are being made to their GitHub repos, sometimes more than 10 commits a day. Bitcoin Core constantly releases new versions of their client. So does go-ethereum. A big perk of cryptocurrencies is that the community can constantly contribute to and improve the protocol through contributing to public code repositories, whether they be hosted on GitHub or elsewhere. To say that people should not be committing code to NEO’s main GitHub repo because its main net is live is nonsensical and demonstrates a lack of understanding of how software development works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, Malcolm claims that instead of committing to the main repo, NEO’s team likes to work with “forks”. Now I have been a software developer for several years now and this statement makes absolutely no sense. Forks in Git’s protocol are used by external parties looking to work on their own version of the code. For example, Litecoin’s code base was a Git fork of Bitcoin Core’s code base. No software development team iterates on their software by constantly forking their code in Git. That’s utterly ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Malcolm is talking about Git’s branch feature, which are forks internal to a Git repository, then it would make more sense. Alas, NEO’s GitHub repo currently only has 3 branches. And the 2 other branches besides the master branch have been practically abandoned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this passage, Malcolm demonstrates a lack of understanding of software development and because of this lack of understanding, throws out 2 completely absurd claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neos-response-claims-that-neo-only-works-for-the-rich-yet-the-rich-doesnt-want-to-work-on-neo&quot;&gt;NEO’s response claims that NEO only works for the rich, yet the rich doesn’t want to work on NEO&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/rE3QTd3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made the claim that there were only 6 smart contracts on NEO’s blockchain. Malcolm not only confirms this but also states that anyone who can’t pay a 500 GAS fee to deploy a smart contract will likely deploy one that is “useless”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are millions of amazing software developers out there that don’t have tons of money lying around to afford a 500 GAS fee. Why is NEO discarding them? How can NEO be an open blockchain where anyone can participate if it costs a fortune to do something as mundane as deploying a smart contract!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what about the people that can afford 500 GAS? Why is no one deploying smart contracts on NEO’s production main net? Surely such a revolutionary smart contract platform where smart contracts can be coded in multiple languages will attract lots of developers right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neos-response-claims-that-knowing-bittrex-bitfinex-and-binance-is-mostly-used-by-westerners-is-insider-information&quot;&gt;NEO’s response claims that knowing Bittrex, Bitfinex, and Binance is mostly used by Westerners is insider information&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How is this insider information? It was made public that Binance “no longer allows Chinese customers to trade on the exchange”, and 82.5% of users on the exchange are located abroad. It’s also common knowledge that Bittrex and Bitfinex cater to the West. Bittrex, for example, states on its website that it’s an exchange “based and fully regulated in the USA”. It doesn’t even have multilanguage support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;we-do-not-want-to-hype-yet-we-make-announcements-of-announcements-causing-rampant-speculation&quot;&gt;“We do not want to hype”, yet we make announcements of announcements causing rampant speculation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/1SPktdu.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malcolm was the person who posted the “big announcement in 3 days” poster on Twitter. This caused wild rumours to circulate that the announcement would be something related to Chinese government regulations. This pushed NEO’s price up from $30 to $45.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now he has the gall to come out and say that he doesn’t want to hype, and that it’s up to the community to judge. You know what? Some very powerful regulators are looking at this behaviour and they will also judge. Some people bought NEO at $45 because of this poster and they are hurting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/JAdifMx.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;finally&quot;&gt;Finally…&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never seen anyone in any professional setting use the inane and childish term “FUD”. I was honestly quite surprised the article would be titled “Response to baseless FUD”. It’s also hilarious that the article calls my work “baseless FUD”, and then proceeds to confirm several of my points!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 13:47:45 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/neo-responded-to-my-article-and-it-confirms-my-worst-fears/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/neo-responded-to-my-article-and-it-confirms-my-worst-fears/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Investor Warning: Major NEO Redflags</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/0XsrvAF.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been following NEO closely since this summer when it was still called Antshares. I was incredibly impressed by the project at the time. Its super fast transaction times, smart contract capability, gas generation, and the possible support from the Chinese government made NEO incredibly attractive. However, after a combination of further research and observation of the project’s progression, I’ve identified a series of major red flags surrounding NEO and my opinion on the project has soured considerably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neo-is-incredibly-centralized-the-entire-network-only-has-13-validating-nodes-developers-whitelist-who-can-run-validating-nodes&quot;&gt;NEO is incredibly centralized. The entire network only has 13 validating nodes. Developers whitelist who can run validating nodes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/PnmOlEw.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core value proposition of a cryptocurrency is its decentralized and trustless nature. It is this property that enables users to store their funds securely on the network without needing to trust anyone else. For this to be possible, any user must be able to operate nodes to validate transactions in the network without having to be approved by a central authority. For example, both the Bitcoin and Ethereum networks have thousands of validation nodes running at any one time upholding network security. Even QTUM, a relatively new cryptocurrency, has more than a thousand validation nodes running concurrently (1,319 nodes at the time of writing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO, however, has only up to 13 concurrently running validation nodes in the entire network. How can this be the case? I was incredibly dismayed to discover that NEO’s team hand-picks operators of their validation nodes. In fact, I believe that all validation nodes are currently exclusively run by the team. This is alarming. How can a blockchain project that is more than 2 years old with a market cap of more than $3 billion only have 13 validation nodes? Why is the public not allowed to participate in upholding the security of the network? Two years is a very, very long time in the cryptocurrency world and there is simply no excuse for this degree of centralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can checkout the network’s validation nodes here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://monitor.cityofzion.io/&quot;&gt;https://monitor.cityofzion.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neos-blockchain-disappeared-for-several-hours-in-october&quot;&gt;NEO’s blockchain disappeared for several hours in October&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/A9vahBl.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because all 13 of NEO’s validation nodes are controlled by its development team, the team was able to shutdown the entire blockchain at a moment’s notice and they did so for several hours earlier in October. During that time, no blocks were generated and the lack of communication left many people confused and scared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official reason for the blackout? NEO’s team had to shut down the network in order to perform “manual checks” after unlocking 15 million of the 50 million NEO that the team held in reserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neos-github-has-alarmingly-sparse-activity&quot;&gt;NEO’s GitHub has alarmingly sparse activity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, the last commit to NEO’s GitHub repo happened 16 days ago. Think about it, more than half a month since the last time the project was updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the last 3 commits to the repo are incredibly inane and insubstantial. Look at the last 3 commit messages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An attempt at improving the English translation (November 2nd)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fix Grammer (November 1st)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confusing spacing (November 1st)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/3LGUlsM.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An inactive GitHub repo is one of the first signs of an abandoned project. Compare this to Ethereum, Bitcoin, Waves, Stellar, and QTUM. There are commits almost every day for these projects. What are NEO’s devs doing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT 1: some people are arguing that even though NEO’s GitHub is inactive, CityOfZion’s GitHub is very active. One needs to understand that CityOfZion builds peripheral tools in NEO’s ecosystem which, at a fundamental level, do not improve NEO’s fundamental blockchain technology. To say that CityOfZion’s developer activity makes up for NEO’s inactivity is like saying Bitcoin is fine if blockchain.info’s developers are still working when all Bitcoin client developers have stopped working (Bitcoin Core is an example of a Bitcoin client). Blockchain.info helps us explore the blockchain, Bitcoin clients are the software running Bitcoin’s nodes and miners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT 2: some people have claimed that NEO’s team doesn’t use GitHub. This is blatantly false since (a) the NEO team has been working in this repository since NEO’s inception and (b) there continues to be (sparse) activity in the repository. If the NEO team doesn’t use GitHub, why commit anything there at all? There’s no good reason to consistently make inane changes to an abandoned code repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neo-only-has-6-smart-contracts-operating-on-the-entire-blockchain&quot;&gt;NEO only has 6 smart contracts operating on the entire blockchain&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/2IEEl6v.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO, a project that is 2 years old, only has 6 smart contracts deployed on its mainnet. In fact, up until October, the only 3 smart contracts on NEO were test contracts deployed by NEO’s lead developer, Erik Zhang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this what a thriving smart contracts ecosystem should look like? Should NEO, a 2 year old, $3 billion smart contract platform have only 6 smart contracts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can checkout all of NEO’s smart contracts here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://neotracker.io/browse/contract/1&quot;&gt;https://neotracker.io/browse/contract/1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-east-has-almost-no-interest-in-neo---90-of-neos-volume-comes-from-the-west&quot;&gt;The East has almost no interest in NEO - 90% of NEO’s volume comes from the West&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/o0mrbKc.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were to visit NEO’s subreddit, you’ll see everyone talking about how NEO has connections with the Chinese government and that the government might be open to using NEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This cannot be more false. NEO is a little known project in China with minimal connections to the government. You’ll quickly realize this after asking around in Chinese cryptocurrency forums and messaging groups. Additionally, look at NEO’s volume distribution, &lt;strong&gt;more than 90% of NEO’s volume comes from Bittrex, Binance, and Bitfinex, three exchanges used mainly be Westerners.&lt;/strong&gt; There is close to zero interest for NEO in Eastern exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can anyone say that NEO is a Chinese project at this point? Almost all of NEO’s investors are from the West and many of them were duped into thinking NEO has a chance in the East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neo-attracts-questionable-icos-and-dapps&quot;&gt;NEO attracts questionable ICOs and dApps&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO released its smart contract 2.0 system in August. Until October, only 3 projects announced that they will be building on NEO, and all of them are incredibly sketchy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first project, AdEx, looks incredibly bad. They announced that they would switch from Ethereum to NEO. This announcement subsequently pumped the token’s price from $0.30 to $2.45. It has since dropped back to $1. I looked over AdEx’s GitHub repo and I don’t like what I see. No only is there very few commits, all of the commits are incredibly unsubstantial and consists of copy changes and adding image assets. Additionally, the team still has a Solidity code in the repo and continue to make commits in November referencing Solidity. Hold on? Solidity is Ethereum’s smart contract language. Where is the code for NEO integration? Why is the team still working with Solidity. AdEx is a project with a $60 million market cap. I’m scared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://imgur.com/3Q46SHN.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second project, Red Pulse, was NEO’s first ever ICO. The project appears to be incredibly sketchy as well. &lt;a href=&quot;https://steemit.com/redpulse/@thecryptohomie/buyer-beware-red-flags-on-the-red-pulse-ico&quot;&gt;Here’s a blog post&lt;/a&gt; detailing its many red flags. For example, the team claims that their 2-year-old non-cryptocurrency service has more than 60,000 subscribers, yet their iOS app only has 1 review. The company’s CEO has also apparently said that RPX can only appreciate in value because other people might consider RPX to be valuable. In other words, the CEO basically admitted that most of RPX’s value derives from speculation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other project, Aphelion, looks even worse. Even devout NEO investors have raised red flags on the project. The team is incredibly small. It consists of 3 founders and that’s it. What’s hilarious is that there are 10 advisors, meaning the project’s advisors outnumber the project’s employees by more than 3 to 1! For a project with so little people working on it and almost no work in progress, its ICO asks for an incredible $30 million. That’s $10 million per founder. It would be too exhausting to list everything wrong about this project so I’ll just link a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7c35ks/aphelion_is_probably_a_money_dump/&quot;&gt;comprehensive post from NEO’s subreddit&lt;/a&gt; (267 karma, 96% upvoted), on why this project is likely a “money dump”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aphelion is NEO’s second ICO. It’s clearly shaping up to be a giant scam and it’s incredibly worrying that no one from the NEO team has warned NEO holders about Aphelion. You can’t build a thriving smart contract ecosystem on top of scams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neo-makes-announcements-of-announcements&quot;&gt;NEO makes announcements of announcements&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making announcements of announcements have become one of the most frowned upon activities in the cryptocurrency world. Doing so purely serves to introduce unhealthy speculation into the market and pump a token’s price. Several projects have already been burned by their communities for doing so in the past few months (e.g. OmiseGo and TenX) and have since stopped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO, on the other hand, continues to engage in this unethical behaviour. The project recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MalcolmLerider/status/931521977839505408&quot;&gt;released a poster&lt;/a&gt; stating that something big will be announced in 3 days. This caused NEO’s price to pump from $28 to $45 in a single day. Completely. Unhealthy. Speculation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s incredibly uncomfortable seeing NEO’s team encouraging speculation and rumours to manipulate the market. This is the kind of activity that forces governments to introduce harsh regulations. Just look at what happened in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neo-is-a-blockchain-built-purely-on-promises-and-rumours-there-is-no-substance&quot;&gt;NEO is a blockchain built purely on promises and rumours. There is no substance.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be clear as day by now that everything associated with NEO is filled with rumours and promises. There is no substance. Nothing really works or creates value in any way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be careful of what you buy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 05:46:24 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/major-neo-redflags/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/major-neo-redflags/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bitcoin vs Bitcoin Cash: Everything You Need To Know</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/lljVhhv.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recent cancellation of SegWit2x and the rapid rise in Bitcoin Cash’s price ($600 to $2000 in 2 days) coupled with a sharp drop in Bitcoin’s price has once again put the spotlight on the intense feud between Bitcoin and Bitcoin Cash. Many questions have arisen around the two cryptocurrency giants as people scramble to understand the situation. This blog post hopes to answer the most common questions as succinctly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-bitcoin-cash&quot;&gt;What is Bitcoin Cash?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Cash is a fork of Bitcoin’s blockchain with two primary changes: an 8mb maximum block size and an emergency difficulty adjustment feature (EDA). The EDA checks, after every block, how long it took to mine the last 6 blocks. If it took over 12 hours, the EDA will drop the mining difficulty by 20%. Bitcoin, on the otherhand, adjusts block difficulty after every 2016 blocks. Each block is set to take approximately 10 minutes to mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EDA was added to Bitcoin Cash to ensure that the new chain won’t stagnate from a lack of hashing power; a dynamic difficulty adjustment algorithm will quickly bring Bitcoin Cash’s difficulty down enough such that it’d be more profitable to mine Bitcoin Cash. This would attract Bitcoin miners to switch to the new chain, albeit as long as the EDA keeps the difficulty low enough. With Bitcoin Cash’s hashing power stabilizing since its turbulent release, the EDA was recently removed and replaced with a new block difficulty adjustment algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Cash brands itself as the real Bitcoin. It justifies this with its embracing of larger block sizes which significantly reduces blockchain fees and transaction confirmation times compared to Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;bitcoin-vs-bitcoin-cash&quot;&gt;Bitcoin vs Bitcoin Cash&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;block-sizes&quot;&gt;Block sizes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin’s community believes in smaller block sizes. Why? Because there is a belief that larger block sizes increase centralization by making it more expensive to run full nodes. Larger block sizes result in a faster growing blockchain which increases the amount of space and bandwidth needed to maintain a full node. Bitcoin’s community doesn’t believe that scaling can be reasonably achieved through larger block sizes and should rather be accomplished through second-layer technology (i.e. the Lightning network). Bitcoin’s block size is capped at &lt;strong&gt;1mb&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Cash’s community, on the other hand, believes in larger block sizes. Its community wholly backs blockchain technology and believes that scaling can be achieved directly on the blockchain without significantly increased centralization and without much reliance on second-layer technology. This follows very closely with the original spirit of Bitcoin. Bitcoin Cash’s block size is capped at &lt;strong&gt;8mb&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-can-use-the-blockchain&quot;&gt;Who can use the blockchain?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Cash’s priorities are: (1) everyone can use the blockchain (2) everyone can run a node.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin’s priorities are: (1) everyone can run a node (2) everyone can use the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin’s community believes that since scaling cannot be done on the blockchain, and block space is a commodity that should be kept scarce, certain transactions are more important than others. Low importance transactions have no place on the blockchain and should be handled by second layer technology. Who determines low importance transactions? Blockchain fees should determine transaction importance. A purist in Bitcoin’s community is happy with high transaction fees. This means that smaller microtransactions will be forced to use second layer technology or pay exorbitant fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Cash’s community believes that every transaction is important. Block space should not be a scarce commodity. When demand exceeds supply, the block size should be increased. Blockchain fees should be kept exceedingly low to encourage everyone to use the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;segwit&quot;&gt;SegWit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin has SegWit, a precursor technology to second layer technology like the Lightning network. SegWit also has the peripheral effect of increasing block size by reducing the size of individual transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Cash does not have SegWit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;costs-and-transaction-time&quot;&gt;Costs and transaction time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is currently significantly more expensive and slow to use than Bitcoin Cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because Bitcoin continues to stick with 1mb block sizes while no second layer technology is available to keep up with the demand to use Bitcoin. The closest upcoming technology is the Lightning network but it’s not clear when it will be production ready. The adoption of SegWit has been surprisingly low and stagnant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;subreddits-and-censorship-concerns&quot;&gt;Subreddits and censorship concerns&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin supporters primarily use /r/Bitcoin. Bitcoin Cash supporters primarily use /r/btc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/r/Bitcoin moderators have been accused of rampant censorship on the subreddit on anything that questions the legitimacy of Bitcoin, Bitcoin Core, and Blockstream. Posts that do not discuss Bitcoin Cash in a negative light are also censored. The accusations are very likely true and have even been echoed by prominent cryptocurrency thought leaders like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/930276246671450112&quot;&gt;Vitalik Buterin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some have expressed concern that the spirit of Bitcoin was anti-censorship and control, yet /r/Bitcoin is completely controlled and censored by its moderators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-backs-bitcoin-and-who-backs-bitcoin-cash&quot;&gt;Who backs Bitcoin and who backs Bitcoin Cash?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bitcoin&quot;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is backed by Bitcoin Core developers and the Blockstream company. Bitcoin Core is the predominant Bitcoin client. While Bitcoin Core is an open source project, Blockstream is a company formed by a group of Bitcoin Core developers. The Bitcoin Core developer community overlaps with and has a very close relationship with the Blockstream company. Blockstream provides significant funding for Bitcoin Core development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockstream currently makes money through “consulting work”. They have also developed a sidechain called Liquid that is aimed at providing high-speed transactions between Bitcoin exchanges. Blockstream earns the fees paid to use the Liquid network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockstream raised $55 million in its Series A funding. The most prominent investor in Blockstream is AXA, a French multinational insurance conglomerate. According to Wikipedia, AXA had €68.5 billion in equity in 2015 and 165,000 employees in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charlie Lee, the founder of Litecoin, a blockchain that started on code forked from Bitcoin Core, supports Bitcoin and is a vocal critic of Bitcoin Cash. Litecoin is branded as a cheaper and faster alternative to Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charlie Shrem, an early investor in Bitcoin and entrepreneur, who is a founding board member of the Bitcoin Foundation and currently serves as the Director of Business and Community Development at Jaxx, is also a vocal critic of Bitcoin Cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bitcoin-cash&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roger Ver is a vocal supporter of Bitcoin Cash. Roger Ver is an early cryptocurrency entrepreneur and investor and is currently the CEO of Bitcoin.com. Ver invested over a million dollars in cryptocurrency startups including Ripple, Blockchain.info, Bitpay, and Kraken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gavin Andresen has voiced his support for Bitcoin Cash. Andresen was designated by Satoshi Nakamoto, the pseudonymous inventor of Bitcoin, as lead developer on Bitcoin Core after Nakamoto left the project. Andresen founded the Bitcoin Foundation in 2012 and left his software development role to concentrate on his work with the Foundation in 2014. As of June 2017, he has not contributed to Bitcoin Core since February 2016 and his commit access on GitHub was revoked in May 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vitalik Buterin, the creator of Ethereum and prominent cryptocurrency thought leader, voiced his support for Bitcoin Cash and has even deemed Bitcoin Cash worthy of taking the Bitcoin name in a series &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/930276246671450112&quot;&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Controversial supporters of Bitcoin Cash include large Bitcoin mining companies and their billionaire CEOs and investors. The most prominent member within the ranks of the “Chinese billionaire miners” is Jihan Wu, the founder of Bitmain. Jihan is a vocal supporter of Bitcoin Cash and critic of Bitcoin Core and Blockstream. Bitmain is a company that holds patents on, and manufactures specialized Bitcoin mining hardware. Bitmain also operates AntPool, one of the largest Bitcoin mining pools in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jihan Wu has been accused of supporting Bitcoin Cash in order to maintain his lucrative mining business. Bitmain’s Bitcoin mining technology doesn’t work with SegWit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 01:40:17 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/bitcoin-vs-bitcoin-cash-everything-you-need-to-know/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/bitcoin-vs-bitcoin-cash-everything-you-need-to-know/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Cancelling SegWit2x Could Be (Really) Bad For Bitcoin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; style=&quot;width: 700px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/lljVhhv.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second phase of SegWit2x, where the maximum block size would be raised from 1mb to 2mb, was recently called off. SegWit2x is the result of years of feuding between two major camps in Bitcoin’s ecosystem. The feud revolved around how to scale Bitcoin; as network adoption increased, its abysmal transaction throughput became increasingly evident as transaction fees and first-confirmation times skyrocketed. One camp, consisting of miners and Bitcoin startups, prefers on-chain scaling while the other camp, consisting of Bitcoin Core developers, prefers off-chain scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick summary of the two camps. The on-chain camp supports:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On-chain scaling through larger blocksizes and first-layer blockchain technology like Graphene or BitcoinNG&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1mb to 2mb maximum block size upgrade in SegWit2x&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The off-chain camp supports:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Off-chain scaling by keeping the maximum blocksize at 1mb and leveraging second-layer blockchain technology like the Lightning Network&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SegWit but not the 1mb to 2mb maximum block size upgrade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SegWit2x was supposed to be a compromise between the two groups. The upgrade consisted of two phases. The first phase involved adding the segregated witness technology (SegWit) to Bitcoin. Although SegWit slightly increased the maximum number of transactions per block by reducing transaction size, its main value proposition lies in setting up Bitcoin for off-chain scaling solutions like the Lightning Network. SegWit2x’s second phase involved on-chain scaling through increasing the maximum blocksize from 1mb to 2mb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the first phase of SegWit2x was locked in and activated in August (meaning Bitcoin has SegWit now), the second phase hasn’t been activated and is scheduled to occur in November. That is, until last week when the on-chain camp suspended their plans for the 2mb upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This suspension was partly the result of pressure from a “NO2X” initiative led by the off-chain camp. Part of the initiative consisted of a Twitter campaign encouraging users to append a NO2X tag to their Twitter username as a show of defiance for the 2mb upgrade. I also noticed a strong push against the 2mb upgrade on major cryptocurrency subreddits, /r/Bitcoin and /r/cryptocurrency, as well as on several Western cryptocurrency editorial websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the on-chain camp backing off the 2mb upgrade, it seems that the off-chain camp has won the scaling debate and successfully implemented SegWit on Bitcoin without a corresponding change in Bitcoin’s maximum block size. However, is this really good for Bitcoin? Does the off-chain camp’s success translate to Bitcoin’s success, or is this actually a veiled defeat for Bitcoin that has disastrous consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s why I think it’s the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;hurt-branding---almost-childish-refusal-to-implement-a-small-network-upgrade&quot;&gt;Hurt branding - almost childish refusal to implement a small network upgrade&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This refusal to move forward with a simple 1mb to 2mb maximum block size upgrade emphasizes how childish this entire scaling debate has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked about the reasons to not increase the block size, pundits would give you answers such as a rushed hard fork, no replay protection, or more centralization. Not only are all these points moot (which I will address later), but why weren’t alarm bells raised immediately after the New York Agreement was signed! The NYA was signed in May of this year leaving so much time for the NO2X’ers to voice their concerns but they didn’t. Instead, they waited till after everything they wanted out of the compromise was in Bitcoin, namely the SegWit upgrade, when they decided to raise their concerns with SegWit2x’s second phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s why this is wrong in so many ways, and why it ultimately hurts Bitcoin’s brand. First of all, SegWit2x was a formal agreement that was aimed at finally making peace between the on-chain scaling and off-chain scaling Bitcoin communities. This was supposed to be a kumbaya moment where everyone came together to make Bitcoin better. Instead, the off-chain camp decided to backstab the on-chain camp after SegWit was in Bitcoin. How shitty is that? And how terrible does this look on Bitcoin to outsiders? Not only that, but the off-chain camp is fighting against something so incredibly trivial it looks like they’re just trying to spite the other party. Let’s be honest here, a 1mb to 2mb maximum block size increase is a harmless upgrade to Bitcoin and it is definitely not worth fighting over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Not only that, but the off-chain camp is fighting against something so incredibly trivial it looks like they’re just trying to spite the other party. Let’s be honest here, a 1mb to 2mb maximum block size increase is a harmless upgrade to Bitcoin and it is definitely not worth fighting over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even worse, the off-chain camp, after vehemently opposing increasing the maximum block size, doesn’t provide any immediate alternatives to alleviate Bitcoin’s ongoing network congestion. Yes, the Lightning network could make everything better, but when is it coming out?! In the meantime, what about existing Bitcoin users and businesses? With more than 100,000 pending transactions in the mempool, Bitcoin has become unusable. The off-chain camp doesn’t seem to be interested in improving Bitcoin right now, all they seem to be interested in is attacking and ostracizing the on-chain camp. Reminds me of high school politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-bitcoin-cash-factor&quot;&gt;The Bitcoin Cash factor&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nomenclature reminder: the on-chain camp supports on-chain scaling where every transaction is considered an important transaction, whereas the off-chain camp supports off-chain scaling where smaller transactions shouldn’t belong on the blockchain and should be offloaded to second layer systems. The on-chain camp supports Bitcoin Cash and SegWit2x while the off-chain camp supports SegWit, 1mb maximum block sizes, and second layer systems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin Cash is an initiative led by the on-chain camp. The blockchain was hard forked from Bitcoin in late August. Here’s my &lt;a href=&quot;https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/bitcoin-cash-how-it-came-to-be/&quot;&gt;post on why and how Bitcoin Cash was created&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circumstances of Bitcoin Cash’s creation was a bit weird. Prior to the Bitcoin Cash hard fork, it seemed that the on-chain camp would only move forward with Bitcoin Cash if SegWit2x was not going to happen, and at the time there definitely was a risk of it not happening. However, once it was practically confirmed that the first phase of SegWit2x was a go, the on-chain camp moved forward with Bitcoin Cash anyways!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of the 1mb to 2mb upgrade fiasco, it makes a lot more sense why the on-chain camp pushed so hard for Bitcoin Cash. Bitcoin Cash is essentially a hedge against the off-chain camp making power plays in Bitcoin, such as with their recent campaign to oppose the second phase of SegWit2x. Whatever happens in Bitcoin, the on-chain camp could still express their vision in Bitcoin Cash. Being a number 3 market cap coin, it poses a very real threat to Bitcoin. There is even a strong possibility that the on-chain camp relented on SegWit2x because they didn’t really need to care about the success of Bitcoin - Bitcoin could continue to experience scaling problems and the on-chain camp would still have Bitcoin Cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of right now, it looks like Bitcoin Cash is set to improve at a significantly faster pace than Bitcoin. Its vision is clear, Bitcoin Cash will primarily scale on-chain with every transaction being an important transaction. Bitcoin, on the other hand, still has a split vision with the ongoing war between the off-chain and on-chain camps. While the off-chain camp might have scored a small victory with the cancellation of the second phase of SegWit2x, the on-chain camp still has a very strong foothold on Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-argument-that-increasing-block-sizes-is-bad-for-bitcoin-because-it-decreases-decentralization-does-not-make-sense&quot;&gt;The argument that increasing block sizes is bad for Bitcoin because it decreases decentralization does not make sense&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The argument that increasing block sizes decreases decentralization simply does not make sense. The idea is that if you increase the block size, the blockchain will grow in size much faster than before resulting in a larger blockchain, which in turn makes it more expensive to operate a node.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is stupid! First of all, just because you increase the maximum block size doesn’t mean blocks will automatically start being larger than before. Block size depends on the usage of the network, if very few transactions are in the mempool, than the next block’s size could be very small!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, if you increase the maximum block size and blocks do start being larger than before, that means that you’ve solved a problem! Transactions are being confirmed earlier than when you had a smaller block size. How is this ever a bad thing? This also means that the blockchain is seeing more use. By arguing that this is bad for Bitcoin is the same as arguing that Bitcoin is worse off the more demand there is to use it. It’s ludicrous! Stopping the growth of Bitcoin’s maximum block size is basically stopping the adoption of Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By arguing that this is bad for Bitcoin is the same as arguing that Bitcoin is worse off the more demand there is to use it. It’s ludicrous! Stopping the growth of Bitcoin’s maximum block size is basically stopping the adoption of Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, increasing the maximum block size from 1mb to 2mb will at most increase the growth rate of the blockchain’s size by 2. At 1mb blocks, the blockchain will theoretically grow by at most 53gb a year (1 * 6 * 24 * 365). At 2mb blocks, the blockchain will theoretically grow by at most 100gb a year. You can already buy 1TB SSDs today at around $250 a piece and storage and bandwidth costs are constantly decreasing. Going from a 1mb to 2mb maximum block size is not going to create a blockchain size problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;segwit2x-shouldnt-need-replay-protection&quot;&gt;SegWit2x shouldn’t need replay protection&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchains are vulnerable to a replay attack after a hardfork. A replay attack consists of replaying a pending transaction in the mempool that was intended for one child chain on the other child chain. For example, after the SegWit2x hard fork, people who held Bitcoin will have both SegWit2x and legacy chain coins. If a user decides to send someone their SegWit2x coins, a malicious actor could take their pending transaction in the mempool and replay it on the legacy chain, which will cause the user to unwittingly send their legacy chain coins as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people claim that the SegWit2x hard fork is bad because it doesn’t have replay protection. The problem is, it shouldn’t need to have replay protection in the first place. This is a simple modification to the maximum block size that will very clearly alleviate existing network congestion pains. Why is there ever a reason to support the legacy chain over the SegWit2x chain? Anybody who does is simply aiming to create more division within Bitcoin instead of helping it improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 1mb to 2mb maximum block size upgrade has an immediate effect of alleviating network congestion in the short term. It comes with little to no downsides for Bitcoin. Why would anybody that has the best interest for Bitcoin support the legacy chain?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-1mb-maximum-block-size-is-an-arbitrary-constant&quot;&gt;The 1mb maximum block size is an arbitrary constant&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 1mb maximum block size is an arbitrarily chosen number a long time ago by Satoshi Nakamoto to counter potential DDoS attacks and to maintain consensus. It’s not a magical, cure-all number that was chosen such that it would ensure decentralization by ensuring x-amount of people in the world can run full nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that its an arbitrary constant, why should Bitcoin not increase the maximum block size to 2mb if its going to allievate network congestion? If the argument is that it would increase centralization, how do we know that the Bitcoin network is not already too centralized at 1mb? If increasing the maximum block size increases centralization, why do we not aggressively decrease the maximum block size… maybe to 0.5mb? Asking these questions should make one realize that its nonsensical to stick with the 1mb maximum block size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1mb is not a magical number, it’s an arbitrary constant. Be flexible and reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;if-youve-enjoyed-this-blog-post&quot;&gt;If you’ve enjoyed this blog post…&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can support the author by tipping some Bitcoin Cash to this address &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;14UFeDBN54pUZTUeyqonpo4j195Q69RvnT&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much thanks if you do, a lot of work and time was put into researching and writing the post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 18:58:01 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/cancelling-segwit2x-defeat-for-bitcoin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/cancelling-segwit2x-defeat-for-bitcoin/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
