<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Store of Value</title>
    <description>In July 2010, one bitcoin was worth $0.08 USD. How much is it worth today? Bitcoin&#39;s meteoric growth has pushed cryptocurrencies from an obscure niche to the mainstream, and created fortunes along the way. Store Of Value is a blog that will help you navigate the cryptocurrency world. As an avid crypto researcher, day-trader, and programmer, I aim to provide in-depth fundamental analyses on cryptocurrencies and help you identify market opportunities. Stay informed. Invest wisely.
</description>
    <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://storeofvalue.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 09:26:25 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 09:26:25 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ancient Romans On Cryptocurrency Investing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/qMfi8oQ.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Romans were not only great at building a global empire, their brightest minds could teach cryptocurrency enthusiasts today a lesson in investing. Here are some pertinent quotes from famous Roman philosophers for cryptocurrency investing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you have overcome your inclination and not been overcome by it, you have reason to rejoice.” - Titus Maccius Plautus (254 BC - 184 BC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plautus was a Roman playwright. This quote warns cryptocurrency investors not to let their inclination to FOMO or panic sell overcome their internal voice of reason. If they didn’t give in, they wouldn’t get rekt and have reason to rejoice in staying wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It is easier to find men who will volunteer to die, than to find those who are willing to endure pain with patience.” - Julius Caesar (100 BC – 44 BC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julius Caesar was a famous Roman general. This quote tells cryptocurrency investors that investing is a game of patience. It’s going to be painful watching their coin stay in a range for days, and then dump to shake out weak hands before pumping back up and stay in a range again. It can’t be perpetually November 2017 but when the next pump comes, the patient will be well rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Those most moved to tears by every word of a preacher are generally weak and a rascal when the feelings evaporate.” - Gaius Sallustius Crispus (86 BC – 34 BC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sallust was the very first man from his provincial plebeian family to serve in the Roman senate. This quote warns cryptocurrency investors not to let social media shilling or FUDing get to them. The shills want you to buy their bags and the FUD’ers want to buy lower. Once your emotions subside, you might’ve just bought the top or sold the bottom. Not ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“An angry man is again angry with himself when he returns to reason.” - Publilius Syrus (85 BC – 43 BC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Publilius was a Latin mime writer. The quote warns of panic selling. When the oversold bouce comes, the only person you can be mad at is yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The lofty pine is oftenest shaken by the winds; High towers fall with a heavier crash; And the lightning strikes the highest mountain.” - Quintus Horatius Flaccus (65 BC – 8 BC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Horace was a Roman lyric poet. FOMO pumps are often followed by large retracements. Look at Bitcoin after pumping from 3k to 20k in a few months last year. It only recently came back up from 6k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Rome has grown since its humble beginnings that it is now overwhelmed by its own greatness.” Titus Livius (59 BC – 17 AD)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin is like Rome. From its humble beginnings of being a small experiment started by an unknown cryptographer and software developer to the multi-billion dollar market cap asset it is today, Bitcoin has come a long way from its humble beginnings. Its tremendous surge in popularity overwhelmed Bitcoin’s transaction capacity, partially resulting in the massive clogging of the blockchain earlier in the year with sky rocketing fees and long confirmation times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Hope is the pillar that holds up the world. Hope is the dream of a waking man.” - Gaius Plinius Secundus (23 AD – 79 AD)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pliny the Elder was a Roman philosopher. He might be the original #HODLGANG member.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If there is a God, whence proceed so many evils? If there is no God, whence cometh any good?” - Anicius Manlius Severinus Boëthius (480 AD – 525 AD)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is a God, why are there 80% retracements? If there is no God, why are there parabolic FOMO pumps?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Nothing happens to any man that he is not formed by nature to bear.” - Marcus Aurelius (121 AD - 180 AD)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, we can’t not have a Roman quote compilation without one from Marcus Aurelius, a famous Roman emperor. In this quote, he might be suggesting that no one is born a bear, which implies that everyone is born an eternal bull. He might also be referring to something else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2018 21:08:55 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/the-romanss-take-on-cryptocurrency-investing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/the-romanss-take-on-cryptocurrency-investing/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Last Year&#39;s Greed Is Rearing Its Ugly Head On Ethereum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/4ogUhmM.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the bear market rages on, with Bitcoin collapsing down to 7,400 after double topping at 11,700. This collapse has pulled down the rest of the market and many cryptocurrencies are hit hard. Ethereum is one of them. From an ETHBTC ratio of just 0.12 in the start of February, the ratio collapsed in March to 0.75 and held steady, before falling again to 0.62. While Bitcoin dropped from 11,700 to 7,400, a 36% drop, Ether dropped from 870 to 460, a 47% drop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethereum’s accelerated freefall has perplexed many investors. Ethereum can do so much more than Bitcoin with its smart contracts and higher transaction throughput. Ethereum has a well defined roadmap and is making consistent progress on it. The Plasma sidechain protocol will soon be released, with OmiseGo being the first Plasma sidechain. Phase 1 of the sharding spec is complete. Casper, Ethereum’s Proof of Stake upgrade, is also well on its way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides a solid protocol roadmap, Ethereum also has the most powerful ecosystem of all other cryptocurrencies. For example, ConsenSys is a large company built around growing Ethereum’s ecosystem. Consensys manages a sizeable portfolio of companies building projects on Ethereum’s ecosystem. The portfolio includes projects like Gnosis, Airswap, Infura, GRID+, and Metamask. Besides ConsenSys projects, there many other high quality projects building on Ethereum’s ecosystem. They include 0x, MakerDAO, Havven, dydx, Augur, and Dharma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why exactly is Ethereum falling so hard?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason, in my opinion, is the greed of 2017 rearing it’s ugly head on Ethereum. Ethereum’s platform was host to a ton of ICOs, games, and scams. Many people participated in them hoping to make a quick buck. ICOs like Filecoin, Tezos, and EOS raised hundreds of millions of dollars in Ether. EOS’s ICO is still happening as we speak. Greed also brought people to participate in questionable games like CryptoCountries and CryptoCelebrities. These “games” were setup exactly like Ponzi schemes, and yet people poured thousands of Ether into them. Finally, greed also led people to participate in blatant scams like EtherTanks, PonziCoin, and Proof of Weak Hands Coin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think these entities will do after receiving so much Ether from greedy Ethereum investors when the market starts dumping? They’ll dump harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, there is strong proof that EOS, an ICO that has raised more than 400,000 Ether, is dumping it on the market right now. The EOS crowdsale wallet has sent more than 163,000 Ether in total to Bitfinex’s wallet, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/claptrapxl/status/975380553653370880&quot;&gt;50,000 of which was sent in the last 12 hours&lt;/a&gt;. It’s incredibly perplexing how Ethereum’s community has not yet outright rejected EOS. EOS is like a leech on Ethereum’s ecosystem, taking Ether to fund its operations in ORDER TO BUILD A PLATFORM TO REPLACE ETHEREUM. How do Ethereum investors find this acceptable at all? In fact, the co-founder of EOS, Dan Larimer, has openly challenged Vitalik Buterin on the efficacy of Ethereum many times in the past. It’s clear that Larimer has little love for Ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that he has his hands on 400,000+ Ether, what do you think he would do? HODL it to keep Ethereum’s investors happy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;moving-forward&quot;&gt;Moving forward&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s clear that the Ethereum community needs to put its foot down and reject any ICOs that try to raise capital with Ether. The best asset to raise capital with is stablecoins, such as Dai, and the community should actively encourage any new ICOs to do so. If most ICOs had raised capital with stablecoins, we would not be in this situation where the price of Ether is at the mercy of so many overnight whales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The community should also actively police scams on the platform. Scams like EtherTanks and Proof of Weak Hands Coin should be quickly reported and labeled as such. Not only are they immediately unhealthy for the platform as they scam investors out of their Ether, they’re unhealthy for the platform in the long term as the scammers sell their Ether on the markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bright side in all this is that Ethereum will survive and it has, without a doubt, the strongest development team, strongest roadmap, and strongest ecosystem of all other cryptocurrencies out there. If anyone really took a deep dive into what people are building on Ethereum, it’s a no-brainer that if cryptocurrencies don’t collapse as an asset class, Ethereum will thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 10:17:14 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/last-years-greed-is-rearing-its-ugly-head-on-ethereum/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/last-years-greed-is-rearing-its-ugly-head-on-ethereum/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Lightning Network&#39;s Elephant In The Room</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/QavGn3X.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lightning Labs is a private company developing Bitcoin’s Lightning network. The company’s CEO, Elizabeth Stark, recently announced the release of the Lightning network on Bitcoin’s mainnet and a modest round of funding (by cryptocurrency standards) of $2.5 million from high profile Silicon Valley executives hailing from companies like Square (Jacqueline Reses and Jack Dorsey), Twitter (Jack Dorsey), RobinhoodApp (Vlad Tenev), and Paypal (David Sacks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The release of the Lightning network beta on Bitcoin’s mainnet was met by much hype and fanfare. This was something promised to Bitcoin’s community for several years now and it’s finally becoming tangible. With the recent blockchain congestion that brought Bitcoin’s network to its knees with super high fees and long block times, as well as the creation of the Bitcoin Cash community that vehemently opposed Bitcoin’s refusal to increase block sizes to relieve congestion, the hint of an imminent release of a viable offchain scaling solution for Bitcoin was highly welcomed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But is the Lightning network as great as many claim it is? The idea is very ambitious but the devil is in the details. There is a significant problem that the network has not solved. Without a solution, the Lightning network cannot become decentralized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-exactly-is-the-lightning-network&quot;&gt;What exactly is the Lightning network?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, what exactly is the Lightning network? It’s a second-layer technology on Bitcoin focused on scaling through state channels. Bitcoin’s community has been stubborn in keeping the 1mb maximum block size that was arbitrarily set by Satoshi Nakamoto in the early days of Bitcoin development. The community believed that raising the block size will reduce decentralization since full nodes will require more space which will be more expensive to setup and maintain. As such, any attempts at raising the block size will start a slippery slope to increasing centralization. As we all know, the archenemy to Bitcoin is centralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This arbitrary block size limit has proved to be insufficient for how popular Bitcoin has become today, with blocks filling to the max with transactions and the mempool clogging up with hundreds of thousands of pending transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of raising the maximum block size to accomodate more transactions, Bitcoin’s community has decided that the best way to scale Bitcoin is with offchain protocols like the Lightning network. Theoretically, the network allows for trustless, secure, and decentralized payments to be conducted over Bitcoin’s network without publishing a transaction in a block. As such, regardless of Bitcoin’s maximum block size, users will be able to quickly transact over Bitcoin without having to pay outrageous fees or wait an outrageously long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lightning network uses a relatively new blockchain technology known as state channels to support offchain transactions. Let’s say Alice, a user that wishes to participate in the network, needs to setup a “payment channel” with another user, Bob, on the Lightning network. To do so, Alice needs to publish a transaction in a block committing some of her bitcoins to the channel with Bob. Bob can also publish a transaction to commit his own bitcoins to the channel. It’s important to note that bitcoins committed to a channel cannot be spent on the blockchain until the channel is closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, a channel is set up between Alice and Bob with a total of A + B bitcoins. Alice has A bitcoins in the channel and Bob has B bitcoins. X = A + B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the magic of cryptography, Alice and Bob can securely send each other Bitcoin over the channel an infinite amount of times without ever touching the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s even more awesome is that if Bob has a seperate payment channel with Charlie, then Alice and Charlie can send bitcoins to each other through Bob without have to setup their own channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking this a little further, imagine the Lightning network had many users and many channels. Theoretically, a user can send funds to any other user on the network as long as there is a path of channels connecting them. This effectively creates a Internet of money over Bitcoin that could scale to an unlimited number of transactions per second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-elephant-in-the-room&quot;&gt;The Elephant In The Room&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/nxdqaCn.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for the Lightning network to work, it needs to be able to route payments from one part of the network to another. Just like the Internet, a user theoretically only needs to maintain one connection (payment channel) to interact with the rest of the network. If a user had to constantly setup channels with other users, than there is no point in using the Lightning network at all since s/he could simply pay via onchain transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only problem is, there is no known efficient solution for decentralized routing. For example, if Alice was separated from Fiona by 5 connections, and Alice wanted to send a payment to Fiona, there is no easy way for the Lightning network to quickly finding a suitable path. In fact, the network really has no way of knowing if there even exists a viable path without having to try all possible paths! Even the Internet, a decades-old technology, has not solved this problem! Internet routing is done via centrally managed routing tables by ISPs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/PjpbW3q.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, the Lightning network’s routing problem is even more complex than the Internet’s. To send a payment, not only does the network need to find a viable route, the connections in between need to have enough liquidity to support the payment. For example, if Alice wanted to send Fiona 1 bitcoin, and the network miraculously found a path from Alice to Bob to Charlie to David to Ellen to fiona, if any of the channels, Alice-Bob, Bob-Charlie, Charlie-David, David-Ellen, and Ellen-Fiona, didn’t have at least 1 bitcoin of liquidity, Alice cannot use this path to send 1 bitcoin to Fiona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, this “liquidity routing” problem is a daunting problem to solve, and one that definitely warrants more discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One might counter by saying that this might not be a problem at all if we kept network topology simple, e.g. having large, highly liquid nodes that everyone connected to so that participants in the network are no more than 2 degrees of separation from each other. Then you realize that this is a highly centralized solution that defeats the whole point of using Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lightning network is currently released as a beta on the mainnet, but if developers cannot solve this “liquidity routing” problem, it might forever be stuck in beta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 3 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3806401153&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-lightning-network-needs-to-be-decentralized&quot;&gt;The Lightning network needs to be decentralized&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am incredibly excited that the Lightning network has finally been deployed on the mainnet. However, the reality is that the network is far from being a viable decentralized payment network. There are a multitude of unanswered questions, some small and some large, that plague the network. The largest of all, in my opinion, is the liquidity routing problem. Without solving this problem, the Lightning network is doomed to become a centralized payment protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 00:33:42 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/lightning-network-elephant-in-the-room/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/lightning-network-elephant-in-the-room/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Deep Dive Into VeChain</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/vkt66gS.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-vechain&quot;&gt;What is VeChain?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VeChain is an up-and-coming Chinese blockchain that currently exists as an ERC20 smart contract on Ethereum. VeChain will be a partially centralized blockchain that uses a “proof-of-authority” system whereby the VeChain Foundation gets to choose who the blockchain’s 101 block producers will be. VeChain will support smart contracts through the Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM). It will also have a unique dual asset economic system with VET and Thor Power. VET is used to generate Thor Power and Thor Power acts as a stablecoin that pays for blockchain operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most standout property of the project is its extensive enterprise partnerships. VeChain has positioned itself as a blockchain-based supply chain management solution, backing up this stance with a powerful partnership with DNV GL. DNV GL is a global quality assurance and risk management company that has so far provided VeChain with access to customers in the Italian wine industry as well as the Chinese tobacco industry. Other VeChain partnerships include BMW, Healthcare Co. Ltd, Kuehne &amp;amp; Nagel, and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-does-vechain-work&quot;&gt;How does VeChain work?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/DbolQS5.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VeChain is a proof-of-authority blockchain. The VeChain Foundation vets block producers and gives them the authority to produce blocks. As you can imagine, this is a very centralized system. Even if there are 101 different block producers in the system, they are all beholden to the whims of the Foundation. This introduces all sorts of questions since the Foundation will essentially have full control of the blockchain. I’ll elaborate on this further in the Project Concerns section below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected, increased blockchain centralization results in increased performance. VeChain has claimed that its blockchain is able to handle up to 10,000 transactions per second. This is an exceptional transaction throughput when compared to Bitcoin and Ethereum, which are both under 50 transactions per second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other benefits of VeChain’s substantial centralization include more stable blockchain governance and a lower risk of forks. With one centralized entity controlling the blockchain’s development direction, disputes within the community are quickly resolved. In addition, given that the Foundation controls who the block producers are, there is virtually no risk of hard forks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vechains-cryptoeconomics---thor-power&quot;&gt;VeChain’s cryptoeconomics - Thor Power&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VeChain aims to stabilize costs of using its blockchain. To do so, the team has introduced a unique economic system in the form of Thor Power. Thor Power is a separate asset on the VeChain blockchain that has a dynamic supply with the intention of keeping prices stable. Thor Power is needed to pay for all blockchain operations including transaction fees and smart contract execution fees. Presumably, the Thor Power paid for blockchain operations is burned. To acquire Thor Power, users will either need to own VET to generate Thor Power or buy it on the open market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, Thor Power’s supply is dynamic. Although it’s currently not clear how the balancing system will work, VeChain’s plan is to adjust the rate of Thor Power generation whenever there’s an imbalance between supply and demand. One can think of Thor Power as VeChain’s native stablecoin, which is analogous to Steem’s Steem-Backed Dollar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every VET will have a base amount of Thor Power generation. Wallets with a certain amount of VET can qualify for different tiers of VeChain economic nodes. Economic nodes generate Thor Power at a higher rate, with higher tiers generating more Thor Power. Current economic node tiers include the VeThor X Node (6k VET), Strength Node (10k VET), Strength X Node (16k VET), Thunder Node (50k VET), Thunder X Node (56k VET), Mjolnir Node (150k VET), and Mjolnir X Node (156k VET).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VeChain block producers will operate what’s known as Thrudheim Masternodes. Thrudheim Masternodes are classified as Authority Nodes and will have the highest rate of Thor Power generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that the price of Thor Power is currently unknown and this could determine how profitable it is holding VET to generate and sell Thor Power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;smart-contracts&quot;&gt;Smart contracts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VeChain plans to introduce smart contracts to its blockchain using the EVM. This is great since existing Ethereum smart contracts will be easily portable to VeChain’s blockchain. It’d be interesting to see how VeChain adapts its Thor Power system to the EVM’s gas system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;supply-chain-management&quot;&gt;Supply chain management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supply chain management is the flagship application for VeChain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to bootstrap VeChain’s supply chain management capabilities, VeChain will be manufacturing its own RFID and NFC chips that will be attached to products to track their passage through the supply chain. VeChain will manufacture several different types of chips suited for different products and supply chains. Some chips will have microsensors in order to detect environmental conditions like temperature and humidity whereas others will be simpler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RFID and NFC chips will be attached to products in order to securely track them on the blockchain. Each chip will have a private and public key pair. The blockchain will store the public key as well as a hash of any data associated with the product. This data could include environmental data, as mentioned before, or data around the passage of the product through the supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the blockchain will only store a hash of a product’s data, the actual data will be stored in CHAOS, a decentralized data encryption and storage solution developed by VeChain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VeChain plans to introduce applications to allow anyone with a product and its associated RFID/NFC chip to fetch the product’s data. For example, a consumer could scan a hand bag’s RFID/NFC chip in order to see its passage through the supply chain and verify that the product was properly handled before they purchased it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vechain-has-many-open-technical-questions&quot;&gt;VeChain has many open technical questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One big concern I have with VeChain is the fact that there are still many open technical questions for the project. The team has provided very few technical details into how its blockchain will work and since the project is entirely closed source, it’s impossible for anyone to find out. There are open questions around how the blockchain will defend against adverse conditions (e.g. when a block producer unexpectedly goes offline or when a block producer is malicious), as well as questions around how the blockchain’s architecture will look like (e.g. how is the EVM adapted to run on VeChain’s blockchain?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-team-behind-vechain&quot;&gt;The team behind VeChain&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The VeChain project is an offshoot of the Shanghai-based Blockchain-as-a-Service (BaaS) company called BitSE. VeChain’s cofounder and CEO, Sunny Lu, used to be BitSE’s COO. VeChain has been in the works for more than two years now and it is a portfolio company of PricewaterhouseCoppers (PwC) China’s incubation program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunny Lu is a charistmatic CEO who has given a series of talks around VeChain. He used to hold executive positions in Louis Vuitton China. Other members of VeChain’s executive team are also quite impressive as well but I won’t iterate through them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VeChain also has a really strong advisory board. The board consists of Bo Shen, a well known blockchain investor who’s the managing partner and founder of FENBUSHI Capital, Jim Breyer, an American billionaire venture capitalist who’s been super bullish on VeChain, Ning Nan, the CEO of BitOcean, and a few others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;vechains-enterprise-partnerships&quot;&gt;VeChain’s enterprise partnerships&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/p3qXAaJ.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic&quot;&gt;Sunny Lu with Luca Crisciotti, CEO of DNV GL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve mentioned above, VeChain is a blockchain project with one of the most extensive enterprise partnerships out there. However, it’s important to note that the details surrounding many of these partnerships are vague and it’s unclear how these partnerships will benefit the long term value of VET.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some key partnerships:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PwC China - VeChain is a portfolio company of PwC China’s incubation program.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DNV GL - a global quality assurance and risk management company. The company has extensive ties with VeChain and has so far connected VeChain with the Italian wine industry and the Chinese tobacco industry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Italian wine industry - My Story is an off-the-shelf blockchain based digital assurance solution for the food and beverage industry developed by DNV GL and VeChain. The first customers of My Story are Italian wine producers, Michele Chiarlo, Ricci Curbastro, Ruffino and Torrevento. These wine producers will feature the My Story label on their wine bottles, which will contain VeChain hardware tags, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@vechainofficial/my-story-the-first-ever-3rd-party-initiated-developed-and-managed-dapp-on-vechainthor-61deb8839e0d&quot;&gt;by the end of the year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;National Research Consulting Center (NRCC) - DNV GL has connected VeChain to China’s NRCC. VeChain will work directly with NRCC to develop blockchain solutions for the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration and the China National Tobacco Corporation. &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@vechainofficial/vechain-blockchain-solutions-to-enter-chinas-tobacco-industry-in-force-c92b3729878f&quot;&gt;Source.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gui’an New Area - Gui’an New Area is a new economic-development zone in China that was recently granted the same government administrative level as the Pudong New Area, of which Shanghai is a part of. As such, expect China to pour significant resources to develop the Gui’an New Area in the near future. A few months ago, VeChain announced that the company was mandated to be the blockchain technology partner of the government of Gui’an. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.vechain.com/vechain_national_government_partnership_guian_release.pdf&quot;&gt;Source.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BMW - BMW is the most recent enterprise partnership announced by VeChain. Details around the partnership are scarce even though it’s probably related to supply chain management.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And many more…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 3 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3806401153&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;project-concerns&quot;&gt;Project concerns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heavy-centralization&quot;&gt;Heavy centralization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, VeChain is going to be a highly centralized blockchain. It’s just as centralized, if not more so, than EOS. With EOS, the community votes for block producers with each EOS token entitling a user to one vote. VeChain’s proof-of-authority system, on the other hand, gives the VeChain Foundation the power to pick and choose block producers. Even if the network is secured by 101 different block producers, everyone of them is beholden to the Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This high degree of centralization is a double-edged sword. The great thing about it is that VeChain’s blockchain can have super high performance with stable governance and no risk of hard forks. This is very attractive to enterprise customers, who, of all things, value stability and predictability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, decentralization is what started the entire cryptocurrency movement and is arguably the core value proposition of the technology. Centralization carries with it the risk of censorship, the risk of systemic failure (from a single point of failure), and the risk of an abuse of power and trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One only needs to remember how broken the existing financial and monetary system is to understand why so many people are attracted to the decentralized nature of cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;many-technical-details-of-the-project-are-unknown&quot;&gt;Many technical details of the project are unknown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VeChain has provided very little technical details about its blockchain. This combined with the fact that the project is entirely closed source, has resulted in investors being completely left in the dark on the technical state of VeChain. There are many open technical questions with the project such as how offline block producers will be handled, how the system will defend against malicious block producers, how the supply of Thor Power will be controlled, how are blockchain fees determined, etc. It’s quite concerning to me that there are still so many open technical questions for a project at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unproven-token-economics-unknown-price-of-thor-power&quot;&gt;Unproven token economics, unknown price of Thor Power&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VeChain’s Thor Power economic system is unproven. The whole idea of Thor Power is that it’s a stable asset on VeChain in order to stabilize costs to use the blockchain. Creating a stablecoin is not an easy task and the jury is still out on whether the Thor Power system will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, many people are buying VET with the hopes of generating Thor Power for passive income. However, without understanding where Thor Power’s price will settle, we cannot accurately predict how profitable it’d be to hold VET. It’s possible that only users with Thunder Nodes and above will make a decent income while everyone else will earn a pittance. This is especially true if almost everyone that’s buying VET right now plans to earn and SELL Thor Power, and no one is buying to earn and USE Thor Power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, in the long run if VeChain’s blockchain is heavily used, Thor Power generation can be exceedingly profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vechain-is-not-open-source&quot;&gt;VeChain is not open source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another concern with VeChain is the fact that the project is closed source and there is low visibility into its development progress. This presents a few problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it’s incredibly hard for investors to gauge whether the project’s on track to meet key release dates. Investors can only take the word of the team at face value to understand how the project is doing. Second, a closed source project is more likely to contain critical bugs since the public cannot audit the code. Finally, it’s highly unusual for cryptocurrency projects to not be open source. Almost every project has stayed true to the open and decentralized spirit of cryptocurrencies and maintained complete transparency with their development progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blatant-reddit-manipulation&quot;&gt;Blatant Reddit manipulation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3EGbq7q.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px; border: solid grey 1px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, VeChain has been banned in the past by the largest cryptocurrency subreddit, /r/cryptocurrency, for blatant upvote brigading. For weeks and even months on end, one would see highly upvoted VeChain posts on /r/cryptocurrency until one day it was announced that all mentions of the project were banned from the subreddit for a month. The mods of /r/cryptocurrency later released proof that VeChain’s Telegram mods were actively encouraging users to upvote VeChain-related posts and comments on /r/cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/2Sznes3.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 600px; border: solid grey 1px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I found most concerning about this debacle is the fact that a project targetting enterprise customers, especially one with so many high profile partnerships already, shouldn’t need to market so heavily to retail investors. Yet here we are with certain factions of the project’s leadership encouraging unhealthy short term hype and speculation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 4 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2933037642&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VeChain is one of the most promising blockchain projects out there. It has an extensive list of enterprise partnerships that you rarely see with any other cryptocurrency project, especially one that’s still so early in development. With large investors like PwC China, FENBUSHI Capital, and Jim Breyers as well as a top tier partnership with DNV GL, VeChain appears to be on track to be the de facto supply chain cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as great as VeChain’s ecosystem might look right now, it’s still very much experimental technology that might or might not see traction with enterprise customers. Until VeChain has proven that it works and it works well in production environments, there will continue to be significant risks in investing in the project. That said, it’s still a high quality project compared to many many other cryptocurrency projects out there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 01:44:35 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-vechain/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-vechain/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Someone Bought Reddit Bots To Censor My Article On NEO, But It&#39;s Not Working</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center -header&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/QKNPTk8.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote a critical article on NEO that presented, among other things, mounting evidence that despite an advertised capability to support 1000 transactions/second, NEO actually has some serious scaling issues. The network has been mysteriously blacking out even with only one concurrent ICO occurring on the platform. For a blockchain that is supposed to be able to process 1000 transactions/second, it’s very surprising to learn that at times, it can’t even handle the load of one ICO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I posted the article on Reddit (specifically /r/cryptomarkets) and noticed very suspicious voting activity about an hour after posting. Initially, the article was well received and the upvote/downvote ratio was quite positive. Within the first hour, the post had gained almost 54 points and it quickly rose to the front page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something incredibly sketchy happened soon after. In the span of 15 minutes, the post received a flood of downvotes that dropped it from around 50 to 0 points. It quickly dropped off from the front page and traffic from /r/cryptomarkets dried up. It was quite obvious someone turned on their legion of bots to censor my article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/TAtjISc.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/dwqoQwe.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to report that even though the bots were able to censor the article from /r/cryptomarkets, they couldn’t censor it from other places like Twitter, Facebook, and /r/buttcoin. In fact, the post performed incredibly well on /r/buttcoin. So far, tens of thousands of people have seen the article and I’m happy to see that even after getting downvoted to oblivion, people are still able to discover and objectively evaluate my research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is so much social media manipulation in the cryptocurrency space because it’s so easy and profitable. If you don’t believe me, just look at all the scam bots that swarm tweets from popular cryptocurrency-related Twitter accounts. The botting on reddit is a little bit more subtle but it shouldn’t come as a surprise that the same bots that downvoted my post are being used to upvote and downvote other posts. The people behind these bots are effectively defining reddit’s narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see it all the time, yet when my own social media posts get botted, it definitely leaves a very bad taste. I highly recommend not basing your investment decisions on what you see on social media. Hype can be easily fabricated, dissenting opinions can be easily suppressed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 19:48:45 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/neo-bought-reddit-bots-to-censor-me-but-its-not-working/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/neo-bought-reddit-bots-to-censor-me-but-its-not-working/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NEO Is A Multi-Billion Dollar Disaster</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Also see the follow-on article: &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/neo-bought-reddit-bots-to-censor-me-but-its-not-working/&quot;&gt;Someone Bought Reddit Bots to Censor My Article On NEO, But It’s Not Working&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of my readers know that I have been highly critical of NEO. This has brought me the ire of NEO’s community. However, I’m not going to stop warning the larger cryptocurrency community of questionable projects because this is how we grow together and this is how a legitimate industry is built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continue to research NEO and follow its community, I continue to find more and more red flags surrounding this multi-billion dollar project. In a previous post, I talked about how NEO was &lt;a href=&quot;http://storeofvalueblog.com/posts/major-neo-redflags/&quot;&gt;incredibly centralized&lt;/a&gt;, that the network had an alarmingly small number of smart contracts, and that there was no Eastern interest even though a rumour kept getting propagated that NEO is compliant with the Chinese government and has its support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, as more and more ICOs start to be conducted on NEO, I’m seeing a serious divergence between the platform’s advertised performance and its actual performance. Da Hongfei, NEO’s cofounder, has claimed that NEO is able to support 1000 transactions per second. However, if you follow the community closely, you’ll realise that this claim is quite dubious. Whenever an ICO is run on NEO, you will see complaint after complaint of the network being down or wallets not working. This is not characteristic of a blockchain capable of 1000 transactions per second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/OkikZmH.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also been increasingly evident that NEO’s smart contract infrastructure has issues as well. Many developers that have tried to build on NEO have encountered heaps of problems with the system. To make matters worse, NEO forces developers to pay tens of thousands of dollars simply to deploy a smart contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, I’ve compiled a series of social media comments from NEO’s community lamenting its problems. Don’t take my word on how problematic NEO is, here’s what its own investors are saying about NEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;single-icos-are-bringing-neos-network-to-a-halt&quot;&gt;Single ICOs are bringing NEO’s network to a halt&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO has experienced major outages during ICOs. It’s interesting to note that NEO has so far hosted at most one concurrent ICO on its platform and still, its network is not able to handle the load. For a centralized platform that is supposedly capable of running 1000 transactions/second, not being able to handle load from a single ICO is very very surprising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few ICOs that have caused significant network outages on NEO recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;red-pulse&quot;&gt;Red Pulse&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Red Pulse ICO took place in October last year and it was NEO’s first ever ICO. This was the first time NEO was put through the strains of hosting an ICO and the blockchain faltered. NEO’s block times are typically around 30 seconds yet block 1,445,026 took almost 4 minutes to generate. The outage was brief enough that very few people took it seriously but this was still an outage nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/7KsauSs.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trinity-network-credit&quot;&gt;Trinity Network Credit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During Trinity’s ICO, NEO’s network went down for almost half an hour. The popular NEON wallet by the City of Zion also stopped working and users were not able to send transactions, claim gas, or sync their balance. It also seems like the ICO was organized very poorly by the admins, with the website going down and the Telegram group filled with trolls and scammers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blocks 1816382 and 1816382 were produced during the Trinity ICO. Notice how it took 25 minutes for NEO’s network to create block 1816382. It then took another 12 minutes to create block 1816383. The network resumed normal operation after block 1816383 with new blocks being created every 30 seconds or so. This is indisputable evidence that the blockchain went down during the ICO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/4972eQC.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7qdjpo/40_minutes_of_trinity_ico/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7qdjpo/40_minutes_of_trinity_ico/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s further confirmation that the network went down. Users are also discussing a NEON wallet outage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/KMM8wMN.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7qdjpo/40_minutes_of_trinity_ico/dsoh8ug/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7qdjpo/40_minutes_of_trinity_ico/dsoh8ug/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s evidence that the ICO was managed poorly. The admins were apparently also exhibiting very questionable behaviour calling people to send NEO even after the cap was reached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ifK2ArX.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7qd4a9/trinity_ico_mega_successful_scaling_is_coming_to/dsp5ji3/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7qd4a9/trinity_ico_mega_successful_scaling_is_coming_to/dsp5ji3/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/nzikb6E.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7qd4a9/trinity_ico_mega_successful_scaling_is_coming_to/dsohecs/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7qd4a9/trinity_ico_mega_successful_scaling_is_coming_to/dsohecs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thekey&quot;&gt;TheKEY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like Trinity, TheKEY’s ICO went poorly. Again, NEO’s network sputtered and the ICO itself was terribly organized. Here’s a very good article on the fiasco: &lt;a href=&quot;https://71republic.com/2018/01/15/thekey-rip-the-story-behind-the-worst-ico-of-2018/&quot;&gt;THEKEY.RIP: The Story Behind The Worst ICO of 2018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an excerpt from the article linked above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/zIaJkIg.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/nqCDUWd.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/CryptoCurrency/comments/7qiz8w/the_key_vip_worst_ico_of_2018_so_far/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/CryptoCurrency/comments/7qiz8w/the_key_vip_worst_ico_of_2018_so_far/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 3 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3806401153&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bridge-protocol&quot;&gt;Bridge Protocol&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bridge Protocol’s ICO is the latest ICO disaster on NEO. Again, the blockchain and wallets went down during the ICO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Ef7xFPO.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7zecxd/daily_discussion_february_23rd_2018/dunstm1/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7zecxd/daily_discussion_february_23rd_2018/dunstm1/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RqLhV6B.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7zecxd/daily_discussion_february_23rd_2018/dunm00g/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7zecxd/daily_discussion_february_23rd_2018/dunm00g/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3z2rOfN.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7zecxd/daily_discussion_february_23rd_2018/dupxev0/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7zecxd/daily_discussion_february_23rd_2018/dupxev0/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Bridge Protocol admin blames network issues on NEO’s blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/sC6bQYg.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7zecxd/daily_discussion_february_23rd_2018/duoy8ke/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7zecxd/daily_discussion_february_23rd_2018/duoy8ke/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/0ap27DM.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEO admits that there are ongoing problems with nodes on the network. This prompts some investors to question NEO’s advertised capability of being able to support 1000 transactions per second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/PCgdaQA.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7zfnmh/neon_014_not_working/dunzlyx/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7zfnmh/neon_014_not_working/dunzlyx/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/jRq4SJQ.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7zecxd/daily_discussion_february_23rd_2018/dunw78b/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7zecxd/daily_discussion_february_23rd_2018/dunw78b/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;neo-experiences-an-outage-even-without-an-ongoing-ico&quot;&gt;NEO experiences an outage even without an ongoing ICO&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two days ago, NEO’s blockchain went down for more than two hours. There was no ongoing ICO when this happened. Many people went on Reddit to inquire and complain about the downtime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/OyxlxeA.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Katg4hc.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/81el6n/we_appear_to_be_stuck/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/81el6n/we_appear_to_be_stuck/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out, a single consensus node out of the seven operated by the team went down because of an unexpected edge case. As such, manual intervention was required to restart the blockchain. At the surface level, this might appear to be an easily fixeable bug but it’s actually much worse. The most basic problem for a fault tolerant consensus system to address is the recovery process when a single node goes down. NEO’s main net has been out for more than a year now and it should be incredibly surprising that its consensus algorithm is still vulnerable to single node downtimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/WftZfg8.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ercwl/status/970294228122263552&quot;&gt;in-depth discussion&lt;/a&gt; on the problem by Eric Wall, a cryptocurrency developer and writer for Bitcoin.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eric’s tweets went viral and they were acknowledged by many prominent cryptocurrency leaders like &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/SatoshiLite/status/970372628220293120&quot;&gt;Charlie Lee&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/el33th4xor/status/970331623236435968&quot;&gt;Emin Gün Sirer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jaredctate/status/970402671382401024&quot;&gt;Jared Tate&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TheRealXinxi/status/970370497551646720&quot;&gt;Xinxi Wang&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/VladZamfir/status/970340842253750272&quot;&gt;Vlad Zamfir&lt;/a&gt;. They all agreed that NEO has a serious problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 4 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2933037642&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;people-have-problems-building-neo-smart-contracts&quot;&gt;People have problems building NEO smart contracts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s becoming increasingly evident that smart contract developers are encountering many problems developing on NEO. Several have even accused the system of being poorly coded. To make matters worse, NEO’s team has imposed a tremendous financial barrier to deploying smart contracts. The fee to deploy a smart contract is 500 GAS, which is more than $15,000 at the current price of GAS. These problems explain why there are so few smart contracts on NEO, and why the rate of growth of NEO smart contracts is so anemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The head developer of a popular Ethereum dApp, Etheremon, recalls his experience developing on NEO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/rsMDC6c.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/BATProject/comments/74vbd7/good_job_major_issues_are_clear_preview_version/do2781g/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/BATProject/comments/74vbd7/good_job_major_issues_are_clear_preview_version/do2781g/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a post on NEO’s subreddit calling for smart contract developers to keep trying and not be &lt;strong&gt;demoralized&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/G7H6a9V.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7yvzxa/a_message_to_all_new_neo_smart_contract_developers/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7yvzxa/a_message_to_all_new_neo_smart_contract_developers/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NEO community’s initiative to setup a NEO Stackexchange community was recently denied on the grounds of a lack of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/9wCbtsy.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7yvzxa/a_message_to_all_new_neo_smart_contract_developers/dulcivl/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/NEO/comments/7yvzxa/a_message_to_all_new_neo_smart_contract_developers/dulcivl/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Reddit user who claims to have tried developing NEO smart contracts before calls the smart contract system “almost unusable right now”. In addition, there seems to be very poor support for multi-language development even though this was a widely advertised property for NEO’s smart contract 2.0 system released last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; border: solid grey 1px&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/v70xyS5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/CryptoCurrency/comments/81w1x4/weekly_skeptics_discussion_march_4_2018/dv6dox1/&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/CryptoCurrency/comments/81w1x4/weekly_skeptics_discussion_march_4_2018/dv6dox1/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was one of the earliest cryptocurrency analysts to raise red flags on NEO. However, because the project was less popular with lower usage then, the problems I raised were theoretical and not tangible. Over the past few months, NEO’s popularity has skyrocketed and so has its platform usage. This has made the platform’s inherent problems increasingly evident. Users experience these problems through a rising number of network outages. Many developers are also eschewing the system for greener pastures as they encounter issues with a poorly coded smart contract system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not want to tell anyone how to invest their money. However, I do want to educate investors on the strengths and weaknesses of the different platforms out there. Cryptocurrency investors tend to treat the projects they have invested in as sports teams and often turn a blind eye to the project’s problems. NEO’s investors are no exception. Don’t fall into this trap, stayed informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Also see the follow-on article: &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/neo-bought-reddit-bots-to-censor-me-but-its-not-working/&quot;&gt;Someone Bought Reddit Bots to Censor My Article On NEO, But It’s Not Working&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 13:01:23 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/neos-secret-scaling-issues/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/neos-secret-scaling-issues/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Deep Dive Into EOS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-header -center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/t0u6yns.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-eos&quot;&gt;What is EOS?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS is a smart contracts platform founded and designed by cryptocurrency genius and serial entrepreneur, Dan Larimer. EOS promises to be a next generation smart contracts platform that uses a novel blockchain architecture designed to enable vertical and horizontal scaling that supports many decentralized applications in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS focuses on performance and useability. Its use of a delegated Proof of Stake consensus algorithm and a messaging-centric design allows it to have incredibly fast block times. Its unique token economics enables free transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, using Ethereum’s decentralized applications (dApps) can be quite cumbersome. A user needs to pay fees and transactions take a while to confirm. In high usage conditions, Ethereum becomes increasingly painful to use as fees rise and transaction confirmation times increase. EOS aims to solve all these issues in order to create a business-ready blockchain that doesn’t feel like a blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are grandiose goals but it’s important to keep in mind that EOS is still an early stage project. The main net hasn’t been released yet and EOS has yet to prove whether it will work as well as advertised in production. There are also concerns with centralization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eoss-design-principles&quot;&gt;EOS’s design principles&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/8sBXh3r.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS very nicely lays out 6 requirements for blockchain applications in its whitepaper:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supports millions of users&lt;/strong&gt;: can’t build a successful blockchain with large network effects if it can only support a small network of users&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free usage&lt;/strong&gt;: users should not have to pay transaction fees to use the network. It’s a bad experience doing so.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy upgrades and bug recovery&lt;/strong&gt;: applications should be super easy to upgrade. Software bugs are inevitable so it should be easy for developers to recover from them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sequential performance&lt;/strong&gt;: basically, a blockchain needs to have super high transaction throughput.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parallel performance&lt;/strong&gt;: a blockchain should be able to parallelize the execution of dApps, since many dApps often work in their own siloes and don’t really care about any other dApps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;who-is-dan-larimer&quot;&gt;Who is Dan Larimer?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/DJUPPl4.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Larimer has been involved with cryptocurrencies for quite a long time. He registered his BitcoinTalk account, &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?action=profile;u=611&quot;&gt;bytemaster&lt;/a&gt;, in 2010 and has been very vocal about blockchain designs on the forum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Larimer is a blockchain genius and serial entrepreneur. He’s the founder of two  blockchain projects, Bitshares and Steem. Both of which have hundreds of millions of dollars in market cap. Bitshares is a blockchain that supports decentralized exchange of custom assets and stablecoins. Steem is a social network blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Larimer has mentioned that his ultimate plan is to build a high performance generalized smart contract platform. He is highly critical of Ethereum and intends for EOS to drastically improve on Ethereum’s shortcomings. It’s clear that EOS incorporates many of his learnings from building Bitshares and Steem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend watching Larimer’s debate on blockchain scaling with Vitalik Buterin &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZQUvcmzenoc&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-does-eos-work&quot;&gt;How does EOS work?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS’s vision is to achieve widespread blockchain adoption. It plans to get there by building a general purpose, high performance, highly useable, and self-governing smart contracts blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do so, EOS needs to have high-scale, support parallelized dApp execution, free transactions, and a self-governing system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dpos-consensus-algorithm-and-a-5-annual-inflation&quot;&gt;DPoS consensus algorithm and a 5% annual inflation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS uses a consensus algorithm developed by Dan Larimer. The algorithm closely resembles delegated Proof of Stake (dPoS) algorithms so I’ll refer to it as dPoS in this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DPoS is incredibly fast. In EOS, blocks are produced in rounds. In each round, 21 block producers are chosen and the producers take turns to produce a block every 3 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users vote for block producers; the top 20 accounts with the most votes are guaranteed to be block producers. The 21st block producer is randomly chosen, with the chance being chosen proportional to the number of votes the account has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS has 5% annual inflation and the community will be able to vote on who receives the inflation. Although the exact distribution of the inflation is still unknown, it’s very likely that the block producers will receive a good portion of the inflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-eos-scale-to-millions-of-transactions-per-second&quot;&gt;How does EOS scale to millions of transactions per second?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS is able to achieve its high scalability and throughput as a result of its dPoS consensus algorithm and a novel blockchain architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DPoS is a blazingly fast consensus algorithm but the catch is, it’s quite centralized and block producers need to run super high performance computers in order to meet EOS’s blockchain demands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS’s novel blockchain architecture augments its dPoS algorithm to enable EOS to scale to millions of transactions per second. The architecture is messaged-based and supports parallelized dApp execution. You can read more about its architecture &lt;a href=&quot;http://iang.org/papers/EOS_An_Introduction.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;eos-supports-dapp-parallelization&quot;&gt;EOS supports dApp parallelization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, EOS is capable of parallelized dApp execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, EOS blocks are split into different threads with each thread assigned a group of dApps and other EOS accounts by the block producer. Two dApps can be safely assigned into different threads if there are no transactions referencing both dApps at once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is made possible by the fact that a dApp’s state only depends on the messages it receives, and EOS has a constraint that messages generated in one block cycle can only be delivered in the next cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 3 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3806401153&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;eoss-transactions-are-free&quot;&gt;EOS’s transactions are free&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transactions in EOS are free. Block producers are compensated partly by an annual 5% inflation rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchains with free transactions are vulnerable to spam. EOS combats this by using a completely different resource model. Holding EOS tokens gives an account a set amount of transaction, computation, and storage bandwidth to use. The more EOS tokens a user holds, relative to other users in the system, the more blockchain resources available to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This limit is elastic. In low blockchain usage conditions, each EOS token provides more bandwidth. As overall blockchain usage increases, bandwidth allocation shrinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that this bandwidth restriction is enforced by EOS block producers in almost a subjective fashion. Since a block is produced by a single block producer, the producer can reject transactions if the producer believes that the transaction is wasteful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-eoss-self-governance-system-work&quot;&gt;How does EOS’s self-governance system work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users holding EOS tokens have a say in the governance of EOS. Users get to vote for block producers and how EOS’s 5% annual inflation is allocated. Each EOS token represents one vote. The top 20 accounts (by votes) are guaranteed to be block producers while the 21st block producer is randomly chosen (chance proportional to the amount of votes an account has).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a block producer gives you tremendous power. Producers can collectively choose to freeze EOS accounts, change a smart contract’s code, and propose protocol changes. In addition, the block producers will likely have a significant portion of EOS tokens and thus have a huge influence over EOS’s governance decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS also introduces the concept of a blockchain constitution. In order to use the blockchain, users will need to sign the constitution by adding a hash of the constitution into the transaction’s signature. The constitution defines user obligations which cannot be entirely enforced by code. The constitution can be changed through proposals made by the block producers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-much-more&quot;&gt;And much more…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS is an incredibly complex blockchain and it has many features that make dApp development as easy as possible. These include:
* a built-in permission management system
* an account recovery system
* ability for full nodes to partially evaluate blockchain state&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about EOS’s technology, I highly recommend reading its &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/EOSIO/Documentation/blob/master/TechnicalWhitePaper.md&quot;&gt;technical whitepaper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eos-is-designed-for-businesses&quot;&gt;EOS is designed for businesses&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Larimer has stated that if EOS is successful, it’d be a blockchain where businesses would run their high performance dApps. These applications could include decentralized exchanges, social networks, and games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because EOS scales so well, it’d be able to support all these applications without being bogged down like Ethereum. EOS’s rich feature set also makes it very convenient for businesses to build dApps. On the flip side, dApps on EOS should be very easy and intuitive to use because of its high transaction throughput, fast confirmation times, and free transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;eoss-ecosystem-is-gaining-momentum&quot;&gt;EOS’s ecosystem is gaining momentum&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/nNteLxP.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company behind EOS, block.one, has a very strong executive team. The team includes Brendan Blumer, a serial entrepreneur who has built businesses like okay.com in Hong Kong and 1Group in India, Richard Jung, a former CEO of Bithumb who has also held an executive position in Alibaba, and of course, the blockchain genius himself, Dan Larimer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Novogratz, a renowned billionaire ex-hedge fund manager who was an incredibly early investor in Ethereum, has invested in EOS through his venture capital firm, Galaxy Digital. Galaxy Digital and block.one announced in January that they have formed a $325 million fund to invest in EOS’s ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Block.one also announced in January that it has formed another EOS ecosystem fund with TomorrowBC, a blockchain investment arm of Eric Schmidt’s venture firm, TomorrowVentures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to these investment funds, block.one announced in September last year that it will be channeling $1 billion of its token sale proceeds to investing in its ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies that have announced they will build on EOS include Everipedia, a blockchain-based fork of Wikipedia, and EOSfinx, an EOS-based decentralized exchange operated by Bitfinex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With so much capital for block.one to deploy, look to seeing more and more companies build dApps on EOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 4 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2933037642&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;project-concerns&quot;&gt;Project concerns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;centralized-cartel-with-the-power-to-modify-contracts-and-censor-accounts&quot;&gt;Centralized cartel, with the power to modify contracts and censor accounts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are significant centralization concerns with EOS. Block producers have tremendous power and the blockchain has weak mechanisms to replace any. If you’re a block producer, you’d likely have a disproportionately large amount of EOS tokens which will basically ensure that you remain as a block producer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a block producer likely entitles you to a large portion of inflation income. You’ll also have the ability to modify contracts and censor accounts. This is a scary amount of power to give to a select few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also really hard for a user to become a block producer. Besides the paramount task of getting enough votes to be in the top 20 accounts, a user would need to operate high performance computers with large storage capacities (I would not be surprised if this reaches the scale of data centers) in order to support blockchain operations. How else will EOS be able to support so many high performance dApps on its platform?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, there is a high risk EOS will become a highly centralized system with the top 20 block producers forming a rigid cartel. Is this worth the ease of development and large performance gains? I have my doubts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jack-of-all-trades-master-of-none&quot;&gt;Jack of all trades, master of none&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS is essentially trying to be a blockchain-based AWS. I don’t think this will work out. Blockchains are not designed to be ultra high scale cloud computing platforms. The essence of blockchains is trustless security and tremendous liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If companies want a high scale cloud computing platform, they’d simply use AWS. AWS is cheap and provides SLAs that a blockchain will never be able to provide. Block producers have varying capabilities because they operate completely different computational and storage hardware. The producers are also able to control which transactions get processed and which don’t without any recourse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain platforms like Ethereum and Bitcoin, which although have pitiful performance, provide a level of trustless security and liquidity that AWS will never be able to provide. These core properties are what sets blockchain apart from other technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS tries to push high performance computing onto blockchains while still maintaining some form of decentralization. I fear that this strategy will only result in a system that’s not great at either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EOS attempts to fix the scaling problems of existing blockchains in order to create a highly scalable and easy-to-use blockchain ready for widespread adoption. However, its ease of use, performance, and scalability comes with an expensive tradeoff: centralization. Although the technology has high potential, there is also a risk that it ends up being a jack of all trades but a master of none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some call EOS the Ethereum killer. I disagree. I believe they serve very different use cases and can coexist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 17:36:22 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-eos/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-eos/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Crypto Scam Spotlight: Ethertanks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-header -center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ocZdwip.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The massive success of CryptoKitties inspired many dApp developers to build games on Ethereum. A few developers, unfortunately, have decided to take a different path and build CryptoKitties-like games that were actually scams. Ethertanks was one of these games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as users can buy virtual cats on CryptoKitties, users can buy virtual tanks in EtherTanks. However, unlike CryptoKitties, Ethertanks doesn’t have any unique gameplay mechanics. In CryptoKitties, users could breed new, unique cats that had a combination of phenotypes from its parents. In Ethertanks, users simply bought tanks. There was nothing else they could do with the tanks accept earn money from users that bought in after them. The game was a clear Ponzi scheme. The devs did promise that users will eventually be able to trade and battle their tanks but they never delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-ponzi-scheme&quot;&gt;The Ponzi scheme&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A Ponzi scheme is defined as “a fraudulent investment operation where the operator generates returns for older investors through revenue paid by new investors, rather than from legitimate business activities or profit of financial trading.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethertanks’s economics system was a clear Ponzi scheme. Every type of tank had a base cost and this increased whenever a new tank of the type is bought. The cost of the new tank consists of the tank’s base cost and a small payout to every existing owner of a tank with the same type. As such, every time a user buys a tank, s/he is essentially paying fees to everyone else that bought in before him/her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a user wanted to make money from the scheme, they needed to get in early such that there would be enough suckers who’d buy in afterwards such that their returns could cover their initial investment and even exceed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a huge incentive for people to buy in as fast as possible and then shill the heck out of the “game” so that they can exit with meaningful profits. All the while, the devs were also making a huge amount of money as they took a cut out of each transaction and they were probably also the first users to buy into the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-pyramid-scheme&quot;&gt;The Pyramid scheme&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A Pyramid scheme is defined as “a form of investment (illegal in the US and elsewhere) in which each paying participant recruits two further participants, with returns being given to early participants using money contributed by later ones”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ponzi structure of Ethertanks resulted in a legion of shills (many from 4chan) that brigaded social networks like Reddit and Twitter to promote Ethertanks as the next CryptoKitties game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a post on 4chan’s infamous /biz/ forum calling its users to promote the Ponzi on the largest cryptocurrency subreddit, /r/cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ZG6sUtl.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brigading was particularly intense on Reddit with users creating and upvoting posts advertising Ethertanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many users justified Ethertanks’s Ponzi structure by saying that the devs had promised a marketplace so any users who bought in could always flip their tanks in the marketplace, just like CryptoKitties. Of course, this was only a promise and many users would learn, to their dismay, that the devs would never deliver on the promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To have a feel of the scale of Ethertanks brigading, check out the frontpage of /r/ethtrader soon after the game was released:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RqCMJhK.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ethtrader/comments/7n6sdg/ethertank_new_ethereum_dapp_buying_tanks_and/&quot;&gt;highest upvoted posts&lt;/a&gt; on Ethertanks. Notice how the poster emphasized how much money they were able to make…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/VYThV7v.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When users asked about the game’s obvious Ponzi scheme structure, the poster immediately countered by saying that there will eventually be a marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/T7nTZGO.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some other comments on Reddit shilling EtherTanks. Honestly, it makes me absolutely sick reading some of them. The comments on this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ethtrader/comments/7n48qm/be_careful_ethertanks_looks_like_a_pyramidponzi/&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; where a /r/ethtrader mod was warning readers about the scam were particularly tough to read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Well my LT-1 is ready for battle”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Looked sketchy as fuck yet here I am earning a bunch of ETH.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Anyone with half a brain knows this is a Ponzi scheme lol. No need to read the code for that. That being said, LT-1 checking in.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I just bought the LT-1 and Eskimo 15 min ago. The shit actually works. And I’ve already recooped 8% of the cost that I purchased the tanks for. Crazy. I look at it as a learning process, how to actually interact with the blockchain. Now I have a decent grasp of it, and I can confidently send and receive crypto, know how to lock it all up, know how to view the blocks of a chain, can view any transaction from the public…and it all really works!!”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I am having a hard time believing this is real…yet here we are. Now I’ve made back ~15% of my initial investment (~$300) in the past 25 minutes.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“This received a lot of FUD today, but the community is great, devs have been responsive and supportive. HT-1 is the play.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I think this is good way to make some extra eth since market is moving slowly recently”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Bought the newest tank and got the investment back in like 30 minutes. Nice :)”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even The Merkle, a popular cryptocurrency news and editorial website, published an &lt;a href=&quot;https://themerkle.com/what-is-ethertanks/&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; promoting Ethertanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;false-promises&quot;&gt;False promises&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/GFT6WGK.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The devs promised that users would be able to trade and battle their tanks. The marketplace was supposed to launch on January 7th while battle mode was supposed to launch a few weeks afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, the devs never delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the devs did pull a final trick to try to get more people to buy in. After missing their January 7th deadline, they created a new dApp called EtherArmy where users can not only buy tanks, but ships and planes as well. EtherArmy was the exact same thing as EtherTanks except for a few new reskinned useless blockchain assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;aftermath&quot;&gt;Aftermath&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with all Ponzi schemes, most people who bought in lost money. The devs made a huge amount of money, the earliest adopters a little less but still a significant amount, and the latecomers lost most of what they put in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some posts from the game’s subreddit, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/ethtanks/&quot;&gt;/r/ethtanks&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/1aYlB5W.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/N8fs1Hp.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one good thing that came out of this game is an important lesson for everyone involved, as well as outsiders. Never let your greed, your desire to make a quick buck, override your common sense. Understand that social media can easily be manipulated and you should not let Reddit and Twitter posts do the decision making for you. If it’s too good to be true and it looks like a scam, it probably is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 23:12:47 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/crypto-scam-spotlight-ethertanks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/crypto-scam-spotlight-ethertanks/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Deep Dive Into Cardano</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-header -center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/SMeXznA.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano is a proof of stake, smart contracts blockchain. Its native cryptocurrency is called ADA and the smallest unit of ADA (1/1,000,000 ADA) is called a Lovelace. This is in tribute to the first recognized computer programmer, Ada Lovelace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano prides itself in the rigorous academic process used to develop various aspects of the blockchain. Its website claims that Cardano is “the first blockchain project to be developed from a scientific philosophy, and the only one to be designed and built by a global team of leading academics and engineers”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to say that blockchain is the new religion and the consensus algorithm is its God. It is clear that Cardano has dedicated significant academic resources in developing its consensus algorithm, Ouroboros. Ouroboros is a provably secure proof of stake algorithm developed by a team of IOHK scientists led by Prof. Aggelos Kiayias. The algorithm is backed by a peer reviewed &lt;a href=&quot;https://iohk.io/research/papers/#9BKRHCSI&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;. According to Charles Hoskinson, the founder of Cardano, Ouroboros’s paper was rewritten 8 times!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extent to which the academic process has influenced Cardano’s development currently does not extend beyond Ouroboros. The team has published a set of other papers, one for a scalable and decentralized randomness algorithm, one for an efficient and decentralized poker protocol, and one for secure sidechains. Besides the randomness algorithm, which is used in Ouroboros to select stake winners, Cardano has not incorporated the ideas of the other papers, yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano is built as a layered blockchain. The Cardano Settlement Layer (SL) is where account balances and transactions are managed. It uses the UTXO model and is supposed to be the most secure part of the blockchain. The SL is kept apart from the computational layer where smart contracts are executed. This layered architecture gives the system the flexibility to be more easily maintained and allow for upgrades by way of soft forks. In Ethereum, the settlement layer and the computational layer are intertwined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano’s properties of academic rigour and provable safety are unique in the cryptocurrency space and a huge selling point for the platform to enterprise customers. Companies looking to deploy blockchain technology want a guarantee of safety and Cardano is the only cryptocurrency with a consensus algorithm backed by a peer reviewed paper with provable safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cardanos-history&quot;&gt;Cardano’s history&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano’s ICO took place in 4 stages between September 2015 - January 2017 with heavy Know Your Customer (KYC) requirements. It was marketed as an “investment to retire on” to primarily Japanese investors; in fact, 95% of the buyers were of Japanese origin, primarily in the 35-55 age bracket. 2.56% of buyers were Korean, and 2.39% were Chinese. The ICO oversaw a total sale of approximately 26,000,000,000 of the 45,000,000,000 maximum supply of ADA tokens. At the conclusion of the ICO a total of approximately $63 million USD was raised; this puts the price at an average of $0.00242 per ADA, and the market capitalization immediately after the ICO at approximately $109 million USD. (&lt;a href=&quot;cardanohub.org&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While 26,000,000,000 ADA was sold in the ICO, an additional 5,185,414,108 ADA were distributed to IOHK, Emurgo, and the Cardano Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A total of 31,112,484,646 ADA was made available at Cardano’s launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;current-state-of-cardano&quot;&gt;Current state of Cardano&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano lays out three eras in its timeline: the Testnet Era, Bootstrap Era, and Reward Era. The Testnet Era is pretty self-explanatory, Cardano is deployed on a test net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bootstrap Era is when Cardano SL is deployed on the main net BUT it is centralized in order to maintain security. Only a fixed, predefined set of users have control over the system. The assumption is that security is poor in this era since people are slow to redeem their ADA coins. For the first few months, stakeholders who jointly possess the majority of the ADA stake are mostly not online yet. The blockchain can be easily attacked if only a small amount of ADA is staked. As consolation to the community, Ouroboros will not provide any block rewards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano is currently in the Bootstrap Era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reward Era is when the network is in a completely decentralized and trustless mode. According to Cardano’s website, “the system will receive regular software updates moving forward, and a massive amount of new features will be released” in this era. These features would include upgrades to Ouroboros, Cardano’s consensus algorithm, an implementation of Cardano’s control layer, and sidechains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;iohk-and-the-cardano-foundation&quot;&gt;IOHK and the Cardano Foundation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/auw5cpJ.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IOHK, or Input Output Hong Kong, is the engineering company implementing Cardano and the Cardano Foundation is the promotor, educator, and standard body for the blockchain and its apps. In October, Hoskinson stated that IOHK had nearly 100 employees and contractors, three research engineers, and operate in nearly ten countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charles Hoskinson is the founder of IOHK and subsequently Cardano and the Cardano Foundation. Hoskinson has a long history as a blockchain entrepreneur. He was initially the CEO of Ethereum before being fired. Reasons of the firing are complicated. Ethereum at the time was 6 months old with a $15 million market cap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoskinson then founded IOHK and IOHK subsequently led the development of Ethereum Classic. Ethereum Classic came to be when Ethereum hard forked after the major DAO hack. A small portion of the community was against this idea and maintained the original chain, which is now known as Ethereum Classic. For IOHK to lead the development of Ethereum Classic suggests that Hoskinson might have some bad blood with members of the Ethereum Foundation, likely from earlier disagreements that resulted in his ousting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While IOHK continues to lead Ethereum Classic’s development, its primary focus is now on Cardano. Hoskinson aspires for Cardano to be a compelling alternative to Ethereum and he plans to do so by building a blockchain that was designed for scale, security, and upgradeability from day one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ouroboros&quot;&gt;Ouroboros&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ouroboros is Cardano’s proof of stake consensus algorithm. Proof of stake was chosen over proof of work since it’s more efficient and it’s way more expensive to perform a 51% attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/eBykRrr.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name Ouroboros comes from the name of an ancient symbol depicting a serpent or dragon eating its own tail. The symbol originated in ancient Egyptian iconography. The name is fitting for this algorithm, since Ouroboros operates in epochs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each Ouroboros epoch contains a fixed number of slots. Each slot represents a new block. The slot leader is an account staking ADA that is responsible for creating the block. Epochs last for 5 days (&lt;a href=&quot;https://steemit.com/cardamon/@dan/peer-review-of-cardano-s-ouroboros&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). Slot leaders for an epoch are chosen during the previous epoch. An account’s chance of being chosen is directly tied to the amount of ADA it’s staking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An account can only participate in staking if it has at least 1% of the total supply of ADA (&lt;a href=&quot;https://steemit.com/cardamon/@dan/peer-review-of-cardano-s-ouroboros&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;). For the accounts that don’t meet that criteria, staking pools will exist so everyone is compensated for owning ADA. This high minimum staking requirement gives rise to concerns of centralization. I outline the concerns below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ouroboros will initially provide both newly minted ADA and transaction fees as block rewards. When the total supply of ADA reaches 45,000,000,000 block rewards will consist only of transaction fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to IOHK/Cardano Foundation, Ouroboros is the first provably secure proof of stake algorithm. The team behind Cardano has mathematically proven that the algorithm is safe from all the known proof of stake attack methods including grinding attacks, nothing-at-stake attacks, and long range attacks. This safety and security should be a very powerful enterprise selling point for Cardano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read more about Ouroboros &lt;a href=&quot;https://cardanodocs.com/cardano/proof-of-stake/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ouroboros-praos&quot;&gt;Ouroboros Praos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ouroboros Praos is an initiative to upgrade Ouroboros. Praos is semi-synchronous, doesn’t require a heavy MPC protocol for randomness and encourages the adoption of a quantum resistant signature scheme for input endorsers and slot leaders. Praos allows for shorter block times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read about Praos &lt;a href=&quot;https://iohk.io/research/papers/#XJ6MHFXX&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ouroboros-hydra&quot;&gt;Ouroboros Hydra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ouroboros Hydra is another upgrade to Ouroboros that introduces sharding. Sharding allows multiple Ouroboros epochs to run at the same time which significantly increases Cardano’s throughput. One of the hardest things to figure out for sharding is inter-shard communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still a ways away from the Hydra upgrade. Expect a paper from Cardano’s team on Hydra before any serious development efforts begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 3 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3806401153&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;sidechains&quot;&gt;Sidechains&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Okl88yP.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidechains are blockchains running in parallel and independently from the main chain. Sidechains and the main chain should be able to securely transfer assets back and forth. If any problems arise in the sidechain, the main chain can confiscate the sidechain’s assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidechains significantly extend the main chain’s capabilities. Because they are separate from the main chain, they can be more centralized and faster and perform more specialized functions. By pegging themselves to the main chain, side chains can take advantage of the main chain’s security without having to adhere to the main chain’s inefficiencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main problem with sidechains today is their security. There are several attacks where mainchains can be compromised through side chains. The Cardanos team has changed this by introducing a provably secure sidechain technology that fixes all known avenues of attack, opening the way for secure sidechains. They call it Non-interactive Proofs of Proof of Work (NIPoPoW). Altough the Cardano’s team is far from implementing NIPoPoW sidechains on Cardano, the technology is a significant step forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;blockchain-performance&quot;&gt;Blockchain performance&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano’s average transaction throughput is 10-15 transactions per second. This is comparable to Ethereum. Charles Hoskinson has claimed that Ouroboros can perform at more than 200 transactions per second in a lab unsharded. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/cardano/comments/77ej8i/cardano_vs_eos/&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 4 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;2933037642&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;project-concerns&quot;&gt;Project concerns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;smart-contracts-are-not-ready&quot;&gt;Smart contracts are not ready&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano’s smart contract virtual machine, the IELE virtual machine, is currently under development. According to Cardano’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://cardanoroadmap.com/&quot;&gt;roadmap&lt;/a&gt;, it is 33% complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano’s smart contract language, Plutus, is also currently under development. The specification of Plutus is complete but the implementation, Plutus core, is not. According to the roadmap, it is 12% complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the control layer still in the early stages of development, Cardano is currently a UTXO blockchain using a proof of stake consensus algorithm. In order for it to compete against existing decentralized smart contract blockchains like Ethereum and QTUM, Cardano needs to get out its control model ASAP in order to get its network effect going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ouroboros-is-prone-to-centralization&quot;&gt;Ouroboros is prone to centralization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, an account can only participate in staking if it has at least 1% of the total supply of ADA. At the current market cap of $13 billion, one needs to have $130 million worth of ADA to participate in staking. If you assume Cardano will be successful, this number will be significantly higher. Who will be able to afford $130 million worth of ADA? Sure there will be staking pools but even staking pools encourage the centralization of wealth. Those participating in the pools will most likely have to pay fees to the pool owner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This minimum balance requirement also means that at most 100 accounts can participate in staking and because of the power law, it will be much less than 100 accounts that will be staking. There will most certainly be a few entities with exponentially large balances of ADA and the minimum balance requirement will only serve to consolidate their power and control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cardano-vs-eos&quot;&gt;Cardano vs EOS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This topic is extremely complex. There is a long history between Dan Larimer and Charles Hoskinson. In fact, before Ethereum, Hoskinson actually worked with Larimer on Bitshares but also left on bad terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out this &lt;a href=&quot;https://steemit.com/cardamon/@dan/peer-review-of-cardano-s-ouroboros&quot;&gt;post by Larimer on the flaws of Cardano&lt;/a&gt;. Also check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://hoskinsoncharles.blogspot.com/2018/01/the-price-of-craftsman-and-zen-of.html&quot;&gt;Hoskinson’s rebuttal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardano is a fundamentally strong cryptocurrency. Ouroboros is a very cool proof of stake algorithm. Its layered blockchain design is sound. Cardano’s security, modularity, and upgradeability will be a big boon for Cardano when it tries to attract enterprise customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Cardano has some fierce competitors and academic rigour and peer research might not be enough to win against years of main net stability and gigantic network effects. That said, Cardano is not going anywhere in the medium term and it does have a very good chance at becoming a top tier smart contracts platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s not a sprint, it’s a marathon” - Charles Hoskinson&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 20:52:53 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-cardano/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-cardano/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Deep Dive Into Theta</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-header -center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/LQN3Oky.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A coworker recently brought to my attention a new cryptocurrency project called Theta. Initially, I dismissed it as just another low cap cryptocurrency project but the more I researched, the more interested I got. The first thing that caught my attention was the impressive list of advisors and investors. The project’s advisors include Steve Chen, a &lt;strong&gt;co-founder of YouTube&lt;/strong&gt;, Justin Kan, a &lt;strong&gt;co-founder of Twitch&lt;/strong&gt;, Fan Zhang, &lt;strong&gt;founding member of Sequoia Capital China&lt;/strong&gt;, and many more. The project’s investors include Sony and Samsung.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what exactly IS Theta to warrant all these high profile advisors and investors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a high level, Theta is a work-in-progress blockchain designed for peer-to-peer video streaming. It aims to be a decentralized video Content Distribution Network (CDN) by allowing anyone with spare bandwidth to become video distribution nodes. These nodes are compensated through proof of work mining on Theta’s blockchain. In order to fairly compensate nodes, Theta introduces a novel concept called Reputation Dependent Mining that increases block rewards based on how many clients a node is serving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world, the Theta blockchain will have a robust internal economy where streamers upload video to Ingest Nodes that transcode video. Video distribution nodes relay the video to viewers and are compensated by the number of viewers the node serves. Advertisers can advertise on Theta by paying streamers Theta tokens and viewers can donate to streamers using Theta tokens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theta is a relatively new project. The team raised $16 million in equity funding and launched Theta in Q2 2017. In Q3 2017, Theta completed &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ThetaLabs/theta-token-sale-success-ac6828d04e97&quot;&gt;an incredibly successful pre-sale&lt;/a&gt; of Theta tokens to strategic investors. A public ICO was scheduled for January 2018 but was cancelled partly from legal concerns. Theta was listed on exchanges starting January 17th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team wil start development of the Theta blockchain in Q1 2018 and plans to launch the blockchain in Q4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 1 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;5229470054&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-theta&quot;&gt;Why Theta?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Theta’s innovation is set to disrupt today’s online video industry much in the same way that the YouTube platform did to traditional video back in 2005. One of our biggest challenges had been the high costs of delivering video to various parts of the world, and this problem is only getting bigger with HD, 4K and higher quality video streams,” said Steve Chen, Co-Founder of YouTube.
I’m excited to be part of the next evolution of the streaming space, helping Theta create a decentralized peer-to-peer network that can offer improved video delivery at lower costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The live streaming market is growing at a breakneck pace, seriously. 81% of internet and mobile audiences watched more live video in 2016 than in 2015. Live video is outpacing all other video content formats in terms of ad revenue and is seeing a 113% increase in annual ad growth. Live streaming is huge in China and growing at the same pace it is in the West. The Chinese live streaming market alone is valued at more than $3 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Steve Chen, Co-founder of Youtube&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Live streaming platforms rely on Content Distribution Networks (CDNs) to distribute video to viewers. Streamers upload video to ingest nodes, ingest nodes transcode the video to different qualities, the video is passed on to the CDN, and viewers connect to the CDN to download video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, CDNs are incredibly expensive to run well. Because video is so bandwidth intensive, companies need to make sure CDN edge nodes are as close to their end users as possible in order to maximize quality of service. As such, nodes need to be numerous and geographically distributed. Bandwidth costs for CDNs are also enormous. Every video stream passing through a CDN is duplicated for every cluster of edge nodes. Publishers like Twitch and YouTube absorb the high costs of operating a CDN which reduces the revenue shared with their streamers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theta aims to solve this problem by acting like torrent for live streams. Users contribute their unused bandwidth to distribute video and are compensated automatically and transparently by the Theta blockchain. Geographical distribution, server costs, and bandwidth costs come for free with such a peer-to-peer network. In addition, it is theoretically a more efficient system compared to centralized CDNs as it takes advantage of the ample amount of spare bandwidth out there. Put together, this SHOULD mean streaming companies will be more willing to use Theta over centralized CDNs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this all relies on the fact that both Theta’s economic model and technology works. This is a big if.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;team-investors-and-advisors&quot;&gt;Team, investors, and advisors&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/TWuUAgZ.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theta has a strong team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mitch Liu, the CEO, has a BS in Computer Science and Engineering from MIT and an MBA from the Stanford Graduate School of Business. He co-founded Tapjoy which today is a 100+ employee company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jieyi Long, the CTO, has a BS in Microelectronics from Peking University, one of China’s top universities. He has a PhD in Computer Engineering from Northwestern University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan Nichols, the Head of Product and Platform at SLIVER.tv, was once the director at Tencent for Wechat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Riz Virk, the Head of Corp Development, was the director at MIT’s Play Labs. He has a BS in Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering from MIT and a Masters in management from Stanford Graduate School of Business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advisors of Theta/SLIVER.tv include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Steve Chen, Co-founder of YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shoucheng Zhang, Founder Danhua Capital&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Justin Kan, Co-founder of Twitch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fan Zhang, Founding member, Sequoia Capital China&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dennis Fong, Founder Plays.tv&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clifford Morgan, CEO of G FUEL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/VbmV99j.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investors of Theta/SLIVER.tv include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lead investor in the token presale is DHVC (Danhua Capital). DHVC was founded by Prof. Shoucheng Zhang, a tenured professor in the Department of Physics at Stanford&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sony Innovation Fund&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SamsungNEXT ventures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sparkland&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sierra Ventures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DCM ventures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and many more…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;slivertv&quot;&gt;SLIVER.tv&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/hlyRMBr.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SLIVER.tv is an existing live streaming platform owned by the Theta team. SLIVER.tv allows users to watch esports events in 360° video. When there are no ongoing events, users can watch streams and bet on in-game events using currency passively earned from watching streams. Winners of bets get tickets to enter a raffle for a Steam item (some can be worth hundreds of dollars). A raffle is held for every game of PUBG or CSGO a streamer is currently playing. SLIVER.tv has more than 1 million Monthly Active Users (MAU).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theta’s team plans to use SLIVER.tv to bootstrap Theta’s network. This will possibly introduce millions of users to the network early on. This bootstrapping is incredibly important for the growth and adoption of Theta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 2 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;7020600859&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thetas-architecture&quot;&gt;Theta’s architecture&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, Theta’s caching nodes act as both miners and relayers of video. The more reliable its service and the more viewers the node serves, the great the rewards from mining a block. To implement this, Theta’s team has come up with two novel concepts they call Reputation Dependent Mining and Proof of Engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reputation Dependent Mining uses Proof of Engagement to calculate a miner’s “reputation”. Reputation is essentially the number of viewers that a miner serves and it essentially determines the miner’s rewards from mining a block. The more viewers a miner serves, the higher its reputation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A miner increases its reputation by having its downstream viewers periodically compute “service certificates” to send back to the caching node. A service certificate is a simple Proof of Work puzzle that helps a miner attest to the rest of Theta’s network that the viewer is being served by the miner. If a viewer decides to stop computing service certificates for a miner, the miner can stop sending video to the viewer. If the miner doesn’t send video to a viewer, then it will be incredibly hard for the miner to convince anyone to compute service certificates for it. If it spends its own computing resources to generate service certificates, it will have less computing resources to create blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;-center&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/mpk5BD7.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;project-concerns&quot;&gt;Project Concerns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If mining rewards are not enough to cover the costs of operating a miner, then there will be very few miners resulting in a poor CDN.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will viewers want to watch Theta streams if it means they need to compute service certificates?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Volatility in the value of Theta tokens might incentivize network participants like advertisers, streamers, and miners to hold onto Theta in as short a time period as possible in order to lock in income. Volatility comes with risk whereas network participants are not investors and adverse to risk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How will advertisers plug into the system? Will advertisers be incentivized to buy Theta or simply pay in fiat? Will streamers be willing accept Theta or simply get paid in fiat?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will service certificates be enough to guarantee service quality? Service certificates are binary, either a viewer computes one or not. What if there’s gray area video quality issues like buffering and dropped frames?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;-ad&quot;&gt;
        &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
        &lt;!-- StoreOfValue Article 3 --&gt;
        &lt;ins class=&quot;adsbygoogle&quot; style=&quot;display:block&quot; data-ad-client=&quot;ca-pub-0144173183236578&quot; data-ad-slot=&quot;3806401153&quot; data-ad-format=&quot;auto&quot;&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;
        &lt;script&gt;
        (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
        &lt;/script&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theta is certainly a very innovative idea. CDNs are, in fact, very expensive to operate and the ability to mobilize spare bandwidth and CPU resources has the potential to create a much more efficient content distribution model. Besides an innovative idea, Theta has many other accolades. Its list of investors and advisors are impressive. Its co-founders have very strong backgrounds. It already has a very popular product in the form of SLIVER.tv that will be perfect for bootstrapping Theta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are several project concerns. The concerns cover both the demand and supply side. Important questions include whether mining rewards are enough to cover the costs of operating a miner, whether viewers are willing to compute service certificates in order to watch streams, and whether video quality will actually be good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Theta works, it will create a self-sustaining economy generating constant value in the form of live streamed entertainment. Large companies will be operating Theta miners and using the Theta network as their CDN. Viewers will be able to choose from a large number of independently operated Theta miners that are closeby to download video from. However, this is certainly a big IF.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 20:27:18 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-theta/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://storeofvalue.github.io/posts/a-deep-dive-into-theta/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
